<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dashveenjit Kaur, Author at AI News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/author/dashveenjit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/author/dashveenjit/</link>
	<description>Artificial Intelligence News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:54:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/ai-icon-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Dashveenjit Kaur, Author at AI News</title>
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/author/dashveenjit/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The emerging US-China Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) rivalry could face a major policy transformation, as the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) recommends a Manhattan Project-style initiative and restrictions on humanoid robots in its latest report to Congress. Released in November 2024, the Commission&#8217;s annual report outlined 32 recommendations that could fundamentally alter how the two countries<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/" title="ReadManhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/">Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The emerging US-China Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) rivalry could face a major policy transformation, as the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Comprehensive_List_of_Recommendations.pdf">recommends</a> a Manhattan Project-style initiative and restrictions on humanoid robots in its latest report to Congress.</p>



<p>Released in November 2024, the Commission&#8217;s <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Annual_Report_to_Congress.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annual report</a> outlined <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Executive_Summary.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">32 recommendations</a> that could fundamentally alter how the two countries interact, with artificial intelligence taking centre stage in a new chapter of strategic rivalry.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">US-China: the AGI moonshot and critical tech controls</h3>



<p>At the heart of the report lies an ambitious proposal: establishing a government-backed programme to develop AGI &#8211; AI systems that could match and potentially exceed human cognitive abilities. </p>



<p>However, the recommendation is just one piece of a larger technological puzzle, including export controls, investment screening, and new trade policies to preserve US technological advantages. </p>



<p>The proposed AGI initiative would provide multi-year contracts to leading AI companies, cloud providers, and data centre operators. It would be backed by the Defense Department&#8217;s highest priority, &#8220;DX Rating&#8221; &#8211; a designation typically reserved for critical national security projects. </p>



<p>This level of government involvement in AI development mirrors the urgency seen in previous technological races. It raises crucial questions about the role of state intervention in an industry primarily driven by private sector innovation.</p>



<p>The Commission&#8217;s tech-focused recommendations extend beyond AI. Notable proposals include restricting imports of Chinese-made autonomous humanoid robots with advanced dexterity, locomotion, and intelligence capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report also targets energy infrastructure products with remote monitoring capabilities, reflecting growing concerns about connected technologies in critical infrastructure. The report builds on existing export controls in the semiconductor space by recommending stronger oversight of technology transfers and investment flows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This comes as China continues to build domestic chip-making capabilities despite international restrictions. The Commission suggests creating an Outbound Investment Office that prevents US capital and expertise from advancing China&#8217;s technological capabilities in sensitive sectors.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Reshaping trade relations and investment flows</h3>



<p>Perhaps most significantly, the report recommends eliminating China&#8217;s Permanent Normal Trade Relations (PNTR) status—a move that could reshape the technology supply chain and trade flows that have defined the global tech industry for decades. This recommendation acknowledges how deeply intertwined the US and Chinese tech ecosystems have become, while suggesting that this interdependence may now pose more risks than benefits.</p>



<p>Data transparency is another key theme, with recommendations for expanded reporting requirements on investments and technology transfers. The Commission calls for better tracking of investments flowing through offshore entities, addressing a significant blind-spot in current oversight mechanisms.</p>



<p>The report&#8217;s release comes at a critical juncture in technological development. China&#8217;s push for self-sufficiency in vital technologies and its &#8220;new quality productive forces&#8221; initiative demonstrates Beijing&#8217;s determination to lead in next-generation technologies. Meanwhile, AI capabilities and quantum computing breakthroughs have raised the stakes in technology competition.</p>



<p>However, the Commission&#8217;s recommendations face practical challenges. Achieving AGI remains a complex scientific challenge that may not yield quick results, regardless of funding levels. Additionally, restrictions on technology transfers and investment could have unintended consequences for global innovation networks that have historically benefited both nations.</p>



<p>If these recommendations are implemented, the tech industry may need to navigate an increasingly complex regulatory landscape. Companies would face new compliance requirements for international investments, technology transfers, and collaborative research projects.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Challenges and future implications</h3>



<p>The effectiveness of the proposed measures will likely depend on coordination with allies and partners who share similar technological capabilities and concerns. The report acknowledges this by recommending multilateral approaches to export controls and investment screening.</p>



<p>US-China technological competition has entered a new phase where government policy may play a more direct role in shaping development. Whether this approach accelerates or hinders innovation remains to be seen, but the tech industry should prepare for increased scrutiny and regulation of international technological collaboration.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nathangbingle?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nathan Bingle</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:844px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/">Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon has announced an additional $4 billion investment in Anthropic, bringing the company&#8217;s total commitment to $8 billion, part of its expanding artificial intelligence strategy. The investment was announced on November 22, 2024 and strengthens Amazon&#8217;s position in the AI sector, building on its established cloud computing services in the form of AWS.  While maintaining<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/" title="ReadAmazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/">Amazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amazon has announced <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-partners-anthropic-enhance-alexa/">an additional</a> $4 billion investment in Anthropic, bringing the company&#8217;s total commitment to $8 billion, part of its expanding artificial intelligence strategy. The investment was <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/aws/amazon-invests-additional-4-billion-anthropic-ai">announced</a> on November 22, 2024 and strengthens Amazon&#8217;s position in the AI sector, building on its established cloud computing services in the form of AWS. </p>



<p>While maintaining Amazon&#8217;s minority stake in Anthropic, the investment represents a significant development in the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-urges-ai-regulation-avoid-catastrophes/">approach to AI technology</a> and cloud infrastructure. The expanded collaboration goes beyond mere financial investment. Anthropic has now designated AWS as its &#8220;primary training partner&#8221; for AI model development, in addition to Amazon&#8217;s role as a primary cloud provider. </p>



<p>Amazon&#8217;s investment will see Anthropic utilizing AWS Trainium and Inferentia chips for training and on which to deploy its future foundational models, including any updates to the flagship Claude AI system.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">AWS&#8217;s competitive edge</h3>



<p>The continuing partnership provides Amazon with several strategic advantages in the competitive cloud computing and AI services market:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Hardware innovation</strong>: The commitment to use AWS Trainium and Inferentia chips for Anthropic&#8217;s advanced AI models validates Amazon&#8217;s investment in custom AI chips and positions AWS as a serious competitor to NVIDIA in the AI infrastructure space.</li>



<li><strong>Cloud service enhancement</strong>: AWS customers will receive early access to fine-tuning capabilities for data processed by Anthropic models. This benefit alone could attract more enterprises to Amazon&#8217;s cloud platform.</li>



<li><strong>Model performance</strong>: Claude 3.5 Sonnet, Anthropic&#8217;s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-new-claude-ai-models-and-computer-control/">latest model</a> available through Amazon Bedrock, has demonstrated exceptional performance in agentic coding tasks, according to Anthropic.</li>
</ol>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Amazon&#8217;s multi-faceted AI strategy</h3>



<p>While the increased investment in Anthropic is impressive in monetary terms, it represents just one component of Amazon&#8217;s broader AI strategy. The company appears to be pursuing a multi-pronged approach:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>External partnerships: </strong>The Anthropic investment provides immediate access to cutting-edge AI capabilities from third-parties.</li>



<li><strong>Internal development:</strong>&nbsp;Amazon continues to develop its own AI models and capabilities.</li>



<li><strong>Infrastructure development:</strong> Ongoing investment in AI-specific hardware like Trainium chips demonstrates a commitment to building AI-focussed infrastructure.</li>
</ol>



<p>The expanded partnership signals Amazon&#8217;s long-term commitment to AI development yet retains flexibility thanks to its minority stakeholding. This approach allows Amazon to benefit from Anthropic&#8217;s innovations while preserving the ability to pursue other partnerships with external AI companies and continue internal development initiatives.</p>



<p>The investment reinforces the growing trend where major tech companies seek strategic AI partnerships rather than relying solely on internal development. It also highlights the important role of cloud infrastructure in the AI industry&#8217;s growth. AWS has positioned itself as a suitable platform for AI model training and deployment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/">Amazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence platform provider Clarifai has unveiled a new compute orchestration capability that promises to help enterprises optimise their AI workloads in any computing environment, reduce costs and avoid vendor lock-in. Announced on December 3, 2024, the public preview release lets organisations orchestrate AI workloads through a unified control plane, whether those workloads are running<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/" title="ReadNew Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/">New Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence platform provider Clarifai has unveiled a new compute orchestration capability that promises to help enterprises optimise their AI workloads in any computing environment, reduce costs and avoid vendor lock-in.</p>



<p>Announced on December 3, 2024, the <a href="https://docs.clarifai.com/sdk/compute-orchestration/">public preview release</a> lets organisations orchestrate AI workloads through a unified control plane, whether those workloads are running on cloud, on-premises, or in air-gapped infrastructure. The platform can work with any AI model and hardware accelerator including GPUs, CPUs, and TPUs.</p>



<p>&#8220;Clarifai has always been ahead of the curve, with over a decade of experience supporting large enterprise and mission-critical government needs with the full stack of AI tools to create custom AI workloads,&#8221; <a href="https://www.clarifai.com/press-release/clarifai-launches-first-vendor-agnostic-compute-orchestration-capabilities-to-optimize-ai-performance-and-spend">said</a> Matt Zeiler, founder and CEO of Clarifai. &#8220;Now, we&#8217;re opening up capabilities we built internally to optimise our compute costs as we scale to serve millions of models simultaneously.&#8221;</p>



<p>The company claims its platform can reduce compute usage by 3.7x through model packing optimisations while supporting over 1.6 million inference requests per second with 99.9997% reliability. According to Clarifai, the optimisations can potentially cut costs by 60-90%, depending on configuration.</p>



<p>Capabilities of the compute orchestration platform include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Cost optimisation through automated resource management, including model packing, dependency simplification, and customisable auto-scaling options that can scale to zero for model replicas and compute nodes,</li>



<li>Deployment flexibility on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/clarifai-launches-mobile-sdk-help-make-ai-available-devices/">any hardware</a> vendor including cloud, on-premise, air-gapped, and Clarifai SaaS infrastructure,</li>



<li>Integration with Clarifai&#8217;s AI platform for data labeling, training, evaluation, workflows, and feedback,</li>



<li>Security features that allow deployment into customer VPCs or on-premise Kubernetes clusters without requiring open inbound ports, VPC peering, or custom IAM roles.</li>
</ul>



<p>The platform emerged from Clarifai customers&#8217; issues with AI performance and cost. &#8220;If we had a way to think about it holistically and look at our on-prem costs compared to our cloud costs, and then be able to orchestrate across environments with a cost basis, that would be incredibly valuable,&#8221; noted a customer, as cited in Clarifai&#8217;s announcement.</p>



<p>The compute orchestration capabilities build on Clarifai&#8217;s existing AI platform that, the company says, has processed over 2 billion operations in computer vision, language, and audio AI. The company reports maintaining 99.99%+ uptime and 24/7 availability for critical applications.</p>



<p>The compute orchestration capability is currently available in public preview. Organisations interested in testing the platform should contact Clarifai for access.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/">New Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>GitHub expands AI suite: Copilot goes multi-model, Spark debuts for web dev</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[github]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub copilot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>GitHub is marking a significant evolution of its developer tools with two major announcements: a multi-model upgrade to Copilot and the introduction of Spark, a natural language web development platform.&#160; The code hosting giant is expanding Copilot beyond its OpenAI-only architecture to include Anthropic&#8217;s Claude 3.5 Sonnet and Google&#8217;s Gemini 1.5 Pro models while simultaneously<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev/" title="ReadGitHub expands AI suite: Copilot goes multi-model, Spark debuts for web dev">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev/">GitHub expands AI suite: Copilot goes multi-model, Spark debuts for web dev</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>GitHub is marking a significant evolution of its developer tools with two major announcements: a multi-model upgrade to Copilot and the introduction of Spark, a natural language web development platform.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The code hosting giant is expanding Copilot beyond its OpenAI-only architecture to include Anthropic&#8217;s Claude 3.5 Sonnet and Google&#8217;s Gemini 1.5 Pro models while simultaneously launching GitHub Spark to simplify web application development through natural language instructions.</p>



<p>The expansion includes additional integration news as Copilot arrives on Apple&#8217;s Xcode in public preview. Since Copilot&#8217;s initial release, this three-pronged update represents GitHub&#8217;s most <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-releases-ai-powered-copilot-help-improve-code/">ambitious AI toolkit expansion</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Enhanced model support for Copilot</h3>



<p>GitHub Copilot has long leveraged different large language models (LLMs) for various use cases. The first public version of Copilot was launched using Codex, an early version of OpenAI GPT-3, specifically fine-tuned for coding tasks. Copilot Chat was launched in 2023 with GPT-3.5 and later GPT-4.</p>



<p>&#8220;Since then, we have updated the base model versions multiple times, using a range from GPT 3.5-turbo to GPT 4o and 4o-mini models for different latency and quality requirements,&#8221; Thomas Dohmke, GitHub&#8217;s CEO, said in a blog&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://github.blog/news-insights/product-news/bringing-developer-choice-to-copilot/" rel="noreferrer noopener">write-up</a>.</p>



<p>GitHub&#8217;s decision to extend Copilot&#8217;s model support beyond OpenAI&#8217;s technology represents a notable evolution in its AI-assisted development strategy. The integration now includes models from industry leaders Anthropic and Google, alongside OpenAI, providing developers access to a broader range of AI capabilities. </p>



<p>The multi-model approach suggests GitHub&#8217;s commitment to offering developers more choice and flexibility in their AI-assisted coding journey.</p>



<p>&#8220;We are bringing developer choice to GitHub Copilot with Anthropic&#8217;s Claude 3.5 Sonnet, Google&#8217;s Gemini 1.5 Pro, and OpenAI&#8217;s o1-preview and o1-mini. These new models will be rolling out—first in Copilot Chat, with OpenAI o1-preview and o1-mini available now, Claude 3.5 Sonnet rolling out progressively over the next week, and Google&#8217;s Gemini 1.5 Pro in the coming weeks. From Copilot Workspace to multi-file editing to code review, security autofix, and the CLI, we will bring multi-model choices across many of GitHub Copilot&#8217;s surface areas and functions soon,&#8221; the CEO said.</p>



<p>GitHub&#8217;s expansion of model support is particularly significant as it allows developers to leverage different AI models&#8217; strengths for various coding tasks. Each AI provider brings its own capabilities and specialisations, which could lead to more accurate and context-aware code suggestions across different programming languages and frameworks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">GitHub Spark: Natural language web development</h3>



<p>However, the company&#8217;s most intriguing announcement is the introduction of GitHub Spark, a new tool designed to revolutionise web application development and achieve GitHub&#8217;s vision of reaching one billion developers. Spark enables developers to build web applications using natural language instructions, potentially reducing the complexity and time required for web development projects.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It all starts with a spark of inspiration ✨<br><br>Bring your ideas to life and build applications entirely in natural language. Sign up for the technical preview of GitHub Spark: <a href="https://t.co/1H3QnTsuW3">https://t.co/1H3QnTsuW3</a> <a href="https://t.co/gs3AlNlNw6">pic.twitter.com/gs3AlNlNw6</a></p>&mdash; GitHub (@github) <a href="https://twitter.com/github/status/1852757148989562958?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 2, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>This natural language approach to web development could particularly benefit:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Developers looking to rapidly prototype applications,</li>



<li>Teams seeking to bridge the gap between design concepts and implementation,</li>



<li>Organisations aiming to accelerate their web development lifecycle.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Copilot arrives on Apple&#8217;s Xcode</h3>



<p>The recent release of Copilot for Apple&#8217;s Xcode in public preview form represents another milestone in GitHub&#8217;s expansion strategy. The integration brings AI-powered coding assistance to Apple&#8217;s integrated development environment, offering several advantages for iOS and macOS developers:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Real-time code suggestions within the Xcode environment,</li>



<li>Improved productivity for Swift and Objective-C development,</li>



<li>Integration with existing Xcode workflows.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Impact on developer productivity</h3>



<p>These developments in GitHub&#8217;s AI toolkit reflect a broader industry trend towards more intelligent and automated development tools. The combination of expanded model support, natural language web development, and Xcode integration suggest a comprehensive approach to enhancing developer productivity across different platforms and development scenarios.</p>



<p>For development teams, the updates could mean:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Reduced time spent on boilerplate code,</li>



<li>More efficient problem-solving through AI-assisted development,</li>



<li>Greater flexibility in choosing AI models that best suit specific project needs.</li>
</ul>



<p>Perhaps, as these tools become available to more developers, we may see shifts in how teams approach software development:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Increased adoption of AI-assisted coding practices,</li>



<li>Evolution of development workflows to incorporate natural language instructions,</li>



<li>Greater emphasis on high-level problem-solving rather than implementation details.</li>
</ul>



<p>Advancements in GitHub&#8217;s AI capabilities mark a step forward in the evolution of development tools. While maintaining the fundamental aspects of software development, the new features and integrations aim to enhance rather than replace developer expertise, potentially leading to more efficient and productive development processes.</p>



<p>The combination of expanded AI model support, GitHub Spark&#8217;s introduction, and Xcode integration represents GitHub&#8217;s holistic approach to modernising software development. As the tools mature and developers incorporate them into their workflows, we may see significant changes in how software is conceived, developed, and deployed.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://x.com/github/status/1752458943245189120/photo/1">Github</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-ceo-eu-will-define-how-world-regulates-ai/">GitHub CEO: The EU ‘will define how the world regulates AI’</a></strong><section class="entry-content" itemprop="text" style="box-sizing: inherit;"><div class="grid-x grid-margin-x margin-top-2" style="box-sizing: inherit; margin-right: -0.9375rem; margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: -0.9375rem; padding: 0px; display: flex; flex-flow: wrap; caret-color: rgb(74, 74, 74); color: rgb(74, 74, 74); font-family: Lato, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 16px; white-space: normal; margin-top: 2rem !important;"></div></section></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev/">GitHub expands AI suite: Copilot goes multi-model, Spark debuts for web dev</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/github-expands-ai-suite-copilot-goes-multi-model-spark-debuts-for-web-dev/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bridging code and conscience: UMD&#8217;s quest for ethical and inclusive AI</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As artificial intelligence systems increasingly permeate critical decision-making processes in our everyday lives, the integration of ethical frameworks into AI development is becoming a research priority. At the University of Maryland (UMD), interdisciplinary teams tackle the complex interplay between normative reasoning, machine learning algorithms, and socio-technical systems.  In a recent interview with Artificial Intelligence News,<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai/" title="ReadBridging code and conscience: UMD&#8217;s quest for ethical and inclusive AI">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai/">Bridging code and conscience: UMD&#8217;s quest for ethical and inclusive AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As artificial intelligence systems increasingly permeate critical decision-making processes in our everyday lives, the integration of ethical frameworks into AI development is becoming a research priority. At the University of Maryland (UMD), <a href="https://today.umd.edu/umd-launches-institute-focused-on-ethical-ai-development">interdisciplinary teams</a> tackle the complex interplay between normative reasoning, machine learning algorithms, and socio-technical systems. </p>



<p>In a recent interview with <em>Artificial Intelligence News</em>, postdoctoral researchers <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/ilariacanavotto/">Ilaria Canavotto</a> and <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Vaishnav-Kameswaran">Vaishnav Kameswaran</a> combine expertise in philosophy, computer science, and human-computer interaction <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-big-data-expo-ethical-ai-integration-future-trends/">to address pressing challenges</a> in AI ethics. Their work spans the theoretical foundations of embedding ethical principles into AI architectures and the practical implications of AI deployment in high-stakes domains such as employment.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Normative understanding of AI systems</h3>



<p>Ilaria Canavotto, a researcher at UMD&#8217;s Values-Centered Artificial Intelligence (VCAI) initiative, is affiliated with the Institute for Advanced Computer Studies and the Philosophy Department. She is tackling a fundamental question: How can we imbue AI systems with normative understanding? As AI increasingly influences decisions that impact human rights and well-being, systems have to comprehend ethical and legal norms.</p>



<p>&#8220;The question that I investigate is, how do we get this kind of information, this normative understanding of the world, into a machine that could be a robot, a chatbot, anything like that?&#8221; Canavotto says.</p>



<p>Her research combines two approaches:</p>



<p><strong>Top-down approach</strong>: This traditional method involves explicitly programming rules and norms into the system. However, Canavotto points out, &#8220;It&#8217;s just impossible to write them down as easily. There are always new situations that come up.&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Bottom-up approach</strong>: A newer method that uses machine learning to extract rules from data. While more flexible, it lacks transparency: &#8220;The problem with this approach is that we don&#8217;t really know what the system learns, and it&#8217;s very difficult to explain its decision,&#8221; Canavotto notes.</p>



<p>Canavotto and her colleagues, Jeff Horty and Eric Pacuit, are developing a hybrid approach to combine the best of both approaches. They aim to create AI systems that can learn rules from data while maintaining explainable decision-making processes grounded in legal and normative reasoning.</p>



<p>&#8220;[Our] approach […] is based on a field that is called artificial intelligence and law. So, in this field, they developed algorithms to extract information from the data. So we would like to generalise some of these algorithms and then have a system that can more generally extract information grounded in legal reasoning and normative reasoning,&#8221; she explains.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">AI&#8217;s impact on hiring practices and disability inclusion</h3>



<p>While Canavotto focuses on the theoretical foundations, Vaishnav Kameswaran, affiliated with UMD&#8217;s NSF Institute for Trustworthy AI and Law and Society, examines AI&#8217;s real-world implications, particularly its impact on people with disabilities.</p>



<p>Kameswaran&#8217;s research looks into the use of AI in hiring processes, uncovering how systems can inadvertently discriminate against candidates with disabilities. He explains, &#8220;We&#8217;ve been working to&#8230; open up the black box a little, try to understand what these algorithms do on the back end, and how they begin to assess candidates.&#8221;</p>



<p>His findings reveal that many AI-driven hiring platforms rely heavily on normative behavioural cues, such as eye contact and facial expressions, to assess candidates. This approach can significantly disadvantage individuals with specific disabilities. For instance, visually impaired candidates may struggle with maintaining eye contact, a signal that AI systems often interpret as lack of engagement.</p>



<p>&#8220;By focusing on some of those qualities and assessing candidates based on those qualities, these platforms tend to exacerbate existing social inequalities,&#8221; Kameswaran warns. He argues that this trend could further marginalise people with disabilities in the workforce, a group already facing significant employment challenges.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The broader ethical landscape</strong></h2>



<p>Both researchers emphasise that the ethical concerns surrounding AI extend far beyond their specific areas of study. They touch on several key issues:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Data privacy and consent:</strong>&nbsp;The researchers highlight the inadequacy of current consent mechanisms, especially regarding data collection for AI training. Kameswaran cites examples from his work in India, where vulnerable populations unknowingly surrendered extensive personal data to AI-driven loan platforms during the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>



<li><strong>Transparency and explainability:</strong>&nbsp;Both researchers stress the importance of understanding how AI systems make decisions, especially when these decisions significantly impact people&#8217;s lives.</li>



<li><strong>Societal attitudes and biases: </strong>Kameswaran points out that technical solutions alone cannot solve discrimination issues. There&#8217;s a need for broader societal changes in attitudes towards marginalised groups, including people with disabilities.</li>



<li><strong>Interdisciplinary collaboration</strong>: The researchers&#8217; work at UMD exemplifies the importance of cooperation between philosophy, computer science, and other disciplines in addressing AI ethics.</li>
</ol>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Looking ahead: solutions and challenges</h3>



<p>While the challenges are significant, both researchers are working towards solutions:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Canavotto&#8217;s hybrid approach to normative AI could lead to more ethically-aware and explainable AI systems.</li>



<li>Kameswaran suggests developing audit tools for advocacy groups to assess AI hiring platforms for potential discrimination.</li>



<li>Both emphasise the need for policy changes, such as updating the Americans with Disabilities Act to address AI-related discrimination.</li>
</ul>



<p>However, they also acknowledge the complexity of the issues. As Kameswaran notes, &#8220;Unfortunately, I don&#8217;t think that a technical solution to training AI with certain kinds of data and auditing tools is in itself going to solve a problem. So it requires a multi-pronged approach.&#8221;</p>



<p>A key takeaway from the researchers&#8217; work is the need for greater public awareness about AI&#8217;s impact on our lives. People need to know how much data they share or how it&#8217;s being used. As Canavotto points out, companies often have an incentive to obscure this information, defining them as &#8220;Companies that try to tell you my service is going to be better for you if you give me the data.&#8221;</p>



<p>The researchers argue that much more needs to be done to educate the public and hold companies accountable. Ultimately, Canavotto and Kameswaran&#8217;s interdisciplinary approach, combining philosophical inquiry with practical application, is a path forward in the right direction, ensuring that AI systems are powerful but also ethical and equitable.</p>



<p><strong><em>See also:</em></strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/">Regulations to help or hinder: Cloudflare’s take</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai/">Bridging code and conscience: UMD&#8217;s quest for ethical and inclusive AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/bridging-code-and-conscience-umds-quest-for-ethical-and-inclusive-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regulations to help or hinder: Cloudflare&#8217;s take</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 11:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber securitty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As AI reshapes the digital landscape, tech companies find themselves in a high-stakes game of regulatory chess, with each move potentially changing the possibilities stemming from innovation. The game board is especially intricate for global infrastructure providers like Cloudflare, involving as it does cybersecurity, data privacy, and content moderation in a complex policy framework. “No<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/" title="ReadRegulations to help or hinder: Cloudflare&#8217;s take">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/">Regulations to help or hinder: Cloudflare&#8217;s take</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As AI reshapes the digital landscape, tech companies find themselves in a high-stakes game of regulatory chess, with each move potentially changing the possibilities stemming from innovation. The game board is especially intricate for global infrastructure providers like Cloudflare, involving as it does cybersecurity, data privacy, and content moderation in a complex policy framework.</p>



<p>“No one wants to miss the boat,” says Alissa Starzak, the company’s deputy chief legal officer and global head of public policy, referring to the rush to regulate AI. Yet, she cautions the tension between urgent action and measured response that encapsulates the complex balancing act Cloudflare navigates daily.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with <em>Artificial Intelligence News</em>, Starzak revealed how the internet infrastructure giant is working to shape a regulatory framework that fosters innovation while safeguarding against emerging cyber threats.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a><strong>The AI regulatory conundrum: Speed vs.&nbsp;caution</strong><strong></strong></h3>



<p>Regulators worldwide face the question of how to mandate as AI technology advances. Urgency is muted by a significant fact: the main dimensions of potential AI are not fully understood yet. “No one really knows yet,” Starzak said, highlighting the challenge of crafting regulations for a technology with unknown scope.</p>



<p>A lack of knowledge has led to producing responsible AI development and deployment frameworks that are speculative. An example would be the AI risk framework set by the <a href="https://www.nist.gov">National Institute of Standards and Technology</a>&nbsp;(NIST), which Starzak said were meaningful steps towards the goal. Voluntary guidelines provide companies with a roadmap for creating AI risk assessment measures and encourage them to do so without <a href="https://techhq.com/2024/09/europes-tech-wake-up-call-draghis-plan-to-close-the-innovation-gap/">stifling innovation</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a><strong>The tightrope of global regulatory harmonisation</strong><strong></strong></h3>



<p>Cloudflare is congnisant of the complexities of achieving regulatory harmony across different jurisdictions, particularly in data protection and privacy. Starzak used the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) to illustrate the benefits and challenges of sweeping regulatory frameworks.</p>



<p>It is noteworthy that GDPR has a significant role in consolidating privacy norms internationally. Starzak said that its real-life application does not always harmonise with the functioning of the internet. “It doesn’t actually feel like the way the internet necessarily works in practice,” she said, referring to restrictions on data transfers between jurisdictions.</p>



<p>This disconnect highlights a broader challenge: crafting regulations that protect consumers and national interests without impeding the global nature of the internet and digital commerce. Starzak emphasised the need for regulatory mechanisms that are “consistent across jurisdiction to jurisdiction, but enable information to travel.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a><strong>The imperative of targeted, narrow actions</strong><strong></strong></h3>



<p>Starzak advocates for a more nuanced, targeted approach to cybersecurity measures and content moderation. Her philosophy is rooted in recognising that broad, sweeping actions often have unintended consequences that can harm the ecosystem they aim to protect.</p>



<p>In terms of cybersecurity, Starzak stressed the importance of proportionality. She drew a stark contrast between targeted actions, like removing a specific piece of content, and drastic measures, like complete internet shutdowns. “The narrower that you can go, the better off you’re going to be from an open internet standpoint,” she said.</p>



<p>The principle extends to content moderation as well. As Starzak describes, the approach by Cloudflare involves carefully distinguishing between different types of services and their impacts. By doing so, the company aims to make more precise, effective decisions that address specific issues without unnecessarily compromising the broader internet ecosystem.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a><strong>Balancing innovation and regulation in AI</strong><strong></strong></h3>



<p>The rapid advancement of AI technology presents a unique regulatory challenge. Starzak highlighted the risk of over-regulation stifling innovation and concentrating power in the hands of a few large players. “If you regulate it too much, you restrict the industry in a very significant way and make it really only available to a very small number of players,” she said.</p>



<p>Starzak advocates a regulatory approach that encourages responsible innovation while addressing potential harms. This includes promoting the development and adoption of AI risk assessment frameworks and encouraging industry self-regulation through model testing and ‘red teaming.’</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The path forward: collaboration and flexibility</strong><strong></strong></h3>



<p>Starzak emphasises the need for ongoing dialogue and flexibility in regulatory approaches to AI and cybersecurity. She highlighted the importance of industry, government, and civil society collaboration to develop effective, balanced regulations.</p>



<p>According to Starzak, the key is to focus on specific harms and consumer protection rather than broad, sweeping regulations. “You have to go in with a purpose,” she stated, urging regulators to understand and articulate the problems they’re trying to solve.</p>



<p>A targeted approach, combined with willingness to adapt as technologies evolve offers a path forward through the complex internet and AI regulation world. As Cloudflare continues to navigate this landscape, Starzak’s insights provide a roadmap for balancing innovation, security, and responsible governance.</p>



<p>As the tech industry and regulators grapple with the challenge of creating effective governance frameworks, Cloudflare’s approach emphasises targeted actions, global harmonisation efforts, and regulatory flexibility. It represents a thoughtful perspective in the dialogue between tech companies and policymakers.</p>



<p>The way forward likely involves collaborative efforts from various stakeholders, including industry leaders, government bodies, and civil society organisations. The focus remains on striking a balance between protecting users and fostering innovation. This goal requires ongoing adaptation and cooperation across the tech ecosystem.</p>



<p><strong>See</strong>&nbsp;<strong>also:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/">Balancing innovation and trust: Experts assess the EU’s AI Act</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/">Regulations to help or hinder: Cloudflare&#8217;s take</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/regulations-to-help-or-hinder-cloudflares-take/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Has Huawei outsmarted Apple in the AI race?</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What was supposed to herald a new era of AI for Apple has instead left many underwhelmed when the tech giant unveiled the iPhone 16 series, its first AI-powered smartphone line-up, which happens to be still in beta testing and expected to take months, if not years, to fully roll out globally.&#160;To make matters worse<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/" title="ReadHas Huawei outsmarted Apple in the AI race?">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/">Has Huawei outsmarted Apple in the AI race?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>What was supposed to herald a new era of AI for Apple has instead left many underwhelmed when the tech giant unveiled the iPhone 16 series, its first AI-powered smartphone line-up, which happens to be still in beta testing and expected to take months, if not years, to fully roll out globally.&nbsp;To make matters worse for the Cupertino, California-based smartphone maker, Chinese tech giant Huawei launched its new Mate XT smartphone just hours after the former&#8217;s event, boasting far more impressive AI features powered by Huawei&#8217;s in-house Kylin chips.</p>



<p>Huawei&#8217;s move showcases its ability to innovate despite facing US sanctions, but it also spells uncertainty for Apple&#8217;s market share in Mainland China, one of its most crucial markets. Let&#8217;s explore why.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Huawei Mate XT <br><br>The world&#39;s first triple-foldable phone,<br> <a href="https://t.co/BVFS7f34JD">pic.twitter.com/BVFS7f34JD</a></p>&mdash; Science girl (@gunsnrosesgirl3) <a href="https://twitter.com/gunsnrosesgirl3/status/1833591820338516074?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Apple and its AI gambit: Worth the hype?</h3>



<p>The delay in rolling out AI features has led many industry analysts to question whether Apple&#8217;s AI push is ready for prime time. &#8220;With lots of words like &#8216;later this year&#8217; and &#8216;early next year&#8217;, the core Apple message for iPhone 16 was: Next year will be better,&#8221;&nbsp;<em><a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/apples-ai-gap-new-iphones-disappoints-china-users-huawei-threat-looms-2024-09-10/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reuters</a></em>&nbsp;quoted Needham analyst Laura Martin.</p>



<p>Apple&#8217;s <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/09/apple-debuts-iphone-16-pro-and-iphone-16-pro-max/">suite of tools</a>, collectively known as Apple Intelligence, has been in development for some time. The company has touted the technology since its developer&#8217;s conference in June. However, the software won&#8217;t be included in the initial versions of the new iPhones, and many key features won&#8217;t arrive until next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For now, the technology primarily focuses on summarising messages and notifications rather than matching the more advanced capabilities of rival systems.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Apple Event - September 9" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uarNiSl_uh4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Delayed AI features in iPhone 16 dampen enthusiasm–especially in China</h3>



<p>In China, the excitement of the launch of the iPhone 16 series on Monday quickly turned to disappointment for many local Apple users when they learned that the AI features would not be immediately available in their language until next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, Huawei&#8217;s AI assistant, with text summary, translation, and editing functions, and AI-boosted image editing functions, such as trimming unwanted parts of photos, will be readily available once Mate XT goes on sale later this month. This delay has prompted scepticism about the value proposition of the new iPhones in China, especially given the fierce competition from local rivals like Huawei.</p>



<p>&#8220;The absence of AI in China is akin to cutting one of Apple&#8217;s arms,&#8221; one commentator remarked on Weibo, China&#8217;s popular microblogging platform. Another user pointedly asked, &#8220;With the biggest selling point unavailable, shouldn&#8217;t you charge us half the price?&#8221; These sentiments reflect a growing frustration among Chinese consumers who feel they are not getting the total value of Apple&#8217;s latest innovations, according to&nbsp;<em><a target="_blank" href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3277959/apples-ai-delay-dents-iphone-16-enthusiasm-china-huawei-gets-ready-pounce" rel="noreferrer noopener">South China Morning Post</a></em>.</p>



<p>In contrast, Huawei&#8217;s new Mate XT, which users can fold three ways like an accordion screen door, has already received more than four million pre-orders, for which no deposit is required, according to the company&#8217;s website. According to research firm IDC, the global market for foldable phones was around 4 million units in the second quarter.</p>



<p>&#8220;Today, we bring you a product everyone can think of but could not make. Our team has been working hard for five years and has never given up,&#8221; Huawei executive director Richard Yu said at the launch.</p>



<p>On the other hand, Apple has yet to announce an AI partner in China to power Apple Intelligence. This is because the uncertain regulatory landscape in mainland China adds to the complexity of the situation. The country&#8217;s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology has approved 188 large language models for public use, none of which are from foreign companies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This raises questions about whether Apple&#8217;s AI features will be available in mainland China even when rolled out in other Chinese-speaking regions. Apple has stated on its website that the launch date of its AI feature in China will depend on the decision of Chinese regulators.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Apple has to catch up, and it has to be fast. Apple sales have been dwindling, and the company&#8217;s ranking in the world&#8217;s second-largest economy has dropped from third to sixth place. This is even though Apple has long experienced robust demand in China, where new iPhone debuts have historically caused a frenzy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The industry took a surprising turn when Shenzhen-based Huawei returned to the high-end smartphone sector last year with the debut of a device powered by a domestically manufactured chip. This defied US sanctions that had cut off access to the global chipset supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Mate 60 Pro&#8217;s debut startled analysts and US officials. In addition, Huawei started offering two-way foldable phones in its inventory, and strong sales in China helped it beat Samsung Electronics as the world&#8217;s largest vendor of such phones earlier this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The delay with Apple Intelligence in China will give competitors like Huawei a window of opportunity to capture market share and establish themselves as leaders in AI-powered smartphones within their home turf. This could make it more challenging for Apple to regain ground once its AI features finally arrive in the country.</p>



<p>Ultimately, Apple&#8217;s AI ambitions in China represent a high-stakes gamble for the tech giant. While the company&#8217;s brand still holds significant appeal, the delayed rollout of AI features and intense competition from resurgent local players like Huawei pose serious challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the smartphone market in China continues to evolve, Apple&#8217;s ability to adapt its AI strategy to local conditions may determine its future success in this critical market.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@picsbyjameslee?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">James Lee</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/could-apple-meta-partnership-redefine-ai-landscape/">Could an Apple-Meta partnership redefine the AI landscape?</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/">Has Huawei outsmarted Apple in the AI race?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Just three months after its inception, Safe Superintelligence (SSI), a new AI startup founded by OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever, has raised $1 billion in funding. Led by venture capital firms Sequoia and Andreessen Horowitz, the latest investment round values the company at approximately $5 billion, according to a Financial Times report. Sutskever, who left OpenAI in May<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/" title="ReadOpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/">OpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just three months after its inception, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/">Safe Superintelligence</a> (SSI), a new AI startup founded by OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever, has raised $1 billion in funding. Led by venture capital firms Sequoia and Andreessen Horowitz, the latest investment round values the company at approximately $5 billion, according to a <em>Financial Times</em> <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2988c7a3-0e70-4c5d-a3f3-665c2d0c37d3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">report</a>.</p>



<p>Sutskever, who left OpenAI in May this year following a failed attempt to oust CEO Sam Altman, established SSI to develop &#8216;safe&#8217;&nbsp;AI models. The company&#8217;s mission is to create AI systems that are both highly capable and aligned with human interests.</p>



<p>&#8216;We&#8217;ve identified a new mountain to climb that is slightly different from what I was working on previously. We&#8217;re not trying to go down the same path faster. If you do something different, it becomes possible for you to do something special, Sutskever told the&nbsp;<em>Financial Times</em>.</p>



<p>The substantial funding will be used to acquire computing resources necessary for AI model development and to expand SSI&#8217;s current team of 10 employees. The company actively recruits and offers positions in Palo Alto, California, and Tel Aviv, Israel.</p>



<p>With its focus on safety and alignment, SSI&#8217;s approach differs from that of other AI companies. Take firms like <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-delivers-gpt-4o-fine-tuning/">OpenAI</a>, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/authors-file-lawsuit-against-anthropic-over-pirated-works/">Anthropic</a>, and <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/">Elon Musk&#8217;s xAI</a>, which are all developing AI models for various consumer and business applications. SSI, on the other hand, is focusing solely on creating what it calls a &#8216;<a href="https://ssi.inc/">straight shot </a>to safe superintelligence&#8217;.</p>



<p>Daniel Gross, SSI&#8217;s chief executive, emphasised the importance of this focused approach in a statement to <em><a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/openai-co-founder-sutskevers-new-safety-focused-ai-startup-ssi-raises-1-billion-2024-09-04/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reuters</a></em>: &#8220;It&#8217;s important for us to be surrounded by investors who understand, respect and support our mission, which is to make a straight shot to safe superintelligence and in particular to spend a couple of years doing R&amp;D on our product before bringing it to market.&#8221;</p>



<p>It is also interesting to point out that despite not having a product yet, the company&#8217;s significant valuation and funding highlight the intense interest and investment in safe AI research. This is amid growing concerns about the potential risks associated with increasingly powerful AI systems.</p>



<p>Even Sutskever&#8217;s departure from OpenAI was reportedly <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-warns-california-ai-bill-threatens-us-innovation/">due to disagreements</a> over the company&#8217;s direction and the pace of AI development. At OpenAI, he led the &#8216;alignment&#8217;&nbsp;team, which focused on ensuring that advanced AI systems would act in humanity&#8217;s best interests.</p>



<p>What is clear, however, is that the formation of SSI and its rapid funding success reflect a broader trend in the AI industry towards addressing safety concerns alongside capability advancements. This approach aligns with calls from AI researchers and ethicists for more responsible development of artificial intelligence.</p>



<p>Today, SSI joins a competitive field of well-funded AI companies. OpenAI is reportedly in talks to raise funds at a valuation exceeding $100 billion, while Anthropic and xAI were recently valued at around $20 billion.</p>



<p>However, the crowded market did not dim SSI&#8217;s unique focus on safety or its high-profile founding team, both of which have clearly resonated with investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;We are assembling a lean, cracked team of the world&#8217;s best engineers and researchers dedicated to focusing on SSI and nothing else. We offer an opportunity to do your life&#8217;s work and help solve our age&#8217;s most important technical challenge,&#8221; the company&#8217;s website states.</p>



<p>For now, the company&#8217;s progress will be closely watched by both the tech industry and those concerned with the ethical implications of AI development.</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-hit-leadership-exodus-as-three-key-figures-depart/">OpenAI hit by leadership exodus as three key figures depart</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/">OpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IDC: GenAI smartphones to drive global shipment growth in 2024</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 10:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>IDC has revised its global smartphone shipments forecast 2024, projecting a 5.8% year-on-year (YoY) growth to 1.23 billion units. The market intelligence firm&#8217;s optimistic outlook is driven by strong growth in affordable Android devices across emerging markets and substantial interest in generative AI-capable smartphones in premium segments. IDC&#8217;s senior research director, Nabila Popal, noted that Android devices<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024/" title="ReadIDC: GenAI smartphones to drive global shipment growth in 2024">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024/">IDC: GenAI smartphones to drive global shipment growth in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>IDC has revised its global smartphone shipments forecast 2024, projecting a 5.8% year-on-year (YoY) growth to 1.23 billion units. The market intelligence firm&#8217;s <a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=IDC_P8397" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">optimistic outlook</a> is driven by strong growth in affordable Android devices across emerging markets and substantial interest in generative AI-capable smartphones in premium segments.</p>



<p>IDC&#8217;s senior research director, Nabila Popal, noted that Android devices are expected to see growth rates nine times faster than iOS at 7.1% compared to 0.8%. This disparity is attributed to increasing competition for Apple in China and a higher comparison base year for the iPhone maker.</p>



<p>However, the forecast suggests potential upside for iOS, depending on the reception of GenAI features in the upcoming iPhone 16 and Apple&#8217;s ability to establish local AI partnerships in China. IDC anticipates an improved trajectory for iOS in 2025, with 4% YoY growth expected due to the anticipated momentum of Apple Intelligence.</p>



<p>The report highlights the rapid adoption of GenAI smartphones, forecasting a 344% growth in this segment to capture 18% of the total market by the end of 2024. IDC research director Anthony Scarsella pointed out that most flagship models will likely incorporate some on-device GenAI features.</p>



<p>&#8220;Although GenAI smartphones are relatively new in the market, premium flagships will continue to adopt GenAI features to help separate them from the pack,&#8221; said Anthony Scarsella, research director for IDC&#8217;s <a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=IDC_P8397" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Worldwide Quarterly Mobile Phone Tracker</a>. Notably, the average selling price for GenAI-capable smartphones is expected to be more than double that of non-GenAI devices, further driving the premiumisation trend in the industry.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="699" height="548" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15915" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1.png 699w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1-300x235.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1-255x200.png 255w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1-364x285.png 364w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1-319x250.png 319w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1-100x78.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IDC-Worldwide-Smartphone-Market-Forecast-to-Grow-Nearly-6-in-2024-Driven-by-Stronger-Growth-for-Android-in-China-and-Emerging-Markets-According-to-IDC-2024-Aug-F-1-60x47.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 699px) 100vw, 699px" /></figure>



<p>The smartphone market&#8217;s recovery comes after a challenging period. IDC&#8217;s data shows 12% growth in the first quarter of 2024, followed by 9% growth in the second quarter. This positive trend has bolstered confidence in the industry&#8217;s performance for the latter half of the year.</p>



<p>Even the latest Canalys research revealed that the<a target="_blank" href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/the-global-smartphone-market-Q2-2024" rel="noreferrer noopener">&nbsp;worldwide smartphone market</a>&nbsp;grew strongly in the second quarter of 2024, with shipments reaching 288.9 million units. &#8220;The market has grown for three consecutive quarters, driven by product innovation initiatives and improvements in business conditions,&#8221; Canalys stated.</p>



<p>Mirroring IDC&#8217;s data, Canalys noted that despite a modest 1% shipment increase, Samsung held onto pole position with 53.5 million units shipped. Meanwhile, Apple held second place with 45.6 million units, bolstered by solid momentum in North America and APAC&#8217;s emerging markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China&#8217;s Xiaomi, with its competitive product offerings, followed closely with shipments of 42.3 million units to achieve a market share of 15%. &#8220;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/china-smartphone-market-Q2-2024" rel="noreferrer noopener">Greater China&#8217;s growth</a>&nbsp;trajectory now mirrors global markets, driven by improved macroeconomic conditions and renewed business confidence among channel and smartphone brands,&#8221; the report stated.</p>



<p>Like elsewhere, the Chinese domestic market will see local Chinese brands use GenAI features <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/huawei-ai-higher-intelligence-smartphones/">to stand out in the premium segment</a>, aiming to capture rising high-end spending and apply successful strategies worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;Samsung will inevitably focus on integrating its Galaxy ecosystem to create strong value propositions for consumers via its flagship offerings with exclusive GenAI features,&#8221; Canalys Senior Analyst Sanyam Chaurasia said. Apple will look to accelerate replacement demand in these markets via&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.canalys.com/insights/apple-unveils-its-ai-strategy-at-wwdc" rel="noreferrer noopener">its AI strategy</a>, with hybrid models, enhanced privacy and personalised Siri features.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even Canalys doesn&#8217;t foresee the smartphone market seeing double-digit growth in 2024 despite the seasonal demand in the year&#8217;s second half. Overall, the global technology market analyst firm anticipates the smartphone market to grow in the mid-single digits in 2024, driven by recovering inventory levels, eased import restrictions, and a better economic climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@sammysays___?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Samuel Angor</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/arm-unveils-new-ai-designs-and-software-for-smartphones/">Arm unveils new AI designs and software for smartphones</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024/">IDC: GenAI smartphones to drive global shipment growth in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/idc-genai-smartphones-drive-global-shipment-growth-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chinese organisations are utilising cloud services from Amazon and its competitors to gain access to advanced US AI chips and capabilities that they cannot otherwise obtain, according to a Reuters report based on public tender documents. In a comprehensive investigation, Reuters revealed how Chinese cloud access to US AI chips is facilitated through intermediaries. Over<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/" title="ReadChinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Chinese organisations are utilising cloud services from Amazon and its competitors to gain access to advanced US AI chips and capabilities that they cannot otherwise obtain, according to a Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinese-entities-turn-amazon-cloud-its-rivals-access-high-end-us-chips-ai-2024-08-23/">report</a> based on public tender documents.</p>



<p>In a comprehensive investigation, Reuters revealed how Chinese cloud access to US AI chips is facilitated through intermediaries. Over 50 tender documents posted in the past year revealed that at least 11 Chinese entities have sought access to restricted US technologies or cloud services. Four of these explicitly named Amazon Web Services (AWS) as a cloud service provider, though accessed through Chinese intermediaries rather than directly from AWS.</p>



<p>&#8220;AWS complies with all applicable US laws, including trade laws, regarding the provision of AWS services inside and outside of China,&#8221; an AWS spokesperson told Reuters.</p>



<p>The report highlights that while the US government has restricted the export of high-end AI chips to China, providing access to such chips or advanced AI models through the cloud is not a violation of US regulations. This loophole has raised concerns among US officials and lawmakers.</p>



<p>One example cited in the report involves Shenzhen University, which spent 200,000 yuan (£21,925) on an AWS account to access cloud servers powered by Nvidia A100 and H100 chips for an unspecified project. The university obtained this service via an intermediary, Yunda Technology Ltd Co. Neither Shenzhen University nor Yunda Technology responded to Reuters&#8217; requests for comment.</p>



<p>The investigation also revealed that Zhejiang Lab, a research institute developing its own large language model called GeoGPT, stated in a tender document that it intended to spend 184,000 yuan to purchase AWS cloud computing services. The institute claimed that its AI model could not get enough computing power from homegrown Alibaba cloud services.</p>



<p>Michael McCaul, chair of the US House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Committee, told <em>Reuters</em>: &#8220;This loophole has been a concern of mine for years, and we are long overdue to address it.&#8221;</p>



<p>In response to these concerns, the US Commerce Department is tightening rules. A government spokeswoman told Reuters that they are &#8220;seeking additional resources to strengthen our existing controls that restrict PRC companies from accessing advanced AI chips through remote access to cloud computing capability.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Commerce Department has also proposed a rule that would require US cloud computing firms to verify large AI model users and notify authorities when they use US cloud computing services to train large AI models capable of &#8220;malicious cyber-enabled activity.&#8221;</p>



<p>The study also found that Chinese companies are seeking access to Microsoft&#8217;s cloud services. For example, Sichuan University stated in a tender filing that it was developing a generative AI platform and would purchase 40 million Microsoft Azure OpenAI tokens to help with project delivery.</p>



<p>Reuters’ report also indicated that Amazon has provided Chinese businesses with access to modern AI chips as well as advanced AI models such as Anthropic&#8217;s Claude, which they would not otherwise have had. This was demonstrated by public postings, tenders, and marketing materials evaluated by the news organisation.</p>



<p>Chu Ruisong, President of AWS Greater China, stated during a generative AI-themed conference in Shanghai in May that &#8220;Bedrock provides a selection of leading LLMs, including prominent closed-source models such as Anthropic&#8217;s Claude 3.&#8221;</p>



<p>The report overall emphasises the difficulty of regulating access to advanced computing resources in an increasingly interconnected global technological ecosystem. It focuses on the intricate relationship between US export laws, cloud service providers, and Chinese enterprises looking to improve their AI capabilities.</p>



<p>As the US government works to close this gap, the scenario raises concerns about the efficacy of present export controls and the potential need for more comprehensive laws that cover cloud-based access to banned technologies.</p>



<p>The findings of this paper are likely to feed ongoing discussions about technology transfer, national security, and the global AI race. As politicians and industry leaders analyse these findings, they may spark fresh discussions about how to balance technological cooperation with national security concerns in an era of rapid AI growth.</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/globaldata-china-is-ahead-of-global-rivals-for-ai-unicorns/">GlobalData: China is ahead of global rivals for AI ‘unicorns’</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
