<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>AGI - AI News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/agi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/agi/</link>
	<description>Artificial Intelligence News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:54:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/ai-icon-60x60.png</url>
	<title>AGI - AI News</title>
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/agi/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The emerging US-China Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) rivalry could face a major policy transformation, as the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) recommends a Manhattan Project-style initiative and restrictions on humanoid robots in its latest report to Congress. Released in November 2024, the Commission&#8217;s annual report outlined 32 recommendations that could fundamentally alter how the two countries<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/" title="ReadManhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/">Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The emerging US-China Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) rivalry could face a major policy transformation, as the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Comprehensive_List_of_Recommendations.pdf">recommends</a> a Manhattan Project-style initiative and restrictions on humanoid robots in its latest report to Congress.</p>



<p>Released in November 2024, the Commission&#8217;s <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Annual_Report_to_Congress.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annual report</a> outlined <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Executive_Summary.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">32 recommendations</a> that could fundamentally alter how the two countries interact, with artificial intelligence taking centre stage in a new chapter of strategic rivalry.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">US-China: the AGI moonshot and critical tech controls</h3>



<p>At the heart of the report lies an ambitious proposal: establishing a government-backed programme to develop AGI &#8211; AI systems that could match and potentially exceed human cognitive abilities. </p>



<p>However, the recommendation is just one piece of a larger technological puzzle, including export controls, investment screening, and new trade policies to preserve US technological advantages. </p>



<p>The proposed AGI initiative would provide multi-year contracts to leading AI companies, cloud providers, and data centre operators. It would be backed by the Defense Department&#8217;s highest priority, &#8220;DX Rating&#8221; &#8211; a designation typically reserved for critical national security projects. </p>



<p>This level of government involvement in AI development mirrors the urgency seen in previous technological races. It raises crucial questions about the role of state intervention in an industry primarily driven by private sector innovation.</p>



<p>The Commission&#8217;s tech-focused recommendations extend beyond AI. Notable proposals include restricting imports of Chinese-made autonomous humanoid robots with advanced dexterity, locomotion, and intelligence capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report also targets energy infrastructure products with remote monitoring capabilities, reflecting growing concerns about connected technologies in critical infrastructure. The report builds on existing export controls in the semiconductor space by recommending stronger oversight of technology transfers and investment flows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This comes as China continues to build domestic chip-making capabilities despite international restrictions. The Commission suggests creating an Outbound Investment Office that prevents US capital and expertise from advancing China&#8217;s technological capabilities in sensitive sectors.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Reshaping trade relations and investment flows</h3>



<p>Perhaps most significantly, the report recommends eliminating China&#8217;s Permanent Normal Trade Relations (PNTR) status—a move that could reshape the technology supply chain and trade flows that have defined the global tech industry for decades. This recommendation acknowledges how deeply intertwined the US and Chinese tech ecosystems have become, while suggesting that this interdependence may now pose more risks than benefits.</p>



<p>Data transparency is another key theme, with recommendations for expanded reporting requirements on investments and technology transfers. The Commission calls for better tracking of investments flowing through offshore entities, addressing a significant blind-spot in current oversight mechanisms.</p>



<p>The report&#8217;s release comes at a critical juncture in technological development. China&#8217;s push for self-sufficiency in vital technologies and its &#8220;new quality productive forces&#8221; initiative demonstrates Beijing&#8217;s determination to lead in next-generation technologies. Meanwhile, AI capabilities and quantum computing breakthroughs have raised the stakes in technology competition.</p>



<p>However, the Commission&#8217;s recommendations face practical challenges. Achieving AGI remains a complex scientific challenge that may not yield quick results, regardless of funding levels. Additionally, restrictions on technology transfers and investment could have unintended consequences for global innovation networks that have historically benefited both nations.</p>



<p>If these recommendations are implemented, the tech industry may need to navigate an increasingly complex regulatory landscape. Companies would face new compliance requirements for international investments, technology transfers, and collaborative research projects.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Challenges and future implications</h3>



<p>The effectiveness of the proposed measures will likely depend on coordination with allies and partners who share similar technological capabilities and concerns. The report acknowledges this by recommending multilateral approaches to export controls and investment screening.</p>



<p>US-China technological competition has entered a new phase where government policy may play a more direct role in shaping development. Whether this approach accelerates or hinders innovation remains to be seen, but the tech industry should prepare for increased scrutiny and regulation of international technological collaboration.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nathangbingle?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nathan Bingle</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:844px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/">Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ASI Alliance launches AIRIS that ‘learns’ in Minecraft</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 16:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben goertzel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fetch ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fetch.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singularitynet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The ASI Alliance has introduced AIRIS (Autonomous Intelligent Reinforcement Inferred Symbolism) that “learns” within the popular game, Minecraft. AIRIS represents the first proto-AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) to harness a comprehensive tech stack across the alliance. SingularityNET, founded by renowned AI researcher Dr Ben Goertzel, uses agent technology from Fetch.ai, incorporates Ocean Data for long-term memory<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft/" title="ReadASI Alliance launches AIRIS that ‘learns’ in Minecraft">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft/">ASI Alliance launches AIRIS that ‘learns’ in Minecraft</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="https://www.superintelligence.io/">ASI Alliance</a> has introduced AIRIS (Autonomous Intelligent Reinforcement Inferred Symbolism) that “learns” within the popular game, <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/">Minecraft</a>.</p>



<p>AIRIS represents the first proto-AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) to harness a comprehensive tech stack across the alliance.</p>



<p>SingularityNET, founded by renowned AI researcher <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Goertzel">Dr Ben Goertzel</a>, uses agent technology from Fetch.ai, incorporates Ocean Data for long-term memory capabilities, and is soon expected to integrate CUDOS Compute infrastructure for scalable processing power.</p>



<p>“AIRIS is a significant step in the direction of practical, scalable neural-symbolic learning, and – alongside its already powerful and valuable functionality – it illustrates several general points about neural-symbolic systems, such as their ability to learn precise generalisable conclusions from small amounts of data,” explains Goertzel.</p>



<p>According to the company, this alliance-driven procedure propels AIRIS towards AGI—crafting one of the first intelligent systems with autonomous and adaptive learning that holds practical applications for real-world scenarios.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">AIRIS&#8217; learning mechanisms</h3>



<p>AIRIS is crafted to enhance its understanding by interacting directly with its environment, venturing beyond the traditional AI limitations that depend on predefined rules or vast datasets. Instead, AIRIS evolves through observation, experimentation, and continual refinement of its unique “rule set.”</p>



<p>This system facilitates a profound level of problem-solving and contextual comprehension, with its implementation in Minecraft setting a new benchmark for AI interaction with both digital and tangible landscapes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="qme" dir="ltr">👀 <a href="https://t.co/jTeQFulzFJ">pic.twitter.com/jTeQFulzFJ</a></p>&mdash; Artificial Superintelligence Alliance (@ASI_Alliance) <a href="https://twitter.com/ASI_Alliance/status/1853874156527370650?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Shifting from a controlled 2D grid to the sophisticated 3D world of Minecraft, AIRIS faced numerous challenges—including terrain navigation and adaptive problem-solving in a dynamic environment. This transition underscores AIRIS&#8217; autonomy in navigation, exploration, and learning.</p>



<p>The AIRIS Minecraft Agent distinguishes itself from other AI entities through several key features:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Dynamic navigation:</strong> AIRIS initially evaluates its milieu to formulate movement strategies, adapting to new environments in real-time. Its capabilities include manoeuvring around obstacles, jumping over barriers, and anticipating reactions to varied terrains.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Obstacle adaptation:</strong> It learns to navigate around impediments like cliffs and forested areas, refining its rule set with every new challenge to avoid redundant errors and minimise needless trial-and-error efforts.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Efficient pathfinding:</strong> Via continuous optimisation, AIRIS advances from initially complex navigation paths to streamlined, direct routes as it &#8220;comprehends&#8221; Minecraft dynamics.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Real-time environmental adaptation:</strong> Contrasting with conventional reinforcement learning systems that demand extensive retraining for new environments, AIRIS adapts immediately to unfamiliar regions, crafting new rules based on partial observations dynamically.</li>
</ul>



<p>AIRIS&#8217; adeptness in dealing with fluctuating terrains, including water bodies and cave systems, introduces sophisticated rule refinement founded on hands-on experience. Additionally, AIRIS boasts optimised computational efficiency—enabling real-time management of complex rules without performance compromises.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Future applications</h3>



<p>Minecraft serves as an excellent launchpad for AIRIS&#8217; prospective applications, establishing a solid foundation for expansive implementations:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Enhanced object interaction:</strong> Forthcoming stages will empower AIRIS to engage more profoundly with its surroundings, improving capabilities in object manipulation, construction, and even crafting. This development will necessitate AIRIS to develop a more refined decision-making framework for contextual tasks.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Social AI collaboration:</strong> Plans are underway to incorporate AIRIS in multi-agent scenarios, where agents learn, interact, and fulfil shared objectives, simulating real-world social dynamics and problem-solving collaboratively.</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Abstract and strategic reasoning:</strong> Expanded developments will enhance AIRIS’s reasoning, enabling it to tackle complex goals such as resource management and prioritisation, moving beyond basic navigation towards strategic gameplay.</li>
</ul>



<p>The transition of AIRIS to 3D environments signifies a pivotal advancement in the ASI Alliance’s mission to cultivate AGI. Through AIRIS’s achievements in navigating and learning within Minecraft, the ASI Alliance aspires to expedite its deployment in the real world, pioneering applications for autonomous robots, intelligent home assistants, and other systems requiring adaptive learning and problem-solving capacities.</p>



<p>Berick Cook, AI Developer at SingularityNET and creator of AIRIS, said: “AIRIS is a whole new way of approaching the problem of machine learning. We are only just beginning to explore its capabilities. We are excited to see how we can apply it to problems that have posed a significant challenge for traditional reinforcement learning.</p>



<p>“The most important aspect of AIRIS to me is its transparency and explainability. Moving away from ‘Black Box’ AI represents a significant leap forward in the pursuit of safe, ethical, and beneficial AI.”</p>



<p>The innovative approach to AI evident in AIRIS – emphasising self-directed learning and continuous rule refinement – lays the foundation for AI systems capable of independent functioning in unpredictable real-world environments. Minecraft’s intricate ecosystem enables the system to hone its skills within a controlled yet expansive virtual setting, effectively bridging the divide between simulation and reality.</p>



<p>The AIRIS Minecraft Agent represents the inaugural tangible step towards an AI that learns from, adapts to and makes autonomous decisions about its environment. This accomplishment illustrates the potential of such technology to re-envision AI&#8217;s role across various industries.</p>



<p><em>(Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/skyeweste-2817590/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1578075">SkyeWeste</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/"><strong>SingularityNET bets on supercomputer network to deliver AGI</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft/">ASI Alliance launches AIRIS that ‘learns’ in Minecraft</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/asi-alliance-launches-airis-learns-minecraft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Just three months after its inception, Safe Superintelligence (SSI), a new AI startup founded by OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever, has raised $1 billion in funding. Led by venture capital firms Sequoia and Andreessen Horowitz, the latest investment round values the company at approximately $5 billion, according to a Financial Times report. Sutskever, who left OpenAI in May<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/" title="ReadOpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/">OpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just three months after its inception, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/">Safe Superintelligence</a> (SSI), a new AI startup founded by OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever, has raised $1 billion in funding. Led by venture capital firms Sequoia and Andreessen Horowitz, the latest investment round values the company at approximately $5 billion, according to a <em>Financial Times</em> <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2988c7a3-0e70-4c5d-a3f3-665c2d0c37d3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">report</a>.</p>



<p>Sutskever, who left OpenAI in May this year following a failed attempt to oust CEO Sam Altman, established SSI to develop &#8216;safe&#8217;&nbsp;AI models. The company&#8217;s mission is to create AI systems that are both highly capable and aligned with human interests.</p>



<p>&#8216;We&#8217;ve identified a new mountain to climb that is slightly different from what I was working on previously. We&#8217;re not trying to go down the same path faster. If you do something different, it becomes possible for you to do something special, Sutskever told the&nbsp;<em>Financial Times</em>.</p>



<p>The substantial funding will be used to acquire computing resources necessary for AI model development and to expand SSI&#8217;s current team of 10 employees. The company actively recruits and offers positions in Palo Alto, California, and Tel Aviv, Israel.</p>



<p>With its focus on safety and alignment, SSI&#8217;s approach differs from that of other AI companies. Take firms like <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-delivers-gpt-4o-fine-tuning/">OpenAI</a>, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/authors-file-lawsuit-against-anthropic-over-pirated-works/">Anthropic</a>, and <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/">Elon Musk&#8217;s xAI</a>, which are all developing AI models for various consumer and business applications. SSI, on the other hand, is focusing solely on creating what it calls a &#8216;<a href="https://ssi.inc/">straight shot </a>to safe superintelligence&#8217;.</p>



<p>Daniel Gross, SSI&#8217;s chief executive, emphasised the importance of this focused approach in a statement to <em><a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/openai-co-founder-sutskevers-new-safety-focused-ai-startup-ssi-raises-1-billion-2024-09-04/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reuters</a></em>: &#8220;It&#8217;s important for us to be surrounded by investors who understand, respect and support our mission, which is to make a straight shot to safe superintelligence and in particular to spend a couple of years doing R&amp;D on our product before bringing it to market.&#8221;</p>



<p>It is also interesting to point out that despite not having a product yet, the company&#8217;s significant valuation and funding highlight the intense interest and investment in safe AI research. This is amid growing concerns about the potential risks associated with increasingly powerful AI systems.</p>



<p>Even Sutskever&#8217;s departure from OpenAI was reportedly <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-warns-california-ai-bill-threatens-us-innovation/">due to disagreements</a> over the company&#8217;s direction and the pace of AI development. At OpenAI, he led the &#8216;alignment&#8217;&nbsp;team, which focused on ensuring that advanced AI systems would act in humanity&#8217;s best interests.</p>



<p>What is clear, however, is that the formation of SSI and its rapid funding success reflect a broader trend in the AI industry towards addressing safety concerns alongside capability advancements. This approach aligns with calls from AI researchers and ethicists for more responsible development of artificial intelligence.</p>



<p>Today, SSI joins a competitive field of well-funded AI companies. OpenAI is reportedly in talks to raise funds at a valuation exceeding $100 billion, while Anthropic and xAI were recently valued at around $20 billion.</p>



<p>However, the crowded market did not dim SSI&#8217;s unique focus on safety or its high-profile founding team, both of which have clearly resonated with investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;We are assembling a lean, cracked team of the world&#8217;s best engineers and researchers dedicated to focusing on SSI and nothing else. We offer an opportunity to do your life&#8217;s work and help solve our age&#8217;s most important technical challenge,&#8221; the company&#8217;s website states.</p>



<p>For now, the company&#8217;s progress will be closely watched by both the tech industry and those concerned with the ethical implications of AI development.</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-hit-leadership-exodus-as-three-key-figures-depart/">OpenAI hit by leadership exodus as three key figures depart</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/">OpenAI co-founder&#8217;s Safe Superintelligence Inc secures $1B</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-safe-superintelligence-inc-secures-1b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SingularityNET bets on supercomputer network to deliver AGI</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial general intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben goertzel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opencog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singularitynet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supercomputer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SingularityNET is betting on a network of powerful supercomputers to get us to Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), with the first one set to whir into action this September. While today&#8217;s AI excels in specific areas – think GPT-4 composing poetry or DeepMind&#8217;s AlphaFold predicting protein structures – it&#8217;s still miles away from genuine human-like intelligence.&#160;<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/" title="ReadSingularityNET bets on supercomputer network to deliver AGI">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/">SingularityNET bets on supercomputer network to deliver AGI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://singularitynet.io/">SingularityNET</a> is betting on a network of powerful supercomputers to get us to Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), with the first one set to whir into action this September.</p>



<p>While today&#8217;s AI excels in specific areas – think GPT-4 composing poetry or DeepMind&#8217;s AlphaFold predicting protein structures – it&#8217;s still miles away from genuine human-like intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;While the novel neural-symbolic AI approaches developed by the SingularityNET AI team decrease the need for data, processing and energy somewhat relative to standard deep neural nets, we still need significant supercomputing facilities,&#8221; SingularityNET CEO Ben Goertzel explained to <a href="https://www.livescience.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/new-supercomputing-network-lead-to-agi-1st-node-coming-within-weeks">LiveScience</a> in a recent written statement.</p>



<p>Enter SingularityNET&#8217;s ambitious plan: a &#8220;multi-level cognitive computing network&#8221; designed to host and train the incredibly complex AI architectures required for AGI. Imagine deep neural networks that mimic the human brain, vast language models (LLMs) trained on colossal datasets, and systems that seamlessly weave together human behaviours like speech and movement with multimedia outputs.</p>



<p>But this level of sophistication doesn&#8217;t come cheap. The first supercomputer, slated for completion by early 2025, will be a Frankensteinian beast of cutting-edge hardware: Nvidia GPUs, AMD processors, Tenstorrent server racks – you name it, it&#8217;s in there.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our new <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AGI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AGI</a> Supercomputer will start to come online in September and the first phase will be completed by the end of 2024 or early 2025, depending on supplier delivery timelines — Via <a href="https://twitter.com/LiveScience?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@LiveScience</a> <a href="https://t.co/SegFiMR9II">https://t.co/SegFiMR9II</a></p>&mdash; SingularityNET (@SingularityNET) <a href="https://twitter.com/SingularityNET/status/1822264864057741759?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>This, Goertzel believes, is more than just a technological leap, it&#8217;s a philosophical one: &#8220;Before our eyes, a paradigmatic shift is taking place towards continuous learning, seamless generalisation, and reflexive AI self-modification.”</p>



<p>To manage this distributed network and its precious data, SingularityNET has developed <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/full-stack-ai-solution-singularitynet-ethereum-cardano/">OpenCog Hyperon</a>, an open-source software framework specifically designed for AI systems. Think of it as the conductor trying to make sense of a symphony played across multiple concert halls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But SingularityNET isn&#8217;t keeping all this brainpower to itself. Reminiscent of arcade tokens, users will purchase access to the supercomputer network with the <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/singularitynet/">AGIX</a> token on blockchains like Ethereum and Cardano and contribute data to the collective pool—fuelling further AGI development.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>With experts like DeepMind&#8217;s Shane Legg predicting human-level AI by 2028, the race is on. Only time will tell if this global network of silicon brains will birth the next great leap in artificial intelligence.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@anshitan?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Anshita Nair</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-merging-of-ai-and-blockchain-was-inevitable-but-what-will-it-mean/"><strong>The merging of AI and blockchain was inevitable – but what will it mean?</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/">SingularityNET bets on supercomputer network to deliver AGI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/singularitynet-bets-supercomputer-network-deliver-agi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk revives OpenAI legal battle with fresh allegations</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 15:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elon musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greg brockman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk&#8217;s revived lawsuit against OpenAI includes fresh allegations against the company and two of its founders, Sam Altman and Greg Brockman. This new legal salvo comes after Musk withdrew a previous lawsuit in June. The earlier suit had primarily focused on claims that OpenAI had breached its founding agreement to keep the company&#8217;s technology<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/" title="ReadElon Musk revives OpenAI legal battle with fresh allegations">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/">Elon Musk revives OpenAI legal battle with fresh allegations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Elon Musk&#8217;s revived lawsuit against <a href="https://openai.com/">OpenAI</a> includes fresh allegations against the company and two of its founders, Sam Altman and Greg Brockman. This new legal salvo comes after Musk <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/musk-ends-openai-lawsuit-slamming-apple-chatgpt-plans/">withdrew a previous lawsuit</a> in June.</p>



<p>The earlier suit had primarily focused on claims that OpenAI had breached its founding agreement to keep the company&#8217;s technology open source. The fresh complaint, however, takes a more aggressive stance.</p>



<p>Musk&#8217;s legal team alleges that Altman and Brockman &#8220;assiduously manipulated Musk into co-founding their spurious non-profit venture&#8221; by making promises about OpenAI&#8217;s safety and transparency that set it apart from profit-driven alternatives. The lawsuit goes so far as to claim that assurances about OpenAI&#8217;s nonprofit structure were &#8220;the hook for Altman&#8217;s long con.&#8221;</p>



<p>Marc Toberoff, Musk&#8217;s lawyer, told <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/05/technology/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit.html">The New York Times</a>, &#8220;This is a much more forceful lawsuit.&#8221; Indeed, the new suit ups the ante by accusing OpenAI of breaching federal racketeering laws in what it describes as a conspiracy to defraud Musk.</p>



<p>The complaint paints a picture of extensive deception, alleging that Altman and OpenAI lured Musk into co-founding the organisation under false pretences of AI safety and openness. Musk claims he invested significant resources and recruited top scientists based on these assurances, only to see the company pivot towards a profit-making model that compromised its original mission.</p>



<p>The lawsuit details allegations of self-dealing and conflicts of interest by Altman, which Musk argues led to their falling out and ultimately compromised OpenAI&#8217;s founding principles. Reports of withheld technology and a compromised Board of Directors have raised serious ethical concerns about the company&#8217;s operations and future direction.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the lawsuit takes aim at OpenAI&#8217;s partnership with Microsoft. It claims that the contract between the two tech giants includes a clause that would revoke Microsoft&#8217;s rights to OpenAI&#8217;s technology once artificial general intelligence (AGI) is achieved. This allegation, if proven true, could have far-reaching implications for the future of AI development and corporate partnerships in the tech industry.</p>



<p>The legal action seeks not only damages and restitution but also punitive measures against the defendants for allegedly exploiting Musk&#8217;s contributions. The tech billionaire is pushing for Altman to be divested of what the lawsuit describes as &#8220;ill-gotten gains&#8221; resulting from the alleged deception.</p>



<p>Musk&#8217;s complaint goes beyond mere contractual disputes, invoking serious legal charges including fraud, breach of contract, wire fraud, and violations of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racketeer_Influenced_and_Corrupt_Organizations_Act">RICO</a> (Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations) law against Altman, Brockman, and OpenAI.</p>



<p>The revival of Musk&#8217;s legal battle against OpenAI comes at a time of increasing scrutiny of AI technologies and their potential impact on society. As one of the original co-founders of OpenAI, Musk&#8217;s allegations carry significant weight and could potentially reshape the narrative around the company&#8217;s evolution from a non-profit to a for-profit entity.</p>



<p>However, it&#8217;s worth noting that OpenAI has consistently maintained that its transition to a &#8220;capped-profit&#8221; model was necessary to secure the funding required for its ambitious AI research and development goals. The company has also emphasised its commitment to developing AI in a responsible and beneficial manner.</p>



<p>The tech community and legal experts will be watching closely as this case progresses, given its potential to set precedents for how AI companies <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/">are held accountable</a> to their stated missions and founding principles.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jupp?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Jonathan Kemper</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/metas-ai-strategy-building-for-tomorrow-not-immediate-profits/"><strong>Meta’s AI strategy: Building for tomorrow, not immediate profits</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/">Elon Musk revives OpenAI legal battle with fresh allegations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-revives-openai-legal-battle-fresh-allegations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The exponential expenses of AI development</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 12:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta (Facebook)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tech giants like Microsoft, Alphabet, and Meta are riding high on a wave of revenue from AI-driven cloud services, yet simultaneously drowning in the substantial costs of pushing AI&#8217;s boundaries. Recent financial reports paint a picture of a double-edged sword: on one side, impressive gains; on the other, staggering expenses.  This dichotomy has led&#160;Bloomberg&#160;to aptly<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development/" title="ReadThe exponential expenses of AI development">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development/">The exponential expenses of AI development</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tech giants like Microsoft, Alphabet, and Meta are riding high on a wave of revenue from AI-driven cloud services, yet simultaneously drowning in the substantial costs of pushing AI&#8217;s boundaries. Recent financial reports paint a picture of a double-edged sword: on one side, impressive gains; on the other, staggering expenses. </p>



<p>This dichotomy has led&nbsp;<em><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-30/why-artificial-intelligence-is-so-expensive?srnd=technology-vp&amp;sref=QqWIvTvt" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bloomberg</a></em>&nbsp;to aptly dub AI development a &#8220;huge money pit,&#8221; highlighting the complex economic reality behind today&#8217;s AI revolution. At the heart of this financial problem lies a relentless push for bigger, more sophisticated AI models. The quest for artificial general intelligence (AGI) has led companies to develop increasingly complex systems, exemplified by large language models like GPT-4. These models require vast computational power, driving up hardware costs to unprecedented levels.</p>



<p>To top it off, the demand for specialised AI chips, mainly graphics processing units (GPUs), has skyrocketed. Nvidia, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/">the leading manufacturer in this space</a>, has seen its market value soar as tech companies scramble to secure these essential components. Its H100 graphics chip, the gold standard for training AI models, has sold for an estimated $30,000 — with some resellers offering them for multiple times that amount. </p>



<p>The global chip shortage has only exacerbated this issue, with some firms waiting months to acquire the necessary hardware. Meta Chief Executive Officer Zuckerberg&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C2QARHJR1sZ/?hl=en" rel="noreferrer noopener">previously said</a>&nbsp;that his company planned to acquire 350,000 H100 chips by the end of this year to support its AI research efforts. Even if he gets a bulk-buying discount, that quickly adds to billions of dollars.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-presents-latest-advancements-visual-ai/">push for more advanced</a> AI has also sparked an arms race in chip design. Companies like Google and Amazon invest heavily in developing their AI-specific processors, aiming to gain a competitive edge and reduce reliance on third-party suppliers. This trend towards custom silicon adds another layer of complexity and cost to the AI development process.</p>



<p>But the hardware challenge extends beyond just procuring chips. The scale of modern AI models necessitates massive data centres, which come with their technological hurdles. These facilities must be designed to handle extreme computational loads while managing heat dissipation and energy consumption efficiently. As models grow larger, so do the power requirements, significantly increasing operational costs and environmental impact.</p>



<p>In a&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/12/podcasts/transcript-ezra-klein-interviews-dario-amodei.html" rel="noreferrer noopener">podcast interview</a>&nbsp;in early April, Dario Amodei, the chief executive officer of OpenAI-rival Anthropic, said the current crop of AI models on the market cost around $100 million to train. &#8220;The models that are in training now and that will come out at various times later this year or early next year are closer in cost to $1 billion,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And then I think in 2025 and 2026, we&#8217;ll get more towards $5 or $10 billion.&#8221;</p>



<p>Then, there is data, the lifeblood of AI systems, presenting its own technological challenges. The need for vast, high-quality datasets has led companies to invest heavily in data collection, cleaning, and annotation technologies. Some firms are developing sophisticated synthetic data generation tools to supplement real-world data, further driving up research and development costs.</p>



<p>The rapid pace of AI innovation also means that infrastructure and tools quickly become obsolete. Companies must continuously upgrade their systems and retrain their models to stay competitive, creating a constant cycle of investment and obsolescence.</p>



<p>&#8220;On April 25, Microsoft said it spent $14 billion on capital expenditures in the most recent quarter and expects those costs to &#8220;increase materially,&#8221; driven partly by AI infrastructure investments. That was a 79% increase from the year-earlier quarter. Alphabet said it spent $12 billion during the quarter, a 91% increase from a year earlier, and expects the rest of the year to be &#8220;at or above&#8221; that level as it focuses on AI opportunities,&#8221; the article by Bloomberg reads.</p>



<p>Bloomberg also noted that Meta, meanwhile, raised its estimates for investments for the year and now believes capital expenditures will be $35 billion to $40 billion, which would be a 42% increase at the high end of the range. &#8220;It cited aggressive investment in AI research and product development,&#8221;&nbsp;<em>Bloomberg</em>&nbsp;wrote.</p>



<p>Interestingly, Bloomberg&#8217;s article also points out that despite these enormous costs, tech giants are proving that AI can be a real revenue driver. Microsoft and Alphabet reported significant growth in their cloud businesses, mainly attributed to increased demand for AI services. This suggests that while the initial investment in AI technology is staggering, the potential returns are compelling enough to justify the expense.</p>



<p>However, the high costs of AI development raise concerns about market concentration. As noted in the article, the expenses associated with cutting-edge AI research may limit innovation to a handful of well-funded companies, potentially stifling competition and diversity in the field. Looking ahead, the industry is focusing on developing more efficient AI technologies to address these cost challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Research into techniques like few-shot learning, transfer learning, and more energy-efficient model architectures aims to reduce the computational resources required for AI development and deployment. Moreover, the push towards edge AI &#8211; running AI models on local devices rather than in the cloud &#8211; could help distribute computational loads and reduce the strain on centralised data centres. </p>



<p>This shift, however, requires its own set of technological innovations in chip design and software optimisation. Overall, it is clear that the future of AI will be shaped not just by breakthroughs in algorithms and model design but also by our ability to overcome the immense technological and financial hurdles that come with scaling AI systems. Companies that can navigate these challenges effectively will likely emerge as the leaders in the next phase of the AI revolution.</p>



<p><em>(Image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@omilaev">Igor Omilaev</a><em style="font-size: revert;">)</em></em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development/">The exponential expenses of AI development</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-exponential-expenses-of-ai-development/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenResearch reveals potential impacts of universal basic income</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job displacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openresearch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universal basic income]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A study conducted by OpenResearch has shed light on the transformative potential of universal basic income (UBI). The research aimed to &#8220;learn from participants&#8217; experiences and better understand both the potential and the limitations of unconditional cash transfers.&#8221; The study – which provided participants with an extra $1,000 per month – revealed significant impacts across<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income/" title="ReadOpenResearch reveals potential impacts of universal basic income">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income/">OpenResearch reveals potential impacts of universal basic income</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A study conducted by <a href="https://www.openresearchlab.org/studies/unconditional-cash-study/study">OpenResearch</a> has shed light on the transformative potential of universal basic income (UBI). The research aimed to &#8220;learn from participants&#8217; experiences and better understand both the potential and the limitations of unconditional cash transfers.&#8221;</p>



<p>The study – which provided participants with an extra $1,000 per month – revealed significant impacts across various aspects of recipients&#8217; lives, including health, spending habits, employment, personal agency, and housing mobility.</p>



<p>In healthcare, the analysis showed increased utilisation of medical services, particularly in dental and specialist care.</p>



<p>One participant noted, &#8220;I got myself braces&#8230;I feel like people underestimate the importance of having nice teeth because it affects more than just your own sense of self, it affects how people look at you.&#8221;</p>



<p>While no immediate measurable effects on physical health were observed, researchers suggest that increased medical care utilisation could lead to long-term health benefits.</p>



<p>The study also uncovered interesting spending patterns among UBI recipients.</p>



<p>On average, participants increased their overall monthly spending by $310, with significant allocations towards basic needs such as food, transportation, and rent. Notably, there was a 26% increase in financial support provided to others, highlighting the ripple effect of UBI on communities.</p>



<p>In terms of employment, the study revealed nuanced outcomes.</p>



<p>While there was a slight decrease in overall employment rates and work hours among recipients, the study found that UBI provided individuals with greater flexibility in making employment decisions aligned with their circumstances and goals.</p>



<p>One participant explained, &#8220;Because of that money and being able to build up my savings, I&#8217;m in a position for once to be picky…I don&#8217;t have to take a crappy job just because I need income right now.&#8221;</p>



<p>The research also uncovered significant improvements in personal agency and future planning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>UBI recipients were 14% more likely to pursue education or job training and 5% more likely to have a budget compared to the control group. Black recipients in the third year of the program were 26% more likely to report starting or helping to start a business.</p>



<p>Lastly, the study&#8217;s analysis revealed increased housing mobility among UBI recipients. Participants were 11% more likely to move neighbourhoods and 23% more likely to actively search for new housing compared to the control group.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">the openresearch team releases the first result from their UBI study:<a href="https://t.co/8YXBwVeQeW">https://t.co/8YXBwVeQeW</a><br><br>great, diligent work over the past few years. proud of the team!</p>&mdash; Sam Altman (@sama) <a href="https://twitter.com/sama/status/1815432708568608946?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 22, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>The study provides valuable insights into the potential impacts of UBI, offering policymakers and researchers a data-driven foundation for future decisions on social welfare programs. This major societal conversation may be necessary if worst case scenarios around AI-induced job displacement come to fruition.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@visuals_by_fred?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Freddie Collins</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/one-banknote-uXWPg9uMwt8?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-could-unleash-119-billion-in-uk-productivity/"><strong>AI could unleash £119 billion in UK productivity</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income/">OpenResearch reveals potential impacts of universal basic income</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openresearch-reveals-potential-impacts-universal-basic-income/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SoftBank chief: Forget AGI, ASI will be here within 10 years</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 17:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Assistants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masayoshi son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[super intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SoftBank founder and CEO Masayoshi Son has claimed that artificial super intelligence (ASI) could be a reality within the next decade. Speaking at SoftBank&#8217;s annual meeting in Tokyo on June 21, Son painted a picture of a future where AI far surpasses human intelligence, potentially revolutionising life as we know it. Son asserted that by<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years/" title="ReadSoftBank chief: Forget AGI, ASI will be here within 10 years">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years/">SoftBank chief: Forget AGI, ASI will be here within 10 years</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://group.softbank/en">SoftBank</a> founder and CEO Masayoshi Son has claimed that artificial super intelligence (ASI) could be a reality within the next decade.</p>



<p>Speaking at SoftBank&#8217;s annual meeting in Tokyo on June 21, Son painted a picture of a future where AI far surpasses human intelligence, potentially revolutionising life as we know it. Son asserted that by 2030, AI could be &#8220;one to 10 times smarter than humans,&#8221; and by 2035, it might reach a staggering &#8220;10,000 times smarter&#8221; than human intelligence.</p>



<p>SoftBank’s CEO made a clear distinction between artificial general intelligence (AGI) and ASI. According to Son, AGI would be equivalent to a human &#8220;genius,&#8221; potentially up to 10 times more capable than an average person. ASI, however, would be in a league of its own, with capabilities 10,000 times beyond human potential.</p>



<p>Son&#8217;s predictions align with the goals of <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/20/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/">Safe Superintelligence Inc. (SSI)</a>, founded by Ilya Sutskever, former chief scientist at OpenAI, along with Daniel Levy and Daniel Gross. SSI&#8217;s mission, as stated on their website, is to &#8220;approach safety and capabilities in tandem, as technical problems to be solved through revolutionary engineering and scientific breakthroughs.&#8221;</p>



<p>The timing of these announcements underscores the growing focus on superintelligent AI within the tech industry. While SoftBank appears to be prioritising the development of ASI, SSI is emphasising the importance of safety in this pursuit. As stated by SSI&#8217;s founders, &#8220;We plan to advance capabilities as fast as possible while making sure our safety always remains ahead.&#8221;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that the scientific community has yet to reach a consensus on the feasibility or capabilities of AGI or ASI. Current AI systems, while impressive in specific domains, are still far from achieving human-level reasoning across all areas.</p>



<p>Son&#8217;s speech took an unexpectedly personal turn when he linked the development of ASI to his own sense of purpose and mortality. &#8220;SoftBank was founded for what purpose? For what purpose was Masayoshi Son born? It may sound strange, but I think I was born to realise ASI. I am super serious about it,&#8221; he declared.</p>



<p>Son&#8217;s predictions and SoftBank&#8217;s apparent pivot towards ASI development, coupled with the formation of SSI, raise important questions about the future of AI and its potential impact on society. While the promise of superintelligent AI is enticing, it also brings concerns about job displacement, ethical considerations, and the potential risks associated with creating an intelligence that far surpasses our own.</p>



<p>Whether Son&#8217;s vision of ASI within a decade proves prescient or overly optimistic remains to be seen, but one thing is certain: the race towards superintelligent AI is heating up, with major players positioning themselves at the forefront.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/21/anthropics-claude-3-5-sonnet-beats-gpt-4o-most-benchmarks/"><strong>Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet beats GPT-4o in most benchmarks</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years/">SoftBank chief: Forget AGI, ASI will be here within 10 years</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/softbank-chief-forget-agi-asi-here-within-10-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever&#8217;s new startup aims for &#8216;safe superintelligence&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ilya Sutskever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssi inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superintelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ilya Sutskever, former chief scientist at OpenAI, has revealed his next major project after departing the AI research company he co-founded in May. Alongside fellow OpenAI alumnus Daniel Levy and Apple&#8217;s former AI lead Daniel Gross, the trio has formed Safe Superintelligence Inc. (SSI), a startup solely focused on building safe superintelligent systems. The formation<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/" title="ReadOpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever&#8217;s new startup aims for &#8216;safe superintelligence&#8217;">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/">OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever&#8217;s new startup aims for &#8216;safe superintelligence&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ilya Sutskever, former chief scientist at OpenAI, has revealed his next major project after departing the AI research company he co-founded in May.</p>



<p>Alongside fellow OpenAI alumnus Daniel Levy and Apple&#8217;s former AI lead Daniel Gross, the trio has formed <a href="https://ssi.inc/">Safe Superintelligence Inc.</a> (SSI), a startup solely focused on building safe superintelligent systems.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I am starting a new company: <a href="https://t.co/BG3K3SI3A1">https://t.co/BG3K3SI3A1</a></p>&mdash; Ilya Sutskever (@ilyasut) <a href="https://twitter.com/ilyasut/status/1803472978753303014?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 19, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>The formation of SSI follows the brief November 2023 <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2023/11/20/microsoft-recruits-former-openai-ceo-sam-altman-co-founder-greg-brockman/">ousting</a> of OpenAI&#8217;s CEO Sam Altman, in which Sutskever played a central role before later expressing regret over the situation.</p>



<p>In a message on SSI&#8217;s website, the founders state::</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“We approach safety and capabilities in tandem, as technical problems to be solved through revolutionary engineering and scientific breakthroughs. We plan to advance capabilities as fast as possible while making sure our safety always remains ahead. This way, we can scale in peace.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><em>Our singular focus means no distraction by management overhead or product cycles, and our business model means safety, security, and progress are all insulated from short-term commercial pressures.”</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Sutskever&#8217;s work at SSI represents a continuation of his efforts at OpenAI, where he was part of the superalignment team tasked with designing control methods for powerful new AI systems. However, that group was disbanded following Sutskever&#8217;s high-profile departure.</p>



<p>According to SSI, it will pursue safe superintelligence in &#8220;a straight shot, with one focus, one goal, and one product.&#8221; This singular focus stands in contrast to the diversification seen at major AI labs like OpenAI, DeepMind, and Anthropic over recent years.</p>



<p>Only time will tell if Sutskever&#8217;s team can make substantive progress toward their lofty goal of safe superintelligent AI. Critics argue the challenge represents a matter of philosophy as much as engineering. However, the pedigree of SSI&#8217;s founders means their efforts will be followed with great interest.</p>



<p>In the meantime, expect to see a resurgence of the “What did Ilya see?” meme:</p>



<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">What did Ilya see? <a href="https://t.co/2Vhn2OXBMt">pic.twitter.com/2Vhn2OXBMt</a></p>&mdash; Matthew Zeits (@MatthewZ73671) <a href="https://twitter.com/MatthewZ73671/status/1801376604926709854?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 13, 2024</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/19/meta-unveils-ai-models-multi-modal-processing-music-generation-more/"><strong>Meta unveils five AI models for multi-modal processing, music generation, and more</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/">OpenAI co-founder Ilya Sutskever&#8217;s new startup aims for &#8216;safe superintelligence&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-co-founder-ilya-sutskevers-startup-aims-safe-superintelligence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk sues OpenAI over alleged breach of nonprofit agreement</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 13:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial general intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elon musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=14473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk has filed a lawsuit against OpenAI and its CEO, Sam Altman, citing a violation of their nonprofit agreement. The legal battle, unfolding in the Superior Court of California for the County of San Francisco, revolves around OpenAI&#8217;s departure from its foundational mission of advancing open-source artificial general intelligence (AGI) for the betterment of<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement/" title="ReadElon Musk sues OpenAI over alleged breach of nonprofit agreement">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement/">Elon Musk sues OpenAI over alleged breach of nonprofit agreement</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Elon Musk has filed a lawsuit against <a href="https://openai.com/">OpenAI</a> and its CEO, Sam Altman, citing a violation of their nonprofit agreement.</p>



<p>The legal battle, unfolding in the Superior Court of California for the County of San Francisco, revolves around OpenAI&#8217;s departure from its foundational mission of advancing open-source artificial general intelligence (AGI) for the betterment of humanity.</p>



<p>Musk was a co-founder and early backer of OpenAI. According to Musk, Altman and Greg Brockman (another co-founder and current president of OpenAI) convinced him to bankroll the startup in 2015 on promises that it would remain a nonprofit.</p>



<p>In his legal challenge, Musk accuses OpenAI of straying from its principles through a collaboration with Microsoft—alleging that the partnership prioritises proprietary technology over the original ethos of open-source advancement.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="676" height="826" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-14474" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit.jpg 676w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit-246x300.jpg 246w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit-164x200.jpg 164w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit-233x285.jpg 233w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit-205x250.jpg 205w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit-82x100.jpg 82w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/elon-musk-openai-lawsuit-49x60.jpg 49w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px" /></figure>



<p>Musk&#8217;s grievances include claims of contract breach, violation of fiduciary duty, and unfair business practices. He calls upon OpenAI to realign with its nonprofit objectives and seeks an injunction to halt the commercial exploitation of AGI technology.</p>



<p>At the heart of the dispute is OpenAI&#8217;s recent launch of GPT-4 in March 2023. Musk contends that unlike its predecessors, GPT-4 represents a shift towards closed-source models—a move he believes favours Microsoft&#8217;s financial interests at the expense of OpenAI&#8217;s altruistic mission.</p>



<p>Founded in 2015 as a nonprofit AI research lab, OpenAI transitioned into a commercial entity in 2020. OpenAI has now adopted a profit-driven approach, with revenues reportedly surpassing $2 billion annually.</p>



<p>Musk, who has long voiced concerns about the risks posed by AI, has called for robust government regulation and responsible AI development. He questions the technical expertise of OpenAI&#8217;s current board and highlights the removal and subsequent reinstatement of Altman in November 2023 as evidence of a profit-oriented agenda aligned with Microsoft&#8217;s interests.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/02/27/mistral-ai-unveils-llm-rivalling-major-players/"><strong>Mistral AI unveils LLM rivalling major players</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement/">Elon Musk sues OpenAI over alleged breach of nonprofit agreement</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/elon-musk-sues-openai-alleged-breach-nonprofit-agreement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
