<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cloud - AI News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/cloud/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/cloud/</link>
	<description>Artificial Intelligence News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:54:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/ai-icon-60x60.png</url>
	<title>cloud - AI News</title>
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/cloud/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AGI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The emerging US-China Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) rivalry could face a major policy transformation, as the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) recommends a Manhattan Project-style initiative and restrictions on humanoid robots in its latest report to Congress. Released in November 2024, the Commission&#8217;s annual report outlined 32 recommendations that could fundamentally alter how the two countries<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/" title="ReadManhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/">Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The emerging US-China Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) rivalry could face a major policy transformation, as the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Comprehensive_List_of_Recommendations.pdf">recommends</a> a Manhattan Project-style initiative and restrictions on humanoid robots in its latest report to Congress.</p>



<p>Released in November 2024, the Commission&#8217;s <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Annual_Report_to_Congress.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annual report</a> outlined <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2024-11/2024_Executive_Summary.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">32 recommendations</a> that could fundamentally alter how the two countries interact, with artificial intelligence taking centre stage in a new chapter of strategic rivalry.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">US-China: the AGI moonshot and critical tech controls</h3>



<p>At the heart of the report lies an ambitious proposal: establishing a government-backed programme to develop AGI &#8211; AI systems that could match and potentially exceed human cognitive abilities. </p>



<p>However, the recommendation is just one piece of a larger technological puzzle, including export controls, investment screening, and new trade policies to preserve US technological advantages. </p>



<p>The proposed AGI initiative would provide multi-year contracts to leading AI companies, cloud providers, and data centre operators. It would be backed by the Defense Department&#8217;s highest priority, &#8220;DX Rating&#8221; &#8211; a designation typically reserved for critical national security projects. </p>



<p>This level of government involvement in AI development mirrors the urgency seen in previous technological races. It raises crucial questions about the role of state intervention in an industry primarily driven by private sector innovation.</p>



<p>The Commission&#8217;s tech-focused recommendations extend beyond AI. Notable proposals include restricting imports of Chinese-made autonomous humanoid robots with advanced dexterity, locomotion, and intelligence capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report also targets energy infrastructure products with remote monitoring capabilities, reflecting growing concerns about connected technologies in critical infrastructure. The report builds on existing export controls in the semiconductor space by recommending stronger oversight of technology transfers and investment flows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This comes as China continues to build domestic chip-making capabilities despite international restrictions. The Commission suggests creating an Outbound Investment Office that prevents US capital and expertise from advancing China&#8217;s technological capabilities in sensitive sectors.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Reshaping trade relations and investment flows</h3>



<p>Perhaps most significantly, the report recommends eliminating China&#8217;s Permanent Normal Trade Relations (PNTR) status—a move that could reshape the technology supply chain and trade flows that have defined the global tech industry for decades. This recommendation acknowledges how deeply intertwined the US and Chinese tech ecosystems have become, while suggesting that this interdependence may now pose more risks than benefits.</p>



<p>Data transparency is another key theme, with recommendations for expanded reporting requirements on investments and technology transfers. The Commission calls for better tracking of investments flowing through offshore entities, addressing a significant blind-spot in current oversight mechanisms.</p>



<p>The report&#8217;s release comes at a critical juncture in technological development. China&#8217;s push for self-sufficiency in vital technologies and its &#8220;new quality productive forces&#8221; initiative demonstrates Beijing&#8217;s determination to lead in next-generation technologies. Meanwhile, AI capabilities and quantum computing breakthroughs have raised the stakes in technology competition.</p>



<p>However, the Commission&#8217;s recommendations face practical challenges. Achieving AGI remains a complex scientific challenge that may not yield quick results, regardless of funding levels. Additionally, restrictions on technology transfers and investment could have unintended consequences for global innovation networks that have historically benefited both nations.</p>



<p>If these recommendations are implemented, the tech industry may need to navigate an increasingly complex regulatory landscape. Companies would face new compliance requirements for international investments, technology transfers, and collaborative research projects.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Challenges and future implications</h3>



<p>The effectiveness of the proposed measures will likely depend on coordination with allies and partners who share similar technological capabilities and concerns. The report acknowledges this by recommending multilateral approaches to export controls and investment screening.</p>



<p>US-China technological competition has entered a new phase where government policy may play a more direct role in shaping development. Whether this approach accelerates or hinders innovation remains to be seen, but the tech industry should prepare for increased scrutiny and regulation of international technological collaboration.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nathangbingle?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nathan Bingle</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:844px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/">Manhattan Project 2.0? US eyes AGI breakthrough in escalating China rivalry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/manhattan-project-2-0-us-eyes-agi-breakthrough-in-escalating-china-rivalry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon has announced an additional $4 billion investment in Anthropic, bringing the company&#8217;s total commitment to $8 billion, part of its expanding artificial intelligence strategy. The investment was announced on November 22, 2024 and strengthens Amazon&#8217;s position in the AI sector, building on its established cloud computing services in the form of AWS.  While maintaining<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/" title="ReadAmazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/">Amazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amazon has announced <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-partners-anthropic-enhance-alexa/">an additional</a> $4 billion investment in Anthropic, bringing the company&#8217;s total commitment to $8 billion, part of its expanding artificial intelligence strategy. The investment was <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/aws/amazon-invests-additional-4-billion-anthropic-ai">announced</a> on November 22, 2024 and strengthens Amazon&#8217;s position in the AI sector, building on its established cloud computing services in the form of AWS. </p>



<p>While maintaining Amazon&#8217;s minority stake in Anthropic, the investment represents a significant development in the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-urges-ai-regulation-avoid-catastrophes/">approach to AI technology</a> and cloud infrastructure. The expanded collaboration goes beyond mere financial investment. Anthropic has now designated AWS as its &#8220;primary training partner&#8221; for AI model development, in addition to Amazon&#8217;s role as a primary cloud provider. </p>



<p>Amazon&#8217;s investment will see Anthropic utilizing AWS Trainium and Inferentia chips for training and on which to deploy its future foundational models, including any updates to the flagship Claude AI system.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">AWS&#8217;s competitive edge</h3>



<p>The continuing partnership provides Amazon with several strategic advantages in the competitive cloud computing and AI services market:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Hardware innovation</strong>: The commitment to use AWS Trainium and Inferentia chips for Anthropic&#8217;s advanced AI models validates Amazon&#8217;s investment in custom AI chips and positions AWS as a serious competitor to NVIDIA in the AI infrastructure space.</li>



<li><strong>Cloud service enhancement</strong>: AWS customers will receive early access to fine-tuning capabilities for data processed by Anthropic models. This benefit alone could attract more enterprises to Amazon&#8217;s cloud platform.</li>



<li><strong>Model performance</strong>: Claude 3.5 Sonnet, Anthropic&#8217;s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-new-claude-ai-models-and-computer-control/">latest model</a> available through Amazon Bedrock, has demonstrated exceptional performance in agentic coding tasks, according to Anthropic.</li>
</ol>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Amazon&#8217;s multi-faceted AI strategy</h3>



<p>While the increased investment in Anthropic is impressive in monetary terms, it represents just one component of Amazon&#8217;s broader AI strategy. The company appears to be pursuing a multi-pronged approach:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>External partnerships: </strong>The Anthropic investment provides immediate access to cutting-edge AI capabilities from third-parties.</li>



<li><strong>Internal development:</strong>&nbsp;Amazon continues to develop its own AI models and capabilities.</li>



<li><strong>Infrastructure development:</strong> Ongoing investment in AI-specific hardware like Trainium chips demonstrates a commitment to building AI-focussed infrastructure.</li>
</ol>



<p>The expanded partnership signals Amazon&#8217;s long-term commitment to AI development yet retains flexibility thanks to its minority stakeholding. This approach allows Amazon to benefit from Anthropic&#8217;s innovations while preserving the ability to pursue other partnerships with external AI companies and continue internal development initiatives.</p>



<p>The investment reinforces the growing trend where major tech companies seek strategic AI partnerships rather than relying solely on internal development. It also highlights the important role of cloud infrastructure in the AI industry&#8217;s growth. AWS has positioned itself as a suitable platform for AI model training and deployment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/">Amazon stakes $4bn more in Anthropic–the next tech arms race?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-stakes-4bn-more-in-anthropic-the-next-tech-arms-race/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NJ cops demand protections against data brokers</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Privacy laws in the United States are a patchwork at best. More often than not, they miss the mark, leaving most people with little actual privacy. When such laws are enacted, they can seem tailored to protect those in positions of power. Even laws designed to protect crime victims might end up protecting the names<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers/" title="ReadNJ cops demand protections against data brokers">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers/">NJ cops demand protections against data brokers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Privacy laws in the United States are a patchwork at best. More often than not, they miss the mark, leaving most people with little actual privacy. When <a target="_blank" href="https://www.techdirt.com/2024/11/26/nj-cops-are-suing-to-protect-their-exclusive-right-to-keep-their-data-out-of-data-brokers-databases/" rel="noreferrer noopener">such laws are enacted</a>, they can seem tailored to protect those in positions of power.</p>



<p>Even laws designed to protect crime victims might end up protecting the names of abusive officers by labelling them as victims of crime in cases like resisting arrest or <a target="_blank" href="https://www.techdirt.com/2019/12/24/alabama-lawmakers-think-time-is-right-to-make-assaulting-cop-hate-crime/" rel="noreferrer noopener">assaulting an officer</a>. Such accusations are often used in cases of excessive force, keeping cops’ names out of the spotlight.</p>



<p>For example, a recent New Jersey law emerged from a tragic event in which a government employee faced violence, sparking a legislative response. Known as “Daniel’s Law,” it was created after the personal information of a federal judge’s family was used by a murderer to track them down. Instead of a broader privacy law that could protect all residents of New Jersey, it focused exclusively on safeguarding certain public employees.</p>



<p>Under the law, judges, prosecutors, and police officers can request that their personal information (addresses and phone numbers, for example) be scrubbed from public databases. Popular services that people use to look up information, such as Whitepages or Spokeo, must comply. While this sounds like a win for privacy, the protections stop there. The average citizen is still left exposed, with no legal recourse if their personal data is misused or sold.</p>



<p>At the centre of the debate is a lawyer who’s taken up the cause of protecting cops’ personal data. He’s suing numerous companies for making this type of information accessible. While noble at first glance, a deeper look raises questions.</p>



<p>It transpires that the lawyer&#8217;s company has previously collected and monetised personal <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/" rel="noreferrer noopener">data</a>. And when a data service responded to his demands by freezing access to some of the firm&#8217;s databases, he and his clients cried foul — despite specifically requesting restrictions on how their information could be used.</p>



<p>It’s also worth noting how unevenly data protection measures are to be applied. Cops, for instance, frequently rely on the same tools and databases they’re now asking to be restricted. These services have long been used by law enforcement for investigations and running background checks. Yet, when law enforcement data appears in such systems, special treatment is required.</p>



<p>A recent anecdote involved a police union leader who was shown a simple property record pulled from an online database. The record displayed basic details like his home address and his property&#8217;s square footage — information anyone could find with a few clicks. His reaction was one of shock and anger – an obvious disconnect.</p>



<p>For everyday citizens, this level of data exposure is a given. But for law enforcement, it requires a level of granular exclusion that&#8217;s not practical.</p>



<p>Perhaps everyone, including law enforcement personnel deserves better safeguards against data harvesting and misuse? But what Daniel&#8217;s law and later events involving police officers point to is the need for the type of improvements to the way data is treated for all, not just one group of society.</p>



<p>Instead of expanding privacy rights to all New Jersey residents, the law carves out exceptions for the powerful — leaving the rest of the population as vulnerable as ever.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by<a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-police-car-parked-in-the-grass-near-palm-trees-E1lR_C-IGdo?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash"> Unsplash</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-legislation-sparks-controversy-over-data-transparency/">EU AI legislation sparks controversy over data transparency</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:1139px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a target="_blank" href="https://www.ai-expo.net/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a target="_blank" href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlockX</a>,<a target="_blank" href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a target="_blank" href="https://techforge.pub/events/" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>

<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers/">NJ cops demand protections against data brokers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nj-cops-demand-protections-against-data-brokers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence platform provider Clarifai has unveiled a new compute orchestration capability that promises to help enterprises optimise their AI workloads in any computing environment, reduce costs and avoid vendor lock-in. Announced on December 3, 2024, the public preview release lets organisations orchestrate AI workloads through a unified control plane, whether those workloads are running<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/" title="ReadNew Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/">New Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence platform provider Clarifai has unveiled a new compute orchestration capability that promises to help enterprises optimise their AI workloads in any computing environment, reduce costs and avoid vendor lock-in.</p>



<p>Announced on December 3, 2024, the <a href="https://docs.clarifai.com/sdk/compute-orchestration/">public preview release</a> lets organisations orchestrate AI workloads through a unified control plane, whether those workloads are running on cloud, on-premises, or in air-gapped infrastructure. The platform can work with any AI model and hardware accelerator including GPUs, CPUs, and TPUs.</p>



<p>&#8220;Clarifai has always been ahead of the curve, with over a decade of experience supporting large enterprise and mission-critical government needs with the full stack of AI tools to create custom AI workloads,&#8221; <a href="https://www.clarifai.com/press-release/clarifai-launches-first-vendor-agnostic-compute-orchestration-capabilities-to-optimize-ai-performance-and-spend">said</a> Matt Zeiler, founder and CEO of Clarifai. &#8220;Now, we&#8217;re opening up capabilities we built internally to optimise our compute costs as we scale to serve millions of models simultaneously.&#8221;</p>



<p>The company claims its platform can reduce compute usage by 3.7x through model packing optimisations while supporting over 1.6 million inference requests per second with 99.9997% reliability. According to Clarifai, the optimisations can potentially cut costs by 60-90%, depending on configuration.</p>



<p>Capabilities of the compute orchestration platform include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Cost optimisation through automated resource management, including model packing, dependency simplification, and customisable auto-scaling options that can scale to zero for model replicas and compute nodes,</li>



<li>Deployment flexibility on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/clarifai-launches-mobile-sdk-help-make-ai-available-devices/">any hardware</a> vendor including cloud, on-premise, air-gapped, and Clarifai SaaS infrastructure,</li>



<li>Integration with Clarifai&#8217;s AI platform for data labeling, training, evaluation, workflows, and feedback,</li>



<li>Security features that allow deployment into customer VPCs or on-premise Kubernetes clusters without requiring open inbound ports, VPC peering, or custom IAM roles.</li>
</ul>



<p>The platform emerged from Clarifai customers&#8217; issues with AI performance and cost. &#8220;If we had a way to think about it holistically and look at our on-prem costs compared to our cloud costs, and then be able to orchestrate across environments with a cost basis, that would be incredibly valuable,&#8221; noted a customer, as cited in Clarifai&#8217;s announcement.</p>



<p>The compute orchestration capabilities build on Clarifai&#8217;s existing AI platform that, the company says, has processed over 2 billion operations in computer vision, language, and audio AI. The company reports maintaining 99.99%+ uptime and 24/7 availability for critical applications.</p>



<p>The compute orchestration capability is currently available in public preview. Organisations interested in testing the platform should contact Clarifai for access.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/">New Clarifai tool orchestrates AI across any infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/new-clarifai-tool-orchestrates-ai-across-any-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Generative AI use soars among Brits, but is it sustainable?</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 20:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A survey by CloudNine PR shows that 83% of UK adults are aware of generative AI tools, and 45% of those familiar with them want companies to be transparent about the environmental costs associated with the technologies. With data centres burning vast amounts of energy, the growing demand for GenAI has sparked a debate about<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable/" title="ReadGenerative AI use soars among Brits, but is it sustainable?">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable/">Generative AI use soars among Brits, but is it sustainable?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A <a href="https://www.cloudninepr.com/genai-technology-climate-consumers-survey/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">survey by CloudNine PR</a> shows that 83% of UK adults are aware of generative AI tools, and 45% of those familiar with them want companies to be transparent about the environmental costs associated with the technologies.</p>



<p>With data centres burning vast amounts of energy, the growing demand for GenAI has sparked a debate about its sustainability.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The cost of intelligence: Generative AI’s carbon footprint</h3>



<p>Behind every AI-generated email, idea, or recommendation are data centres running thousands of energy-hungry servers. Data centres are responsible for both training the large language models that power generative AI and processing individual user queries. Unlike a simple Google search, which uses relatively little energy, a single generative AI request can consume up to ten times as much electricity.</p>



<p>The numbers are staggering. If all nine billion daily Google searches worldwide were replaced with generative AI tasks, the additional electricity demand would match the annual energy consumption of 1.5 million EU residents. According to consultants Morgan Stanley, the energy demands of generative AI are expected to grow by 70% annually until 2027. By that point, the energy required to support generative AI systems could rival the electricity needs of an entire country—Spain, for example, based on its 2022 usage.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">UK consumers want greener AI practices</h3>



<p>The survey also highlights growing awareness among UK consumers about the environmental implications of generative AI. Nearly one in five respondents said they don’t trust generative AI providers to manage their environmental impact responsibly. Among regular users of these tools, 10% expressed a willingness to pay a premium for products or services that prioritise energy efficiency and sustainability.</p>



<p>Interestingly, over a third (35%) of respondents think generative AI tools should &#8220;actively remind&#8221; users of their environmental impact. While this appears like a small step, it has the potential to encourage more mindful usage and place pressure on companies to adopt greener technologies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Efforts to tackle the environmental challenge</h3>



<p>Fortunately, some companies and policymakers are beginning to address these concerns. In the United States, the Artificial Intelligence Environmental Impacts Act was introduced earlier this year. The legislation aims to standardise how AI companies measure and report carbon emissions. It also provides a voluntary framework for developers to evaluate and disclose their systems’ environmental impact, pushing the industry towards greater transparency.</p>



<p>Major players in the tech industry are also stepping up. Companies like Salesforce have voiced support for legislation requiring standardised methods to measure and report AI’s carbon footprint. Experts point to several practical ways to reduce generative AI’s environmental impact, including adopting energy-efficient hardware, using sustainable cooling methods in data centres, and transitioning to renewable energy sources.</p>



<p>Despite these efforts, the urgency to address generative AI’s environmental impact remains critical. As Uday Radia, owner of CloudNine PR, puts it: “Generative AI has huge potential to make our lives better, but there is a race against time to make it more sustainable before it gets out of control.”</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/red-and-white-striped-flag-vuV25OfnGa8?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/the-ai-revolution-reshaping-data-centres-and-the-digital-landscape/" rel="noreferrer noopener">The AI revolution: Reshaping data centres and the digital landscape&nbsp;</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:969px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a target="_blank" href="https://www.ai-expo.net/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a target="_blank" href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlockX</a>,<a target="_blank" href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a target="_blank" href="https://techforge.pub/events/" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable/">Generative AI use soars among Brits, but is it sustainable?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/generative-ai-use-soars-among-brits-but-is-it-sustainable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Big tech’s AI spending hits new heights</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2024, Big Tech is all-in on artificial intelligence, with companies like Microsoft, Amazon, Alphabet, and Meta leading the way. Their combined spending on AI is projected to exceed a jaw-dropping $240 billion. Why? Because AI isn’t just the future—it’s the present, and the demand for AI-powered tools and infrastructure has never been higher. The<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights/" title="ReadBig tech’s AI spending hits new heights">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights/">Big tech’s AI spending hits new heights</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 2024, Big Tech is all-in on artificial intelligence, with companies like Microsoft, Amazon, Alphabet, and Meta leading the way.</p>



<p>Their combined spending on AI is projected to exceed a jaw-dropping $240 billion. Why? Because AI isn’t just the future—it’s the present, and the demand for AI-powered tools and infrastructure has never been higher. The companies aren’t just keeping up; they’re setting the pace for the industry.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://dataconomy.com/2024/11/18/big-tech-ai-spending-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scale of their investment</a> is hard to ignore. In the first half of 2023, tech giants poured $74 billion into capital expenditure. By Q3, that number had jumped to $109 billion. In mid-2024, spending reached $104 billion, a remarkable 47% rise over the same period a year earlier. By Q3, the total hit $171 billion.</p>



<p>If this pattern continues, Q4 might add another $70 billion, bringing the total to a truly staggering $240 billion for the year.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Why so much spending?</h3>



<p>AI’s potential is immense, and companies are making sure they’re positioned to reap the rewards.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A growing market: AI is projected to create $20 trillion in global economic impact by 2030. In countries like India, AI could contribute $500 billion to GDP by 2025. With stakes this high, big tech isn’t hesitating to invest heavily.</li>



<li>Infrastructure demands: Training and running AI models require massive investment in infrastructure, from data centres to high-performance GPUs. Alphabet increased its capital expenditures by 62% last quarter compared to the previous year, even as it cut its workforce by 9,000 employees to manage costs.</li>



<li>Revenue potential: AI is already proving its value. Microsoft’s AI products are expected to generate $10 billion annually—the fastest-growing segment in the company’s history. Alphabet, meanwhile, uses AI to write over 25% of its new code, streamlining operations.</li>
</ul>



<p>Amazon is also ramping up, with plans to spend $75 billion on capital expenditure in 2024. Meta’s forecast is not far behind, with estimates between $38 and $40 billion. Across the board, organisations recognise that maintaining their edge in AI requires sustained and significant investment.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Supporting revenue streams</h3>



<p>What keeps the massive investments keep on coming is the strength of big tech’s core businesses. Last quarter, Alphabet’s digital advertising machine, which is powered by Google’s search engine, generated $49.39 billion in ad revenue, a 12% year-over-year increase. This as a solid foundation that allows Alphabet to pour resources into building out its AI arsenal without destabilising the bottom line.</p>



<p>Microsoft’s diversified revenue streams are another example. While the company spent $20 billion on AI and cloud infrastructure last quarter, its productivity segment, which includes Office, grew by 12% to $28.3 billion, and its personal computing business, boosted by <a href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/24/11/18/0022217/google-microsoft-are-spending-massively-on-ai-quarterly-earnings-show" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox and the Activision Blizzard acquisition</a>, grew 17% to $13.2 billion. These successes demonstrate how AI investments can support broader growth strategies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The financial payoff</h3>



<p>Big tech is already seeing the benefits of its heavy spending. Microsoft’s Azure platform has seen substantial growth, with its AI income approaching $6 billion. Amazon’s AI business is growing at triple-digit rates, and Alphabet reported a 34% jump in profits last quarter, with cloud revenue playing a major role.</p>



<p>Meta, while primarily focused on advertising, is leveraging AI to make its platforms more engaging. AI-driven tools, such as improved feeds and search features keep users on its platforms longer, resulting in new revenue growth.</p>



<p>AI spending shows no signs of slowing down. Tech leaders at Microsoft and Alphabet view AI as a long-term investment critical to their future success. And the results speak for themselves: Alphabet’s cloud revenue is up 35%, while Microsoft’s cloud business grew 20% last quarter.</p>



<p>For the time being, the focus is on scaling up infrastructure and meeting demand. However, the real transformation will come when big tech unlocks AI’s full potential, transforming industries and redefining how we work and live.</p>



<p>By investing in high-quality, centralised data strategies, businesses can ensure trustworthy and accurate AI implementations, and unlock AI’s full potential to drive innovation, improve decision-making, and gain competitive edge. AI’s revolutionary promise is within reach—but only for companies prepared to lay the groundwork for sustainable growth and long-term results.</p>



<p>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/black-and-white-smartphone-displaying-google-search-yp-BBMj_4wM?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>)</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-tries-to-convert-google-chrome-users/">Microsoft tries to convert Google Chrome users</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:1291px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a target="_blank" href="https://www.ai-expo.net/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a target="_blank" href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlockX</a>,<a target="_blank" href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a target="_blank" href="https://techforge.pub/events/" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights/">Big tech’s AI spending hits new heights</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/big-tech-ai-spending-hits-new-heights/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salesforce launches AI platform for automated task management</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 09:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salesforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Business Insider’s “CXO AI Playbook” looks at how firms are utilising AI to tackle challenges, scale operations, and plan for the future. The Playbook looks at stories from various industries to see what problems AI is solving, who’s driving these initiatives, and how it’s reshaping strategies. Salesforce, well known for its CRM software used by<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management/" title="ReadSalesforce launches AI platform for automated task management">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management/">Salesforce launches AI platform for automated task management</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><a target="_blank" href="https://www.businessinsider.com/salesforce-agentforce-ai-tool-automate-tasks-boost-productivity-2024-11" rel="noreferrer noopener">Business Insider’s</a></em> “CXO AI Playbook” looks at how firms are utilising AI to tackle challenges, scale operations, and plan for the future.</p>



<p>The Playbook looks at stories from various industries to see what problems AI is solving, who’s driving these initiatives, and how it’s reshaping strategies.</p>



<p>Salesforce, well known for its CRM software used by over 150,000 companies like Amazon and Walmart, is no stranger to innovation. It also owns Slack, the popular workplace communication app. Salesforce is now stepping up its AI game with Agentforce, a platform that lets businesses to build and deploy digital agents to automate tasks such as creating sales reports and summarising Slack conversations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What problem is it solving?</h3>



<p>Salesforce has been working with AI for years. In 2016, it launched Einstein, an AI feature baked into its CRM platform. Einstein handled basic scriptable tasks, but the rise of generative AI brought a chance to do more. Smarter tools could now make better decisions and understand natural language.</p>



<p>This sparked a transformation. First came Einstein GPT, then Einstein Copilot, and now Agentforce—a platform designed for flexibility with prebuilt and customisable agents to handle diverse business needs.</p>



<p>“Our customers wanted more. Some wanted to tweak the agents we offer, while others wanted to create their own,” said Tyler Carlson, Salesforce’s VP of Business Development.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The tech behind it</h3>



<p>Agentforce is powered by Salesforce’s Atlas Reasoning Engine, developed in-house. The platform connects with AI models from major players like OpenAI, Anthropic, Amazon, and Google, giving businesses access to a variety of tools.</p>



<p>Slack has become a testing ground for these AI agents. Currently in beta, Agentforce’s Slack integration puts automations where employees already spend their time. “Slack makes these tools easy to use and accessible,” Carlson added.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Smarter, more flexible AI</h3>



<p>Agentforce uses ReAct prompting, a technique that helps agents break down problems into smaller steps and adjust their approach as they go. This leads to more accurate responses and hands-off task management, from answering questions to scheduling meetings.</p>



<p>Agentforce works with Salesforce’s proprietary LLMs and third-party models, giving clients plenty of options. To ensure security, Salesforce enforces strict data privacy policies, including limits on data retention.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Making it work for businesses</h3>



<p>With tools like Agentbuilder, companies can design AI agents tailored to their needs. For example, an agent could sort emails or answer specific HR questions using internal data. One example is Salesforce’s collaboration with Workday to create an AI service agent for employee queries.</p>



<p>Salesforce is already seeing results, with Agentforce resolving 90% of customer inquiries in early trials. The goal? Broader adoption, more capabilities, and higher workloads handled by these agents.</p>



<p>“We’re building a bigger ecosystem of partners and skills,” Carlson said. “By next year, we want Agentforce to be a must-have for businesses.”</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-large-open-office-space-with-many-desks-and-chairs-Mgm6aq1UYpI?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/paul-osullivan-salesforce-transforming-work-genai-era/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Paul O&#8217;Sullivan, Salesforce: Transforming work in the GenAI era</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:2239px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a target="_blank" href="https://www.ai-expo.net/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a target="_blank" href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlockX</a>,<a target="_blank" href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a target="_blank" href="https://techforge.pub/events/" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management/">Salesforce launches AI platform for automated task management</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-launches-ai-platform-for-automated-task-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NVIDIA AI Summit Japan: NVIDIA’s role in Japan’s big AI ambitions</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nvidia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Japan is on a mission to become a global AI powerhouse, and it’s starting with some impressive advances in AI-driven language models. Japanese technology experts are developing advanced models that grasp the unique nuances of the Japanese language and culture—essential for industries such as healthcare, finance, and manufacturing – where precision is key. But this<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions/" title="ReadNVIDIA AI Summit Japan: NVIDIA’s role in Japan’s big AI ambitions">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions/">NVIDIA AI Summit Japan: NVIDIA’s role in Japan’s big AI ambitions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Japan is on a mission to become a global AI powerhouse, and it’s starting with some impressive advances in AI-driven language models. </p>



<p>Japanese technology experts are developing advanced models that grasp the unique nuances of the Japanese language and culture—essential for industries such as healthcare, finance, and manufacturing – where precision is key.</p>



<p>But this effort isn’t Japan’s alone. Consulting giants like Accenture, Deloitte, EY Japan, FPT, Kyndryl, and TCS Japan are partnering with NVIDIA to create AI innovation hubs across the country. The centres are using NVIDIA’s AI software and specialised Japanese language models to build tailored AI solutions, helping industries boost productivity in a digital workforce. The goal? To get Japanese companies fully on board with enterprise and physical AI.</p>



<p>One standout technology supporting the drive is NVIDIA’s Omniverse platform. With Omniverse, Japanese companies can create digital twins—virtual replicas of real-world assets—and test complex AI systems safely before implementing them. This is a game-changer for industries such as manufacturing and robotics, allowing businesses to fine-tune processes without the risk of real-world trial and error. This use of AI is more than just innovation; it represents Japan’s plan for addressing some major challenges ahead.</p>



<p>Japan faces a shrinking workforce presence as its population ages. With its strengths in robotics and automation, Japan is well-positioned to use AI solutions to bridge the gap. In fact, Japan’s government recently shared its vision of becoming “the world’s most AI-friendly country,” underscoring the perceived role AI will play in the nation’s future.</p>



<p>Supporting this commitment, Japan’s AI market hit $5.9 billion in value this year; a 31.2% growth rate according to IDC. New AI-focused consulting centres in Tokyo and Kansai give Japanese businesses hands-on access to NVIDIA’s latest technologies, equipping them to solve social challenges and aid economic growth.</p>



<p>Top cloud providers like SoftBank, GMO Internet Group, KDDI, Highreso, Rutilea, and SAKURA Internet are also involved, working with NVIDIA to build AI infrastructure. Backed by Japan’s Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry, they’re establishing AI data centres across Japan to accelerate growth in robotics, automotive, healthcare, and telecoms.</p>



<p>NVIDIA and SoftBank have also formed a remarkable partnership to build Japan’s most powerful AI supercomputer using <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/data-center/technologies/blackwell-architecture/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA’s Blackwell platform</a>. Additionally, SoftBank has tested the world’s first AI and 5G hybrid telecoms network with NVIDIA’s AI Aerial platform, allowing Japan to set a worldwide standard. With these developments, Japan is taking big strides toward establishing itself as a leader in the AI-powered industrial revolution.</p>



<p>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@zelebb?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Andrey Matveev</a>)</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-share-price-nosedives-antitrust-clouds-gather/" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA&#8217;s share price nosedives as antitrust clouds gather</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions/">NVIDIA AI Summit Japan: NVIDIA’s role in Japan’s big AI ambitions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-ai-summit-japan-nvidia-role-in-japans-big-ai-ambitions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Telecom trains AI model with 1 trillion parameters on domestic chips</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telecoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[llm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nvidia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>China Telecom, one of the country&#8217;s state-owned telecom giants, has created two LLMs that were trained solely on domestically-produced chips. This breakthrough represents a significant step in China&#8217;s ongoing efforts to become self-reliant in AI technology, especially in light of escalating US limitations on access to advanced semiconductors for its competitors. According to the company&#8217;s<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips/" title="ReadChina Telecom trains AI model with 1 trillion parameters on domestic chips">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips/">China Telecom trains AI model with 1 trillion parameters on domestic chips</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China Telecom, one of the country&#8217;s state-owned telecom giants, has created two LLMs that were trained solely on domestically-produced chips.</p>



<p>This breakthrough represents a significant step in China&#8217;s ongoing efforts to become self-reliant in AI technology, especially in light of escalating US limitations on access to advanced semiconductors for its competitors.</p>



<p>According to the company&#8217;s Institute of AI, one of the models, TeleChat2-115B and another unnamed model were trained on tens of thousands of Chinese-made chips. This achievement is especially noteworthy given the tighter US export rules that have limited China&#8217;s ability to purchase high-end processors from <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-share-price-nosedives-antitrust-clouds-gather/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nvidia</a> and other foreign companies. In a statement shared on WeChat, the AI institute claimed that this accomplishment demonstrated China&#8217;s capability to independently train LLMs and signals a new era of innovation and self-reliance in AI technology.</p>



<p>The scale of these models is remarkable. China Telecom stated that the unnamed LLM has one trillion parameters. In AI terminology, parameters are the variables that help the model in learning during training. The more parameters there are, the more complicated and powerful the AI becomes.</p>



<p>Chinese companies are striving to keep pace with global leaders in AI based outside the country. Washington&#8217;s export restrictions on Nvidia&#8217;s latest AI chips such as the A100 and H100, have compelled China to seek alternatives. As a result, Chinese companies have developed their own processors to reduce reliance on Western technologies. For instance, the TeleChat2-115B model has approximately 100 billion parameters, and therefore can perform as well as mainstream platforms.</p>



<p>China Telecom did not specify which company supplied the domestically-designed chips used to train its models. However, as previously discussed on these pages,  <a href="https://www.scmp.com/knowledge/companies/huawei?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Huawei&#8217;s Ascend chips</a> play a key part in the country&#8217;s AI plans.</p>



<p>Huawei, which has faced US penalties in recent years, is also increasing its efforts in the artificial intelligence field. The company has recently started testing its latest AI processor, the Ascend 910C, with potential clients waiting in the domestic market. Large Chinese server companies, as well as internet giants that have previously used Nvidia chips, are apparently testing the new chip&#8217;s performance. Huawei&#8217;s Ascend processors, as one of the few viable alternatives to Nvidia hardware, are viewed as a key component of China&#8217;s strategy that will lessen its reliance on foreign technology.</p>



<p>In addition to Huawei, China Telecom is collaborating with other domestic chipmakers such as Cambricon, a Chinese start-up specialising in AI processors. The partnerships reflect a broader tendency in China&#8217;s tech industry to build a homegrown ecosystem of AI solutions, further shielding the country from the effects of US export controls.</p>



<p>By developing its own AI chips and technology, China is gradually reducing its dependence on foreign-made hardware, especially Nvidia&#8217;s highly sought-after and therefore expensive GPUs. While US sanctions make it difficult for Chinese companies to obtain the latest Nvidia hardware, a black market for foreign chips has emerged. Rather than risk operating in the grey market, many Chinese companies prefer to purchase lower-powered alternatives such as previous-gen models to maintain access to Nvidia&#8217;s official support and services.</p>



<p>China&#8217;s achievement reflects a broader shift in its approach to AI and semiconductor technology, emphasising self-sufficiency and resilience in an increasingly competitive global economy and in face of American protectionist trade policies.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@markkuiper?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Mark Kuiper</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/has-huawei-outsmarted-apple-in-ai-race/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Has Huawei outsmarted Apple in the AI race?</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips/">China Telecom trains AI model with 1 trillion parameters on domestic chips</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/china-telecom-trains-ai-model-with-1-trillion-parameters-on-domestic-chips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Han Heloir, MongoDB: The role of scalable databases in AI-powered apps</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As data management grows more complex and modern applications extend the capabilities of traditional approaches, AI is revolutionising application scaling. In addition to freeing operators from outdated, inefficient methods that require careful supervision and extra resources, AI enables real-time, adaptive optimisation of application scaling. Ultimately, these benefits combine to enhance efficiency and reduce costs for<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases/" title="ReadHan Heloir, MongoDB: The role of scalable databases in AI-powered apps">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases/">Han Heloir, MongoDB: The role of scalable databases in AI-powered apps</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As data management grows more complex and modern applications extend the capabilities of traditional approaches, AI is revolutionising application scaling.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-medium is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="300" height="300" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-300x300.jpeg" alt="Han Heloir, EMEA gen AI senior solutions architect at MongoDB" class="wp-image-16127" style="object-fit:cover;width:210px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-125x125.jpeg 125w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-200x200.jpeg 200w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-285x285.jpeg 285w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-250x250.jpeg 250w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-100x100.jpeg 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB-60x60.jpeg 60w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Han-Heloir-EMEA-gen-AI-senior-solutions-architect-at-MongoDB.jpeg 399w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Han Heloir, EMEA gen AI senior solutions architect, MongoDB.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In addition to freeing operators from outdated, inefficient methods that require careful supervision and extra resources, AI enables real-time, adaptive optimisation of application scaling. Ultimately, these benefits combine to enhance efficiency and reduce costs for targeted applications.</p>



<p>With its predictive capabilities, AI ensures that applications scale efficiently, improving performance and resource allocation—marking a major advance over conventional methods.</p>



<p>Ahead of <a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/europe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI &amp; Big Data Expo Europe</a>, Han Heloir, EMEA gen AI senior solutions architect at <a href="https://www.mongodb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MongoDB</a>, discusses the future of AI-powered applications and the role of scalable databases in supporting generative AI and enhancing business processes.</p>



<p><strong>AI News: As AI-powered applications continue to grow in complexity and scale, what do you see as the most significant trends shaping the future of database technology?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Heloir:</strong> While enterprises are keen to leverage the transformational power of generative AI technologies, the reality is that building a robust, scalable technology foundation involves more than just choosing the right technologies. It&#8217;s about creating systems that can grow and adapt to the evolving demands of generative AI, demands that are changing quickly, some of which traditional IT infrastructure may not be able to support. That is the uncomfortable truth about the current situation.</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s IT architectures are being overwhelmed by unprecedented data volumes generated from increasingly interconnected data sets. Traditional systems, designed for less intensive data exchanges, are currently unable to handle the massive, continuous data streams required for real-time AI responsiveness. They are also unprepared to manage the variety of data being generated.</p>



<p>The generative AI ecosystem often comprises a complex set of technologies. Each layer of technology—from data sourcing to model deployment—increases functional depth and operational costs. Simplifying these technology stacks isn&#8217;t just about improving operational efficiency; it&#8217;s also a financial necessity.</p>



<p><strong>AI News: What are some key considerations for businesses when selecting a scalable database for AI-powered applications, especially those involving generative AI?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Heloir: </strong>Businesses should prioritise flexibility, performance and future scalability. Here are a few key reasons:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The variety and volume of data will continue to grow, requiring the database to handle diverse data types—structured, unstructured, and semi-structured—at scale. Selecting a database that can manage such variety without complex ETL processes is important.</li>



<li>AI models often need access to real-time data for training and inference, so the database must offer low latency to enable real-time decision-making and responsiveness.</li>



<li>As AI models grow and data volumes expand, databases must scale horizontally, to allow organisations to add capacity without significant downtime or performance degradation.</li>



<li>Seamless integration with data science and machine learning tools is crucial, and native support for AI workflows—such as managing model data, training sets and inference data—can enhance operational efficiency.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>AI News: What are the common challenges organisations face when integrating AI into their operations, and how can scalable databases help address these issues?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Heloir:</strong> There are a variety of challenges that organisations can run into when adopting AI. These include the massive amounts of data from a wide variety of sources that are required to build AI applications. Scaling these initiatives can also put strain on the existing IT infrastructure and once the models are built, they require continuous iteration and improvement.</p>



<p>To make this easier, a database that scales can help simplify the management, storage and retrieval of diverse datasets. It offers elasticity, allowing businesses to handle fluctuating demands while sustaining performance and efficiency. Additionally, they accelerate time-to-market for AI-driven innovations by enabling rapid data ingestion and retrieval, facilitating faster experimentation.</p>



<p><strong>AI News: Could you provide examples of how collaborations between database providers and AI-focused companies have driven innovation in AI solutions?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Heloir:</strong> Many businesses struggle to build generative AI applications because the technology evolves so quickly. Limited expertise and the increased complexity of integrating diverse components further complicate the process, slowing innovation and hindering the development of AI-driven solutions.</p>



<p>One way we address these challenges is through our MongoDB AI Applications Program (<a href="https://www.mongodb.com/blog/post/mongodb-ai-applications-program-maap-is-now-available" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MAAP</a>), which provides customers with resources to assist them in putting AI applications into production. This includes reference architectures and an end-to-end technology stack that integrates with leading technology providers, professional services and a unified support system.</p>



<p>MAAP categorises customers into four groups, ranging from those seeking advice and prototyping to those developing mission-critical AI applications and overcoming technical challenges. MongoDB&#8217;s MAAP enables faster, seamless development of generative AI applications, fostering creativity and reducing complexity.</p>



<p><strong>AI News: How does MongoDB approach the challenges of supporting AI-powered applications, particularly in industries that are rapidly adopting AI?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Heloir:</strong> Ensuring you have the underlying infrastructure to build what you need is always one of the biggest challenges organisations face.</p>



<p>To build AI-powered applications, the underlying database must be capable of running queries against rich, flexible data structures. With AI, data structures can become very complex. This is one of the biggest challenges organisations face when building AI-powered applications, and it&#8217;s precisely what MongoDB is designed to handle. We unify source data, metadata, operational data, vector data and generated data—all in one platform.<a id="_msocom_1"></a></p>



<p><strong>AI News: What future developments in database technology do you anticipate, and how is MongoDB preparing to support the next generation of AI applications?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Heloir:</strong> Our key values are the same today as they were when MongoDB initially launched: we want to make developers&#8217; lives easier and help them drive business ROI. This remains unchanged in the age of artificial intelligence. We will continue to listen to our customers, assist them in overcoming their biggest difficulties, and ensure that MongoDB has the features they require to develop the next [generation of] great applications.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@casparrubin?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Caspar Camille Rubin</a>)</em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases/">Han Heloir, MongoDB: The role of scalable databases in AI-powered apps</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/han-heloir-mongodb-the-future-of-ai-powered-applications-and-scalable-databases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
