<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>eu Archives - AI News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tag/eu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tag/eu/</link>
	<description>Artificial Intelligence News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/ai-icon-60x60.png</url>
	<title>eu Archives - AI News</title>
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tag/eu/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Governments are scrambling to establish regulations to govern AI, citing numerous concerns over data privacy, bias, safety, and more. AI News caught up with Nerijus Šveistys, Senior Legal Counsel at Oxylabs, to understand the state of play when it comes to AI regulation and its potential implications for industries, businesses, and innovation. “The boom of<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/" title="ReadAI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/">AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Governments are scrambling to establish regulations to govern AI, citing numerous concerns over data privacy, bias, safety, and more.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="800" height="800" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-16743" style="width:174px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs.jpeg 800w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-768x768.jpeg 768w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-125x125.jpeg 125w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-200x200.jpeg 200w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-285x285.jpeg 285w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-250x250.jpeg 250w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-100x100.jpeg 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-60x60.jpeg 60w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-400x400.jpeg 400w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-600x600.jpeg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<p>AI News caught up with Nerijus Šveistys, Senior Legal Counsel at <a href="https://oxylabs.io/">Oxylabs</a>, to understand the state of play when it comes to AI regulation and its potential implications for industries, businesses, and innovation.</p>



<p>“The boom of the last few years appears to have sparked a push to establish regulatory frameworks for AI governance,” explains Šveistys.</p>



<p>“This is a natural development, as the rise of AI seems to pose issues in data privacy and protection, bias and discrimination, safety, intellectual property, and other legal areas, as well as ethics that need to be addressed.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Regions diverge in regulatory strategy</h3>



<p>The European Union’s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/">AI Act</a> has, unsurprisingly, positioned the region with a strict, centralised approach. The regulation, which came into force this year, is set to be fully effective by 2026.</p>



<p>Šveistys pointed out that the EU has acted relatively swiftly compared to other jurisdictions: “The main difference we can see is the comparative quickness with which the EU has released a uniform regulation to govern the use of all types of AI.”</p>



<p>Meanwhile, other regions have opted for more piecemeal approaches. China, for instance, has been implementing regulations specific to certain AI technologies in a phased-out manner. According to Šveistys, China began regulating AI models as early as 2021.</p>



<p>“In 2021, they introduced regulation on recommendation algorithms, which [had] increased their capabilities in digital advertising. It was followed by regulations <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinas-deepfake-laws-come-into-effect-today/">on deep synthesis models</a> or, in common terms, deepfakes and content generation in 2022,” he said.</p>



<p>“Then, in 2023, regulation on generative AI models was introduced as these models were making a splash in commercial usage.”</p>



<p>The US, in contrast, remains relatively uncoordinated in its approach. Federal-level regulations are yet to be enacted, with efforts mostly emerging at the state level.</p>



<p>“There are proposed regulations at the state level, such as the so-called California AI Act, but even if they come into power, it may still take some time before they do,” Šveistys noted.</p>



<p>This delay in implementing unified AI regulations in the US has raised questions about the extent to which business pushback may be contributing to the slow rollout. Šveistys said that while lobbyist pressure is a known factor, it’s not the only potential reason.</p>



<p>“There was <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/">pushback to the EU AI Act</a>, too, which was nevertheless introduced. Thus, it is not clear whether the delay in the US is only due to lobbyism or other obstacles in the legislation enactment process,” explains Šveistys.</p>



<p>“It might also be because some still see AI as a futuristic concern, not fully appreciating the extent to which it is already a legal issue of today.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Balancing innovation and safety</h3>



<p>Differentiated regulatory approaches could affect the pace of innovation and business competitiveness across regions.</p>



<p>Europe’s regulatory framework, though more stringent, aims to ensure consumer protection and ethical adherence—something that less-regulated environments may lack.</p>



<p>“More rigid regulatory frameworks may impose compliance costs for businesses in the AI field and stifle competitiveness and innovation. On the other hand, they bring the benefits of protecting consumers and adhering to certain ethical norms,” comments Šveistys.</p>



<p>This trade-off is especially pronounced in AI-related sectors such as targeted advertising, where algorithmic bias is increasingly scrutinised.</p>



<p>AI governance often extends beyond laws that specifically target AI, incorporating related legal areas like those governing data collection and privacy. For example, the EU AI Act also regulates the use of AI in physical devices, such as elevators.</p>



<p>&#8220;Additionally, all businesses that collect data for advertisement are potentially affected as AI regulation can also cover algorithmic bias in targeted advertising,&#8221; emphasises Šveistys.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Impact on related industries</h3>



<p>One industry that is deeply intertwined with AI developments is web scraping. Typically used for collecting publicly available data, web scraping is undergoing an AI-driven evolution.</p>



<p>&#8220;From data collection, validation, analysis, or overcoming anti-scraping measures, there is a lot of potential for AI to massively improve the efficiency, accuracy, and adaptability of web scraping operations,&#8221; said Šveistys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, as AI regulation and related laws tighten, web scraping companies will face greater scrutiny.</p>



<p>“AI regulations may also bring the spotlight on certain areas of law that were always very relevant to the web scraping industry, such as privacy or copyright laws,” Šveistys added.</p>



<p>“At the end of the day, scraping content protected by such laws without proper authorisation could always lead to legal issues, and now so can using AI this way.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Copyright battles and legal precedents</h3>



<p>The implications of AI regulation are also playing out on a broader legal stage, particularly in cases involving generative AI tools.</p>



<p>High-profile <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-microsoft-lawsuit-github-copilot/">lawsuits</a> have been launched against AI giants like OpenAI and its primary backer, Microsoft, by authors, artists, and musicians who claim their copyrighted materials were used to train AI systems without proper permission.</p>



<p>“These cases are pivotal in determining the legal boundaries of using copyrighted material for AI development and establishing legal precedents for protecting intellectual property in the digital age,” said Šveistys.</p>



<p>While these lawsuits could take years to resolve, their outcomes may fundamentally shape the future of AI development. So, what can businesses do now as the regulatory and legal landscape continues to evolve?</p>



<p>“Speaking about the specific cases of using copyrighted material for AI training, businesses should approach this the same way as any web-scraping activity – that is, evaluate the specific data they wish to collect with the help of a legal expert in the field,” recommends Šveistys.</p>



<p>“It is important to recognise that the AI legal landscape is very new and rapidly evolving, with not many precedents in place to refer to as of yet. Hence, continuous monitoring and adaptation of your AI usage are crucial.”</p>



<p>Just this week, the UK Government made headlines with its announcement of a consultation on the use of copyrighted material for training AI models. Under the proposals, tech firms could be permitted to use copyrighted material unless owners have specifically opted out.</p>



<p>Despite the diversity of approaches globally, the AI regulatory push marks a significant moment for technological governance. Whether through the EU’s comprehensive model, China’s step-by-step strategy, or narrower, state-level initiatives like in the US, businesses worldwide must navigate a complex, evolving framework.</p>



<p>The challenge ahead will be striking the right balance between fostering innovation and mitigating risks, ensuring that AI remains a force for good while avoiding potential harms.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nathangbingle?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nathan Bingle</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-urges-ai-regulation-avoid-catastrophes/"><strong>Anthropic urges AI regulation to avoid catastrophes</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:844px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/">AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU introduces draft regulatory guidance for AI models</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guidance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16496</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The release of the &#8220;First Draft General-Purpose AI Code of Practice&#8221; marks the EU&#8217;s effort to create comprehensive regulatory guidance for general-purpose AI models. The development of this draft has been a collaborative effort, involving input from diverse sectors including industry, academia, and civil society. The initiative was led by four specialised Working Groups, each<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models/" title="ReadEU introduces draft regulatory guidance for AI models">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models/">EU introduces draft regulatory guidance for AI models</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/first-draft-general-purpose-ai-code-practice-published-written-independent-experts">release</a> of the &#8220;First Draft General-Purpose AI Code of Practice&#8221; marks the EU&#8217;s effort to create comprehensive regulatory guidance for general-purpose AI models.</p>



<p>The development of this draft has been a collaborative effort, involving input from diverse sectors including industry, academia, and civil society. The initiative was led by four specialised Working Groups, each addressing specific aspects of AI governance and risk mitigation:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Working Group 1: Transparency and copyright-related rules</li>



<li>Working Group 2: Risk identification and assessment for systemic risk</li>



<li>Working Group 3: Technical risk mitigation for systemic risk</li>



<li>Working Group 4: Governance risk mitigation for systemic risk</li>
</ul>



<p>The draft is aligned with existing laws such as the Charter of Fundamental Rights of the European Union. It takes into account international approaches, striving for proportionality to risks, and aims to be future-proof by contemplating rapid technological changes.</p>



<p>Key objectives outlined in the draft include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Clarifying compliance methods for providers of general-purpose AI models</li>



<li>Facilitating understanding across the AI value chain, ensuring seamless integration of AI models into downstream products</li>



<li>Ensuring compliance with Union law on copyrights, especially concerning the use of copyrighted material for model training</li>



<li>Continuously assessing and mitigating systemic risks associated with AI models</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Recognising and mitigating systemic risks</h3>



<p>A core feature of the draft is its taxonomy of systemic risks, which includes types, natures, and sources of such risks. The document outlines various threats such as cyber offences, biological risks, loss of control over autonomous AI models, and large-scale disinformation. By acknowledging the continuously evolving nature of AI technology, the draft recognises that this taxonomy will need updates to remain relevant.</p>



<p>As AI models with systemic risks become more common, the draft emphasises the need for robust safety and security frameworks (SSFs). It proposes a hierarchy of measures, sub-measures, and key performance indicators (KPIs) to ensure appropriate risk identification, analysis, and mitigation throughout a model&#8217;s lifecycle.</p>



<p>The draft suggests that providers establish processes to identify and report serious incidents associated with their AI models, offering detailed assessments and corrections as needed. It also encourages collaboration with independent experts for risk assessment, especially for models posing significant systemic risks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Taking a proactive stance to AI regulatory guidance</h3>



<p>The <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/">EU AI Act</a>, which came into force on 1 August 2024, mandates that the final version of this Code be ready by 1 May 2025. This initiative underscores the EU&#8217;s proactive stance towards AI regulation, emphasising the need for AI safety, transparency, and accountability.</p>



<p>As the draft continues to evolve, the working groups invite stakeholders to participate actively in refining the document. Their collaborative input will shape a regulatory framework aimed at safeguarding innovation while protecting society from the potential pitfalls of AI technology.</p>



<p>While still in draft form, the EU&#8217;s Code of Practice for general-purpose AI models could set a benchmark for responsible AI development and deployment globally. By addressing key issues such as transparency, risk management, and copyright compliance, the Code aims to create a regulatory environment that fosters innovation, upholds fundamental rights, and ensures a high level of consumer protection.</p>



<p><em>This draft is open for written feedback until 28 November 2024.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-urges-ai-regulation-avoid-catastrophes/"><strong>Anthropic urges AI regulation to avoid catastrophes</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:2239px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models/">EU introduces draft regulatory guidance for AI models</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-introduces-draft-regulatory-guidance-for-ai-models/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU AI Act: Early prep could give businesses competitive edge</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The EU AI Act is set to fully take effect in August 2026, but some provisions are coming into force even earlier. The legislation establishes a first-of-its-kind regulatory framework for AI systems, employing a risk-based approach that categorises AI applications based on their potential impact on safety, human rights, and societal wellbeing. &#8220;Some systems are<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/" title="ReadEU AI Act: Early prep could give businesses competitive edge">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/">EU AI Act: Early prep could give businesses competitive edge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The EU AI Act is set to fully take effect in August 2026, but some provisions are coming into force even earlier.</p>



<p>The legislation establishes a first-of-its-kind regulatory framework for AI systems, employing a risk-based approach that categorises AI applications based on their potential impact on safety, human rights, and societal wellbeing.</p>



<p>&#8220;Some systems are banned entirely, while systems deemed &#8216;high-risk&#8217; are subject to stricter requirements and assessments before deployment,&#8221; explains the <a href="https://www.dpocentre.com/">DPO Centre</a>, a data protection consultancy.</p>



<p>Similar to <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/EN/legal-content/summary/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr.html">GDPR</a>, the Act&#8217;s extra-territorial reach means it applies to any organisation marketing, deploying, or using AI systems within the EU, regardless of where the system is developed. Businesses will be classified primarily as either ‘Providers’ or ‘Deployers,’ with additional categories for ‘Distributors,’ ‘Importers,’ ‘Product Manufacturers,’ and ‘Authorised Representatives.’</p>



<p>For organisations developing or deploying AI systems, particularly those classified as high-risk, compliance preparation promises to be complex. However, experts suggest viewing this as an opportunity rather than a burden.</p>



<p>&#8220;By embracing compliance as a catalyst for more transparent AI usage, businesses can turn regulatory demands into a competitive advantage,&#8221; notes the DPO Centre.</p>



<p>Key preparation strategies include comprehensive staff training, establishing robust corporate governance, and implementing strong cybersecurity measures. The legislation&#8217;s requirements often overlap with existing GDPR frameworks, particularly regarding transparency and accountability.</p>



<p>Organisations must also adhere to ethical AI principles and maintain clear documentation of their systems&#8217; functionality, limitations, and intended use. The EU is currently developing specific codes of practice and templates to assist with compliance obligations.</p>



<p>For businesses uncertain about their obligations, experts recommend seeking professional guidance early. Tools like the EU AI Act Compliance Checker can help organisations verify their systems&#8217; alignment with regulatory requirements.</p>



<p>Rather than viewing compliance as <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/">merely a regulatory burden</a>, forward-thinking organisations should view the EU’s AI Act <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/">as an opportunity</a> to demonstrate commitment to responsible AI development and build greater trust with their customers.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-gap-95-of-firms-havent-frameworks/"><strong>AI governance gap: 95% of firms haven’t implemented frameworks</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/">EU AI Act: Early prep could give businesses competitive edge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech industry giants urge EU to streamline AI regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 15:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta (Facebook)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Meta has spearheaded an open letter calling for urgent reform of AI regulations in the EU. The letter, which garnered support from over 50 prominent companies – including Ericsson, SAP, and Spotify – was published as an advert in the Financial Times. The collective voice of these industry leaders highlights a pressing issue: Europe&#8217;s bureaucratic<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/" title="ReadTech industry giants urge EU to streamline AI regulations">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/">Tech industry giants urge EU to streamline AI regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/metas-ai-strategy-building-for-tomorrow-not-immediate-profits/">Meta</a> has spearheaded an open letter calling for urgent reform of AI regulations in the EU. The letter, which garnered support from over 50 prominent companies – including <a href="https://www.telecomstechnews.com/news/ai-ran-collaboration-advance-mobile-networks/">Ericsson</a>, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sap-taps-microsoft-generative-ai-technologies/">SAP</a>, and Spotify – was published as an advert in the <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ft-and-openai-ink-partnership-web-scraping-criticism/">Financial Times</a>.</p>



<p>The collective voice of these industry leaders highlights a pressing issue: Europe&#8217;s bureaucratic approach to AI regulation may be stifling innovation and causing the region to lag behind its global counterparts.</p>



<p>&#8220;Europe has become less competitive and less innovative compared to other regions and it now risks falling further behind in the AI era due to inconsistent regulatory decision making,&#8221; the letter states, painting a stark picture of the continent&#8217;s current position in the AI race.</p>



<p>The signatories emphasise two key areas of concern. Firstly, they point to the development of &#8216;open&#8217; models, which are freely available for use, modification, and further development. These models are lauded for their potential to &#8220;multiply the benefits and spread social and economic opportunity&#8221; while simultaneously bolstering sovereignty and control.</p>



<p>Secondly, the letter underscores the importance of &#8216;multimodal&#8217; models, which integrate text, images, and speech capabilities. The signatories argue that the leap from text-only to multimodal models is akin to &#8220;the difference between having only one sense and having all five of them&#8221;. They assert that these advanced models could significantly boost productivity, drive scientific research, and inject hundreds of billions of euros into the European economy.</p>



<p>However, the crux of the matter lies in the regulatory landscape. The letter expresses frustration with the uncertainty surrounding data usage for AI model training, stemming from interventions by European Data Protection Authorities. This ambiguity, they argue, could result in Large Language Models (LLMs) lacking crucial Europe-specific training data.</p>



<p>To address these challenges, the signatories call for &#8220;harmonised, consistent, quick and clear decisions under EU data regulations that enable European data to be used in AI training for the benefit of Europeans&#8221;. They stress the need for &#8220;decisive action&#8221; to unlock Europe&#8217;s potential for creativity, ingenuity, and entrepreneurship, which they believe is essential for the region&#8217;s prosperity and technological leadership.</p>



<p>A copy of the letter can be found below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="636" height="1024" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-636x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-16118" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-636x1024.jpg 636w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-186x300.jpg 186w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-768x1236.jpg 768w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-954x1536.jpg 954w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-124x200.jpg 124w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-177x285.jpg 177w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-155x250.jpg 155w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-62x100.jpg 62w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal-37x60.jpg 37w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/meta-eu-ai-regulation-letter-artificial-intelligence-european-union-politics-law-legal.jpg 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p>While the letter acknowledges the importance of consumer protection, it also highlights the delicate balance regulators must strike to avoid hindering commercial progress. The European Commission&#8217;s approach to regulation has often been criticised for its perceived heavy-handedness, and this latest appeal from industry leaders adds weight to growing concerns about the region&#8217;s global competitiveness in the AI sector.</p>



<p>The pressure is rapidly mounting on European policymakers to <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/">create a regulatory environment</a> that fosters innovation while maintaining <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-signs-ai-safety-treaty-to-protect-human-rights-and-democracy/">appropriate safeguards</a>. The coming months will likely see intensified dialogue between industry stakeholders and regulators as they grapple with these complex issues that will shape the future of AI development in Europe.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@stereophototyp?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Sara Kurfeß</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/solarwinds-it-professionals-stronger-ai-regulation/"><strong>SolarWinds: IT professionals want stronger AI regulation</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/">Tech industry giants urge EU to streamline AI regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Balancing innovation and trust: Experts assess the EU&#8217;s AI Act</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 15:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As the EU&#8217;s AI Act prepares to come into force tomorrow, industry experts are weighing in on its potential impact, highlighting its role in building trust and encouraging responsible AI adoption. Curtis Wilson, Staff Data Engineer at Synopsys’ Software Integrity Group, believes the new regulation could be a crucial step in addressing the AI industry&#8217;s<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/" title="ReadBalancing innovation and trust: Experts assess the EU&#8217;s AI Act">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/">Balancing innovation and trust: Experts assess the EU&#8217;s AI Act</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As the EU&#8217;s AI Act prepares to come into force tomorrow, industry experts are weighing in on its potential impact, highlighting its role in building trust and encouraging responsible AI adoption.</p>



<p>Curtis Wilson, Staff Data Engineer at Synopsys’ <a href="https://www.synopsys.com/software-integrity/all-products-services.html">Software Integrity Group</a>, believes the new regulation could be a crucial step in addressing the AI industry&#8217;s most pressing challenge: building trust.</p>



<p>&#8220;The greatest problem facing AI developers is not regulation, but a lack of trust in AI,&#8221; Wilson stated. &#8220;For an AI system to reach its full potential, it needs to be trusted by the people who use it.&#8221;</p>



<p>This sentiment is echoed by Paul Cardno, Global Digital Automation &amp; Innovation Senior Manager at <a href="https://www.3m.co.uk/">3M</a>, who noted, &#8220;With nearly 80% of UK adults now believing AI needs to be heavily regulated, the introduction of the EU&#8217;s AI Act is something that businesses have been long-waiting for.&#8221;</p>



<p>Both experts emphasise the Act&#8217;s potential to foster confidence in AI technologies. Wilson explained that while his company has implemented internal measures to build trust, external regulation is equally important.</p>



<p>&#8220;I see regulatory frameworks like the EU AI Act as an essential component to building trust in AI,&#8221; Wilson said. &#8220;The strict rules and punishing fines will deter careless developers and help customers feel more confident in trusting and using AI systems.&#8221;</p>



<p>Cardno added, &#8220;We know that AI is shaping the future, but companies will only be able to reap the rewards if they have the confidence to rethink existing processes and break away from entrenched structures.&#8221;</p>



<p>The EU AI Act primarily focuses on high-risk systems and foundational models. Wilson noted that many of its requirements align with existing best practices in data science, such as risk management, testing procedures, and comprehensive documentation.</p>



<p>For UK businesses, the impact of the EU AI Act extends beyond those directly selling to EU markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wilson pointed out that certain aspects of the Act may apply to Northern Ireland due to the Windsor Framework. Additionally, the UK government is developing its own AI regulations, with a recent whitepaper emphasising interoperability with EU and US regulations.</p>



<p>&#8220;While the EU Act isn&#8217;t perfect, and needs to be assessed in relation to other global regulations, having a clear framework and guidance on AI from one of the world&#8217;s major economies will help encourage those who remain on the fence to tap into the AI revolution,&#8221; Cardno explained.</p>



<p>While acknowledging that the new regulations may create some friction, particularly around registration and certification, Wilson emphasised that many of the Act&#8217;s obligations are already standard practice for responsible companies. However, he recognised that small companies and startups might face greater challenges.</p>



<p>&#8220;Small companies and start-ups will experience issues more strongly,&#8221; Wilson said. &#8220;The regulation acknowledges this and has included provisions for sandboxes to foster AI innovation for these smaller businesses.&#8221;</p>



<p>However, Wilson notes that these sandboxes will be established at the national level by individual EU member states, potentially limiting access for UK businesses.</p>



<p>As the AI landscape continues to evolve, the EU AI Act represents a significant step towards establishing a framework for responsible AI development and deployment.</p>



<p>&#8220;Having a clear framework and guidance on AI from one of the world&#8217;s major economies will help encourage those who remain on the fence to tap into the AI revolution, ensuring it has a safe, positive ongoing influence for all organisations operating across the EU, which can only be a promising step forwards for the industry,&#8221; concludes Cardno.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@guillaumeperigois?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Guillaume Périgois</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/"><strong>UAE blocks US congressional meetings with G42 amid AI transfer concerns</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/">Balancing innovation and trust: Experts assess the EU&#8217;s AI Act</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/balancing-innovation-trust-experts-assess-eu-ai-act/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta joins Apple in withholding AI models from EU users</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta (Facebook)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Meta has announced it will not be launching its upcoming multimodal AI model in the European Union due to regulatory concerns. This decision from Meta comes on the heels of Apple&#8217;s similar move to exclude the EU from its Apple Intelligence rollout, signalling a growing trend of tech giants hesitating to introduce advanced AI technologies<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users/" title="ReadMeta joins Apple in withholding AI models from EU users">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users/">Meta joins Apple in withholding AI models from EU users</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://about.meta.com/%20meta/">Meta</a> has announced it will not be launching its upcoming multimodal AI model in the European Union due to regulatory concerns.</p>



<p>This decision from Meta comes on the heels of Apple&#8217;s similar move <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/apple-eu-ai-delay-innovation-vs-regulation/">to exclude the EU</a> from its Apple Intelligence rollout, signalling a growing trend of tech giants hesitating to introduce advanced AI technologies in the region.</p>



<p>Meta’s latest multimodal AI model – capable of handling video, audio, images, and text – was set to be released under an open license. However, Meta&#8217;s decision will prevent European companies from utilising this technology, potentially putting them at a disadvantage in the global AI race.</p>



<p>&#8220;We will release a multimodal Llama model over the coming months, but not in the EU due to the unpredictable nature of the European regulatory environment,&#8221; a Meta spokesperson stated.</p>



<p>A text-only version of Meta&#8217;s Llama 3 model is still expected to launch in the EU.</p>



<p>Meta’s announcement comes just days after the EU finalised compliance deadlines for its new <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/">AI Act</a>. Tech companies operating in the EU will have until August 2026 to comply with rules surrounding copyright, transparency, and specific AI applications like predictive policing.</p>



<p>The withholding of these advanced AI models from the EU market creates a challenging situation for companies outside the region. Those hoping to provide products and services utilising these models will be unable to offer them in one of the world&#8217;s largest economic markets.</p>



<p>Meta plans to integrate its multimodal AI models into products like the Meta Ray-Ban smart glasses. The company&#8217;s EU exclusion will extend to future multimodal AI model releases as well.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Meta will *not* release the multimodal versions of its AI products and models in the EU because of an unpredictable regulatory environment. <br>This means that EU users of Ray-Ban Meta won&#39;t be able to use the image understanding features.<br>It also means that the EU industry will not…</p>&mdash; Yann LeCun (@ylecun) <a href="https://twitter.com/ylecun/status/1814308324038381618?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>As more tech giants potentially follow suit, the EU may face challenges in maintaining its position as a leader in technological innovation while balancing concerns about AI&#8217;s societal impacts.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@enginakyurt?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">engin akyurt</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-could-unleash-119-billion-in-uk-productivity/"><strong>AI could unleash £119 billion in UK productivity</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users/">Meta joins Apple in withholding AI models from EU users</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/meta-joins-apple-withholding-ai-models-eu-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft and Apple back away from OpenAI board</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft and Apple have decided against taking up board seats at OpenAI. The decision comes as regulatory bodies intensify their scrutiny of big tech&#8217;s involvement in AI development and deployment. According to a Bloomberg report on July 10, citing an anonymous source familiar with the matter, Microsoft has officially communicated its withdrawal from the OpenAI<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board/" title="ReadMicrosoft and Apple back away from OpenAI board">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board/">Microsoft and Apple back away from OpenAI board</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft and Apple have decided against taking up board seats at OpenAI. The decision comes as regulatory bodies intensify their scrutiny of big tech&#8217;s involvement in AI development and deployment.</p>



<p>According to a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-10/microsoft-quits-openai-board-after-antitrust-scrutiny-grows">Bloomberg</a> report on July 10, citing an anonymous source familiar with the matter, Microsoft has officially communicated its withdrawal from the OpenAI board. This move comes approximately a year after the Redmond-based company made a substantial $13 billion investment in OpenAI in April 2023.</p>



<p>In a memo addressed to OpenAI, Microsoft stated: &#8220;Over the past eight months we have witnessed significant progress from the newly formed board and are confident in the company&#8217;s direction.&#8221; The tech giant added, &#8220;We no longer believe our limited role as an observer is necessary.&#8221;</p>



<p>Contrary to recent reports suggesting that Apple would <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/07/03/apple-secures-observer-seat-openai-board/">secure an observer role</a> on OpenAI&#8217;s board as part of a landmark agreement announced in June, it appears that OpenAI will now have no board observers following Microsoft&#8217;s departure.</p>



<p>Responding to these developments, OpenAI expressed gratitude towards Microsoft, stating, &#8220;We&#8217;re grateful to Microsoft for voicing confidence in the board and the direction of the company, and we look forward to continuing our successful partnership.&#8221;</p>



<p>This retreat from board involvement by major tech players occurs against a backdrop of mounting regulatory pressure. Concerns about the potential impact of big tech on AI development and industry dominance have prompted increased scrutiny from regulatory bodies worldwide.</p>



<p>In June, European Union regulators announced that OpenAI could face an EU antitrust investigation over its partnership with Microsoft. EU competition chief Margrethe Vestager also <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/07/01/eu-probes-microsoft-openai-and-google-samsung-ai-deals/">revealed plans</a> for local regulators to seek additional third-party views and survey firms such as Microsoft, Google, Meta, and ByteDance&#8217;s TikTok regarding their AI partnerships.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">📢 For now, we conclude that <a href="https://twitter.com/Microsoft?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Microsoft</a> has not acquired control of <a href="https://twitter.com/OpenAI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@OpenAI</a> under 🇪🇺 Merger Regulation.<br><br>We will keep monitoring the relationships between all key players in the AI sector, incl. Microsoft &amp; OpenAI.<br><br> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GenAIVirtualWorldsWorkshop?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GenAIVirtualWorldsWorkshop</a></p>&mdash; Margrethe Vestager (@vestager) <a href="https://twitter.com/vestager/status/1806715558978601180?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>The decision by Microsoft and Apple to step back from board positions at OpenAI could be interpreted as a strategic move to mitigate potential regulatory challenges. By maintaining a more arm&#8217;s length relationship with the AI firm, these tech giants may be attempting to avoid accusations of undue influence or control over AI development.</p>



<p>Alex Haffner, a competition partner at <a href="https://www.fladgate.com/">Fladgate</a>, said:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>“It is hard not to conclude that Microsoft’s decision has been heavily influenced by the ongoing competition/antitrust scrutiny of its (and other major tech players) influence over emerging AI players such as Open AI.</em></p>



<p><em>Microsoft scored a ‘win’ in this regard at the end of June when the EU Commission announced it was dropping its merger control probe of Microsoft and Open AI, an investigation originally announced when Open AI re-shaped its board structure at the time of Sam Altman’s on-off departure from the company.</em></p>



<p><em>However, the Commission confirmed it was still looking at the competitive impact of the broader arrangements between the parties and it is clear that regulators are very much focussed on the complex web of interrelationships that big tech has created with AI providers, hence the need for Microsoft and others to carefully consider how they structure these arrangements going forward.”</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>As AI continues to play an increasingly critical role in technological advancement and societal change, the balance between innovation, competition, and regulation remains a complex challenge for both industry players and policymakers.</p>



<p>The coming months will likely see continued scrutiny of AI partnerships and investments, as regulators worldwide grapple with the task of ensuring fair competition and responsible AI development.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@andrewtneel?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Andrew Neel</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/07/04/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/"><strong>Nvidia: World’s most valuable company under French antitrust fire</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board/">Microsoft and Apple back away from OpenAI board</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-apple-back-away-openai-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nvidia: World&#8217;s most valuable company under French antitrust fire</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 09:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[france]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia recently overtook Microsoft as the world&#8217;s most valuable company and is now in the crosshairs of French antitrust regulators. The French authority is preparing to charge Nvidia with anti-competitive practices as part of the EU&#8217;s commitment to maintaining checks and balances within the industry.  This development underscores the EU&#8217;s resolve to ensure fair competition<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/" title="ReadNvidia: World&#8217;s most valuable company under French antitrust fire">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/">Nvidia: World&#8217;s most valuable company under French antitrust fire</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Nvidia recently overtook Microsoft as the world&#8217;s most valuable company and is now in the crosshairs of French antitrust regulators. The French authority is preparing to charge Nvidia with anti-competitive practices as part of the EU&#8217;s commitment to maintaining checks and balances within the industry. </p>



<p>This development underscores the EU&#8217;s resolve to ensure fair competition and prevent market dominance from stifling innovation and consumer choice. Let&#8217;s recall Nvidia&#8217;s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/21/broadcom-ai-surge-challenges-nvidia-dominance/">meteoric rise</a> to the pinnacle of the tech industry. Founded in 1993, the US-based giant has grown from a graphics chip manufacturer to a leader in AI, data centres, and autonomous vehicles. Its products power some of the most advanced computing systems in the world, and its influence extends across multiple industries.</p>



<p>Nvidia&#8217;s graphics processing units (GPUs) are essential for <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/17/nvidia-presents-latest-advancements-visual-ai/">AI and machine learning applications</a>, driving the next wave of technological advancement. This strategic positioning has catapulted Nvidia&#8217;s market valuation, surpassing tech giants like Apple and Microsoft.</p>



<p>However, with great power comes great responsibility—and scrutiny. According to recent&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/french-antitrust-regulators-preparing-nvidia-charges-sources-say-2024-07-01/" rel="noreferrer noopener">reports</a>, French antitrust regulators are poised to charge Nvidia with anti-competitive practices. The investigation centres on allegations that Nvidia has leveraged its dominant market position to stifle competition and maintain its supremacy in the tech industry.</p>



<p>The French authorities&#8217; move is part of a broader trend of increasing regulatory scrutiny of tech giants worldwide. Governments and regulatory bodies are increasingly wary of companies like Nvidia&#8217;s outsized influence and market power. In Europe, where antitrust laws are particularly stringent, regulators are keen to ensure a level playing field and protect consumer interests.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Potential Implications</strong></h3>



<p>If the charges are upheld, Nvidia could face substantial fines and be forced to alter its business practices. Though potentially significant, the financial penalties might not be the most critical aspect of the investigation. The operational changes imposed on Nvidia could be more consequential, impacting its competitive edge and market strategy.</p>



<p>In short, the stakes are high for Nvidia. The company&#8217;s leadership in AI and other cutting-edge technologies relies on its ability to innovate and dominate the market. Regulatory constraints could slow its momentum and allow competitors to catch up. Moreover, the scrutiny could extend beyond France, prompting investigations in other jurisdictions and creating a ripple effect across the global tech industry.</p>



<p>Nvidia&#8217;s situation is not unique. Tech giants worldwide are facing similar challenges as regulators grapple with the complexities of the digital economy. In recent years, companies like Google, Amazon, and Facebook have also been targets of antitrust investigations and regulatory actions.</p>



<p>It points to a widening consensus on balancing innovation with fair competition. While tech companies drive economic growth and technological progress, their market dominance can threaten competition and consumer choice. Regulators are tasked with finding this balance, ensuring that the benefits of technological advancement are widely shared without stifling innovation.</p>



<p>To recall, in September 2023, French antitrust authorities raided unnamed companies believed to be indulging in anti-competitive practices related to graphics card products. While they did not name the company or identify it as Nvidia, the chipmaker has since confirmed that it is targeted by French courts, among other companies, regarding its business practices.</p>



<p>Nvidia said in a February filing that officials in the US, European Union, China, and the UK are also scrutinizing its operations. &#8220;Our position in markets relating to AI has led to increased interest in our business from regulators worldwide,&#8221; the chipmaker said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, according to a&nbsp;<em>Bloomberg</em>&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-01/french-antitrust-regulators-set-to-charge-nvidia-reuters-says?srnd=technology-vp&amp;sref=QqWIvTvt" rel="noreferrer noopener">report</a>, French antitrust authorities have already been conducting interviews with market participants regarding Nvidia&#8217;s key role in production price control due to an acute lack of chips and how it affects prices. &#8220;The office raid was designed to gather additional knowledge regarding possible anti-competitive practices.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is next for Nvidia and the French regulators?</strong></h3>



<p>It is more likely than not for Nvidia to mount a robust defence because the AI chip giant has consistently argued that its business practices are competitive and that its innovations benefit consumers and industries alike. Nvidia will likely emphasize its contributions to technological progress and economic growth, positioning itself as a driver of positive change rather than a monopolistic force.</p>



<p>However, public perception and regulatory interpretations can differ. Thus, the challenge for Nvidia is clear: to continue its trajectory of success while addressing the concerns of regulators and stakeholders. Ultimately, Nvidia&#8217;s response to this regulatory challenge could define its legacy as the world&#8217;s most valuable company, demonstrating whether it can uphold its leadership position while adapting to the evolving demands of a fair and competitive market.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/03/19/nvidia-unveils-blackwell-architecture-power-next-genai-wave/"><strong>NVIDIA unveils Blackwell architecture to power next GenAI wave&nbsp;</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/">Nvidia: World&#8217;s most valuable company under French antitrust fire</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-worlds-most-valuable-company-under-french-antitrust-fire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU launches office to implement AI Act and foster innovation</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 12:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=14903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The European Union has launched a new office dedicated to overseeing the implementation of its landmark AI Act, which is regarded as one of the most comprehensive AI regulations in the world. This new initiative adopts a risk-based approach, imposing stringent regulations on higher-risk AI applications to ensure their safe and ethical deployment. The primary<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/" title="ReadEU launches office to implement AI Act and foster innovation">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/">EU launches office to implement AI Act and foster innovation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The European Union has launched a new office dedicated to overseeing the implementation of its landmark <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/03/13/eu-approves-controversial-ai-act-mixed-reactions/">AI Act</a>, which is regarded as one of the most comprehensive AI regulations in the world. This new initiative adopts a risk-based approach, imposing stringent regulations on higher-risk AI applications to ensure their safe and ethical deployment.</p>



<p>The primary goal of this office is to promote the &#8220;future development, deployment and use&#8221; of AI technologies, aiming to harness their societal and economic benefits while mitigating associated risks. By focusing on innovation and safety, the office seeks to position the EU as a global leader in AI regulation and development.</p>



<p>According to Margerthe Vertager, the EU competition chief, the new office will play a &#8220;key role&#8221; in implementing the AI Act, particularly with regard to general-purpose AI models. She stated, &#8220;Together with developers and a scientific community, the office will evaluate and test general-purpose AI to ensure that AI serves us as humans and upholds our European values.&#8221;</p>



<p>Sridhar Iyengar, Managing Director for <a href="https://www.zoho.com/">Zoho Europe</a>, welcomed the establishment of the AI office, noting, &#8220;The establishment of the AI office in the European Commission to play a key role with the implementation of the EU AI Act is a welcome sign of progress, and it is encouraging to see the EU positioning itself as a global leader in AI regulation. We hope to continue to see collaboration between governments, businesses, academics and industry experts to guide on safe use of AI to boost business growth.&#8221;</p>



<p>Iyengar highlighted the dual nature of AI&#8217;s impact on businesses, pointing out both its benefits and concerns. He emphasised the importance of adhering to best practice guidance and legislative guardrails to ensure safe and ethical AI adoption.</p>



<p>&#8220;AI can drive innovation in business tools, helping to improve fraud detection, forecasting, and customer data analysis to name a few. These benefits not only have the potential to elevate customer experience but can increase efficiency, present insights, and suggest actions to drive further success,&#8221; Iyengar said.</p>



<p>The office will be staffed by more than 140 individuals, including technology specialists, administrative assistants, lawyers, policy specialists, and economists. It will consist of various units focusing on regulation and compliance, as well as safety and innovation, reflecting the multifaceted approach needed to govern AI effectively.</p>



<p>Rachael Hays, Transformation Director for <a href="https://www.definia.com/">Definia</a>, part of The IN Group, commented: &#8220;The establishment of a dedicated AI Office within the European Commission underscores the EU&#8217;s commitment to both innovation and regulation which is undoubtedly crucial in this rapidly evolving AI landscape.&#8221;</p>



<p>Hays also pointed out the potential for workforce upskilling that this initiative provides. She referenced findings from their Tech and the Boardroom research, which revealed that over half of boardroom leaders view AI as the biggest direct threat to their organisations.</p>



<p>&#8220;This initiative directly addresses these fears as employees across various sectors are given the opportunity to adapt and thrive in an AI-driven world. The AI Office offers promising hope and guidance in developing economic benefits while mitigating risks associated with AI technology, something we should all get on board with,&#8221; she added.</p>



<p>As the EU takes these steps towards comprehensive AI governance, the office’s work will be pivotal in driving forward both innovation and safety in the field.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@stereophototyp?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Sara Kurfeß</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/05/29/elon-musk-xai-secures-6-billion-to-challenge-openai-ai-race/"><strong>Elon Musk’s xAI secures $6B to challenge OpenAI in AI race</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/">EU launches office to implement AI Act and foster innovation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-launches-office-implement-ai-act-foster-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI faces complaint over fictional outputs</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 08:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gdpr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hallucinations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noyb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=14751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>European data protection advocacy group noyb has filed a complaint against OpenAI over the company&#8217;s inability to correct inaccurate information generated by ChatGPT. The group alleges that OpenAI&#8217;s failure to ensure the accuracy of personal data processed by the service violates the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in the European Union. &#8220;Making up false information<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs/" title="ReadOpenAI faces complaint over fictional outputs">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs/">OpenAI faces complaint over fictional outputs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>European data protection advocacy group <a href="https://noyb.eu/en">noyb</a> has filed a complaint against <a href="https://openai.com/">OpenAI</a> over the company&#8217;s inability to correct inaccurate information generated by ChatGPT. The group alleges that OpenAI&#8217;s failure to ensure the accuracy of personal data processed by the service violates the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in the European Union.</p>



<p>&#8220;Making up false information is quite problematic in itself. But when it comes to false information about individuals, there can be serious consequences,&#8221; said Maartje de Graaf, Data Protection Lawyer at noyb.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s clear that companies are currently unable to make chatbots like ChatGPT comply with EU law when processing data about individuals. If a system cannot produce accurate and transparent results, it cannot be used to generate data about individuals. The technology has to follow the legal requirements, not the other way around.&#8221;</p>



<p>The GDPR requires that personal data be accurate, and individuals have the right to rectification if data is inaccurate, as well as the right to access information about the data processed and its sources. However, OpenAI has openly admitted that it cannot correct incorrect information generated by ChatGPT or disclose the sources of the data used to train the model.</p>



<p>&#8220;Factual accuracy in large language models remains an area of active research,&#8221; OpenAI has argued.</p>



<p>The advocacy group highlights a New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/06/technology/chatbots-hallucination-rates.html">report</a> that found chatbots like ChatGPT &#8220;invent information at least 3 percent of the time – and as high as 27 percent.&#8221; In the complaint against OpenAI, noyb cites an example where ChatGPT repeatedly provided an incorrect date of birth for the complainant, a public figure, despite requests for rectification.</p>



<p>&#8220;Despite the fact that the complainant&#8217;s date of birth provided by ChatGPT is incorrect, OpenAI refused his request to rectify or erase the data, arguing that it wasn&#8217;t possible to correct data,&#8221; noyb stated.</p>



<p>OpenAI claimed it could filter or block data on certain prompts, such as the complainant&#8217;s name, but not without preventing ChatGPT from filtering all information about the individual. The company also failed to adequately respond to the complainant&#8217;s access request, which the GDPR requires companies to fulfil.</p>



<p>&#8220;The obligation to comply with access requests applies to all companies. It is clearly possible to keep records of training data that was used to at least have an idea about the sources of information,&#8221; said de Graaf. &#8220;It seems that with each &#8216;innovation,&#8217; another group of companies thinks that its products don&#8217;t have to comply with the law.&#8221;</p>



<p>European privacy watchdogs have already scrutinised ChatGPT&#8217;s inaccuracies, with the Italian Data Protection Authority imposing <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2023/04/13/italy-lift-chatgpt-ban-openai-fixes-privacy-issues/">a temporary restriction</a> on OpenAI&#8217;s data processing in March 2023 and the European Data Protection Board establishing a task force on ChatGPT.</p>



<p>In its complaint, noyb is asking the Austrian Data Protection Authority to investigate OpenAI&#8217;s data processing and measures to ensure the accuracy of personal data processed by its large language models. The advocacy group also requests that the authority order OpenAI to comply with the complainant&#8217;s access request, bring its processing in line with the GDPR, and impose a fine to ensure future compliance.</p>



<p><em>You can read the full complaint </em><a href="https://noyb.eu/sites/default/files/2024-04/OpenAI%20Complaint_EN_redacted.pdf"><em>here</em></a><em> (PDF)</em></p>



<p>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@eleonoirewho?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Eleonora Francesca Grotto</a>)</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/04/25/igor-jablokov-pryon-building-responsible-ai-future/"><strong>Igor Jablokov, Pryon: Building a responsible AI future</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs/">OpenAI faces complaint over fictional outputs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-faces-complaint-over-fictional-outputs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
