<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>China Archives - AI News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tag/china/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tag/china/</link>
	<description>Artificial Intelligence News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/ai-icon-60x60.png</url>
	<title>China Archives - AI News</title>
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tag/china/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Governments are scrambling to establish regulations to govern AI, citing numerous concerns over data privacy, bias, safety, and more. AI News caught up with Nerijus Šveistys, Senior Legal Counsel at Oxylabs, to understand the state of play when it comes to AI regulation and its potential implications for industries, businesses, and innovation. “The boom of<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/" title="ReadAI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/">AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Governments are scrambling to establish regulations to govern AI, citing numerous concerns over data privacy, bias, safety, and more.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="800" height="800" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-16743" style="width:174px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs.jpeg 800w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-768x768.jpeg 768w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-125x125.jpeg 125w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-200x200.jpeg 200w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-285x285.jpeg 285w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-250x250.jpeg 250w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-100x100.jpeg 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-60x60.jpeg 60w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-400x400.jpeg 400w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-600x600.jpeg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<p>AI News caught up with Nerijus Šveistys, Senior Legal Counsel at <a href="https://oxylabs.io/">Oxylabs</a>, to understand the state of play when it comes to AI regulation and its potential implications for industries, businesses, and innovation.</p>



<p>“The boom of the last few years appears to have sparked a push to establish regulatory frameworks for AI governance,” explains Šveistys.</p>



<p>“This is a natural development, as the rise of AI seems to pose issues in data privacy and protection, bias and discrimination, safety, intellectual property, and other legal areas, as well as ethics that need to be addressed.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Regions diverge in regulatory strategy</h3>



<p>The European Union’s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/">AI Act</a> has, unsurprisingly, positioned the region with a strict, centralised approach. The regulation, which came into force this year, is set to be fully effective by 2026.</p>



<p>Šveistys pointed out that the EU has acted relatively swiftly compared to other jurisdictions: “The main difference we can see is the comparative quickness with which the EU has released a uniform regulation to govern the use of all types of AI.”</p>



<p>Meanwhile, other regions have opted for more piecemeal approaches. China, for instance, has been implementing regulations specific to certain AI technologies in a phased-out manner. According to Šveistys, China began regulating AI models as early as 2021.</p>



<p>“In 2021, they introduced regulation on recommendation algorithms, which [had] increased their capabilities in digital advertising. It was followed by regulations <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinas-deepfake-laws-come-into-effect-today/">on deep synthesis models</a> or, in common terms, deepfakes and content generation in 2022,” he said.</p>



<p>“Then, in 2023, regulation on generative AI models was introduced as these models were making a splash in commercial usage.”</p>



<p>The US, in contrast, remains relatively uncoordinated in its approach. Federal-level regulations are yet to be enacted, with efforts mostly emerging at the state level.</p>



<p>“There are proposed regulations at the state level, such as the so-called California AI Act, but even if they come into power, it may still take some time before they do,” Šveistys noted.</p>



<p>This delay in implementing unified AI regulations in the US has raised questions about the extent to which business pushback may be contributing to the slow rollout. Šveistys said that while lobbyist pressure is a known factor, it’s not the only potential reason.</p>



<p>“There was <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/">pushback to the EU AI Act</a>, too, which was nevertheless introduced. Thus, it is not clear whether the delay in the US is only due to lobbyism or other obstacles in the legislation enactment process,” explains Šveistys.</p>



<p>“It might also be because some still see AI as a futuristic concern, not fully appreciating the extent to which it is already a legal issue of today.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Balancing innovation and safety</h3>



<p>Differentiated regulatory approaches could affect the pace of innovation and business competitiveness across regions.</p>



<p>Europe’s regulatory framework, though more stringent, aims to ensure consumer protection and ethical adherence—something that less-regulated environments may lack.</p>



<p>“More rigid regulatory frameworks may impose compliance costs for businesses in the AI field and stifle competitiveness and innovation. On the other hand, they bring the benefits of protecting consumers and adhering to certain ethical norms,” comments Šveistys.</p>



<p>This trade-off is especially pronounced in AI-related sectors such as targeted advertising, where algorithmic bias is increasingly scrutinised.</p>



<p>AI governance often extends beyond laws that specifically target AI, incorporating related legal areas like those governing data collection and privacy. For example, the EU AI Act also regulates the use of AI in physical devices, such as elevators.</p>



<p>&#8220;Additionally, all businesses that collect data for advertisement are potentially affected as AI regulation can also cover algorithmic bias in targeted advertising,&#8221; emphasises Šveistys.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Impact on related industries</h3>



<p>One industry that is deeply intertwined with AI developments is web scraping. Typically used for collecting publicly available data, web scraping is undergoing an AI-driven evolution.</p>



<p>&#8220;From data collection, validation, analysis, or overcoming anti-scraping measures, there is a lot of potential for AI to massively improve the efficiency, accuracy, and adaptability of web scraping operations,&#8221; said Šveistys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, as AI regulation and related laws tighten, web scraping companies will face greater scrutiny.</p>



<p>“AI regulations may also bring the spotlight on certain areas of law that were always very relevant to the web scraping industry, such as privacy or copyright laws,” Šveistys added.</p>



<p>“At the end of the day, scraping content protected by such laws without proper authorisation could always lead to legal issues, and now so can using AI this way.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Copyright battles and legal precedents</h3>



<p>The implications of AI regulation are also playing out on a broader legal stage, particularly in cases involving generative AI tools.</p>



<p>High-profile <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-microsoft-lawsuit-github-copilot/">lawsuits</a> have been launched against AI giants like OpenAI and its primary backer, Microsoft, by authors, artists, and musicians who claim their copyrighted materials were used to train AI systems without proper permission.</p>



<p>“These cases are pivotal in determining the legal boundaries of using copyrighted material for AI development and establishing legal precedents for protecting intellectual property in the digital age,” said Šveistys.</p>



<p>While these lawsuits could take years to resolve, their outcomes may fundamentally shape the future of AI development. So, what can businesses do now as the regulatory and legal landscape continues to evolve?</p>



<p>“Speaking about the specific cases of using copyrighted material for AI training, businesses should approach this the same way as any web-scraping activity – that is, evaluate the specific data they wish to collect with the help of a legal expert in the field,” recommends Šveistys.</p>



<p>“It is important to recognise that the AI legal landscape is very new and rapidly evolving, with not many precedents in place to refer to as of yet. Hence, continuous monitoring and adaptation of your AI usage are crucial.”</p>



<p>Just this week, the UK Government made headlines with its announcement of a consultation on the use of copyrighted material for training AI models. Under the proposals, tech firms could be permitted to use copyrighted material unless owners have specifically opted out.</p>



<p>Despite the diversity of approaches globally, the AI regulatory push marks a significant moment for technological governance. Whether through the EU’s comprehensive model, China’s step-by-step strategy, or narrower, state-level initiatives like in the US, businesses worldwide must navigate a complex, evolving framework.</p>



<p>The challenge ahead will be striking the right balance between fostering innovation and mitigating risks, ensuring that AI remains a force for good while avoiding potential harms.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nathangbingle?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nathan Bingle</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-urges-ai-regulation-avoid-catastrophes/"><strong>Anthropic urges AI regulation to avoid catastrophes</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:844px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/">AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why QwQ-32B-Preview is the reasoning AI to watch</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 09:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s a new contender in the AI space that’s making waves: QwQ-32B-Preview. This so-called “reasoning” AI model is being compared to OpenAI o1, and it’s one of the few you can download under a permissive license. For developers and researchers eager to experiment, that’s a significant bonus. Built by Alibaba’s Qwen team, QwQ-32B-Preview is anything<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/" title="ReadWhy QwQ-32B-Preview is the reasoning AI to watch">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/">Why QwQ-32B-Preview is the reasoning AI to watch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There’s a new contender in the AI space that’s making waves: QwQ-32B-Preview. </p>



<p>This so-called “reasoning” AI model is being compared to OpenAI o1, and it’s one of the few you can download under a permissive license. For developers and researchers eager to experiment, that’s a significant bonus.</p>



<p>Built by Alibaba’s Qwen team, QwQ-32B-Preview is anything but lightweight. It packs 32.5 billion parameters—think of these as the building blocks of its problem-solving abilities—and can handle prompts of up to 32,000 words; longer than some novels! Tests show it outperforms OpenAI o1-preview and o1-mini on benchmarks like AIME and MATH. For context, AIME uses other AI models to assess performance, while MATH is a collection of  word problems.</p>



<p>But the model isn’t just about maths problems or logic puzzles. What sets it apart is how it approaches tasks. QwQ-32B-Preview plans ahead, fact-checks its work, and avoids common AI mistakes. Of course, it’s not flawless—Alibaba acknowledges issues like language switching, occasional loops, and difficulties with “common sense” reasoning. Even so, it represents a step toward more intelligent AI systems.</p>



<p>QwQ-32B-Preview is accessible: You can run or download it via Hugging Face. However, like other Chinese-developed AI, it operates within regulatory boundaries. That means it carefully avoids politically sensitive topics to comply with China’s rules, ensuring it aligns with “core socialist values.”</p>



<p>Alibaba isn’t alone in this space. Meta’s Llama 3.1 is another open-source option, though it takes a different approach by focusing on generative AI rather than reasoning. While both models are innovative, QwQ-32B-Preview specialises in problem-solving with what the company describes as a human-like approach, putting it in the reasoning category.</p>



<p>The competition in AI inside China is intensifying. Companies such as DeepSeek, Shanghai AI Lab, and Kunlun Tech have entered the reasoning AI race, releasing their models at pace. For example, DeepSeek’s r1 claims to outperform OpenAI’s o1 on half of its benchmark tests, particularly in maths and programming. Shanghai AI Lab’s InternThinker takes a structured approach to problem-solving, incorporating steps such as understanding queries, recalling knowledge, planning solutions, and reflecting on its answers.</p>



<p>This surge of activity highlights how quickly Chinese companies are catching up with US tech giants. Xu Liang, an AI entrepreneur from Hangzhou, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3289022/chinese-ai-firms-rush-out-costly-reasoning-models-take-openais-o1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">summed it up</a>: “OpenAI gave the direction; with research, Chinese tech firms are making progress.” The release of QwQ-32B-Preview and its competitors shows how much ground they’re covering.</p>



<p>But this goes beyond just catching up. Reasoning AI marks a change in how models are designed and used. Unlike older AI systems that relied on brute force to generate answers, reasoning models like QwQ-32B-Preview aim to mimic human problem-solving. The approach not only makes them more effective for complex tasks but also expands their potential use cases, like tackling advanced maths or providing detailed financial advice.</p>



<p>Whether it’s solving puzzles, reasoning through intricate problems, or expanding what open-source AI can achieve, one thing is clear: the evolution of AI is accelerating. Buckle up—this is only the beginning.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-group-of-people-riding-scooters-in-front-of-a-tall-building-GoJ5By4jCfI?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alibaba Cloud overhauls AI partner initiative</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:969px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a target="_blank" href="https://www.ai-expo.net/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a target="_blank" href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlockX</a>,<a target="_blank" href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a target="_blank" href="https://techforge.pub/events/" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/">Why QwQ-32B-Preview is the reasoning AI to watch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chinese organisations are utilising cloud services from Amazon and its competitors to gain access to advanced US AI chips and capabilities that they cannot otherwise obtain, according to a Reuters report based on public tender documents. In a comprehensive investigation, Reuters revealed how Chinese cloud access to US AI chips is facilitated through intermediaries. Over<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/" title="ReadChinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Chinese organisations are utilising cloud services from Amazon and its competitors to gain access to advanced US AI chips and capabilities that they cannot otherwise obtain, according to a Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinese-entities-turn-amazon-cloud-its-rivals-access-high-end-us-chips-ai-2024-08-23/">report</a> based on public tender documents.</p>



<p>In a comprehensive investigation, Reuters revealed how Chinese cloud access to US AI chips is facilitated through intermediaries. Over 50 tender documents posted in the past year revealed that at least 11 Chinese entities have sought access to restricted US technologies or cloud services. Four of these explicitly named Amazon Web Services (AWS) as a cloud service provider, though accessed through Chinese intermediaries rather than directly from AWS.</p>



<p>&#8220;AWS complies with all applicable US laws, including trade laws, regarding the provision of AWS services inside and outside of China,&#8221; an AWS spokesperson told Reuters.</p>



<p>The report highlights that while the US government has restricted the export of high-end AI chips to China, providing access to such chips or advanced AI models through the cloud is not a violation of US regulations. This loophole has raised concerns among US officials and lawmakers.</p>



<p>One example cited in the report involves Shenzhen University, which spent 200,000 yuan (£21,925) on an AWS account to access cloud servers powered by Nvidia A100 and H100 chips for an unspecified project. The university obtained this service via an intermediary, Yunda Technology Ltd Co. Neither Shenzhen University nor Yunda Technology responded to Reuters&#8217; requests for comment.</p>



<p>The investigation also revealed that Zhejiang Lab, a research institute developing its own large language model called GeoGPT, stated in a tender document that it intended to spend 184,000 yuan to purchase AWS cloud computing services. The institute claimed that its AI model could not get enough computing power from homegrown Alibaba cloud services.</p>



<p>Michael McCaul, chair of the US House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Committee, told <em>Reuters</em>: &#8220;This loophole has been a concern of mine for years, and we are long overdue to address it.&#8221;</p>



<p>In response to these concerns, the US Commerce Department is tightening rules. A government spokeswoman told Reuters that they are &#8220;seeking additional resources to strengthen our existing controls that restrict PRC companies from accessing advanced AI chips through remote access to cloud computing capability.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Commerce Department has also proposed a rule that would require US cloud computing firms to verify large AI model users and notify authorities when they use US cloud computing services to train large AI models capable of &#8220;malicious cyber-enabled activity.&#8221;</p>



<p>The study also found that Chinese companies are seeking access to Microsoft&#8217;s cloud services. For example, Sichuan University stated in a tender filing that it was developing a generative AI platform and would purchase 40 million Microsoft Azure OpenAI tokens to help with project delivery.</p>



<p>Reuters’ report also indicated that Amazon has provided Chinese businesses with access to modern AI chips as well as advanced AI models such as Anthropic&#8217;s Claude, which they would not otherwise have had. This was demonstrated by public postings, tenders, and marketing materials evaluated by the news organisation.</p>



<p>Chu Ruisong, President of AWS Greater China, stated during a generative AI-themed conference in Shanghai in May that &#8220;Bedrock provides a selection of leading LLMs, including prominent closed-source models such as Anthropic&#8217;s Claude 3.&#8221;</p>



<p>The report overall emphasises the difficulty of regulating access to advanced computing resources in an increasingly interconnected global technological ecosystem. It focuses on the intricate relationship between US export laws, cloud service providers, and Chinese enterprises looking to improve their AI capabilities.</p>



<p>As the US government works to close this gap, the scenario raises concerns about the efficacy of present export controls and the potential need for more comprehensive laws that cover cloud-based access to banned technologies.</p>



<p>The findings of this paper are likely to feed ongoing discussions about technology transfer, national security, and the global AI race. As politicians and industry leaders analyse these findings, they may spark fresh discussions about how to balance technological cooperation with national security concerns in an era of rapid AI growth.</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/globaldata-china-is-ahead-of-global-rivals-for-ai-unicorns/">GlobalData: China is ahead of global rivals for AI ‘unicorns’</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/">Chinese firms use cloud loophole to access US AI tech</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinese-firms-cloud-loophole-access-us-ai-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UAE blocks US congressional meetings with G42 amid AI transfer concerns</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zulhusni]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 11:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uae]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There have been reports that the United Arab Emirates (UAE) has &#8220;suddenly cancelled&#8221; the ongoing series of meetings between a group of US congressional staffers and Emirati AI firm G42, after some US lawmakers raised concerns that this practice may lead to the transfer of advanced American AI technology to China. However, a congressional spokesperson,<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/" title="ReadUAE blocks US congressional meetings with G42 amid AI transfer concerns">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/">UAE blocks US congressional meetings with G42 amid AI transfer concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There have been reports that the United Arab Emirates (UAE) has &#8220;suddenly cancelled&#8221; the ongoing series of meetings between a group of US congressional staffers and Emirati AI firm <a href="https://www.g42.ai/">G42</a>, after some US lawmakers raised concerns that this practice may lead to the transfer of advanced American AI technology to China.</p>



<p>However, a congressional spokesperson, who provided this information, chose to remain anonymous due to internal committee policy, as reported by <em><a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/uae-blocks-meetings-between-ai-firm-g42-us-congressional-staffers-spokesperson-2024-07-29/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reuters</a></em>.</p>



<p>The order was given directly by the UAE&#8217;s ambassador to the US, who halted the meetings between staffers from the House Select Committee on China and G42, as well as various Emirati government officials. This development only adds fuel to the fire of high tensions surrounding the scrutiny of G42 amid a $1.5 billion agreement with Microsoft. Some US congresspeople are already worried about sensitive technology getting into the hands of a UAE firm that reportedly has Chinese ties.</p>



<p>The committee&#8217;s spokesperson expressed increased concerns regarding the G42-Microsoft deal due to the UAE&#8217;s unwillingness to engage in talks. &#8220;Expect Congress to become more involved in overseeing these negotiations,&#8221; the spokesperson said.</p>



<p>The cancelled meetings may signal a diplomatic crisis due to the increased attention of China hawks in Congress. The efforts of these lawmakers to closely scrutinise the G42-Microsoft deal have particularly sparked controversies. Members of Congress are focused on ensuring that sensitive AI developments and products resulting from the agreement will not be diverted by the Emiratis to China.</p>



<p>The State Department gave no comment, whereas G42 directed the media to the Emirati government. The UAE embassy spokesperson announced that the situation resulted from a &#8220;miscommunication,&#8221; as they were notified of the staff delegation just the day before their planned arrival. The embassy emphasised its regular engagement with committee members and staffers in recent months, asserting that the committee has been kept informed about joint UAE-US efforts to strengthen control over critical advanced technologies.</p>



<p>The congressional staffers had planned these meetings as part of a regional visit from July 16-19. Their agenda included discussions on the transfer of sophisticated chips from companies like Nvidia to the UAE and Saudi Arabia, as well as US-China tech competition.</p>



<p>Ambassador Yousef Al Otaiba cited a July 11 letter from committee chairman John Moolenaar to US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan as the reason for the cancellations. This letter, co-signed by House Foreign Affairs chair Michael McCaul, requested a White House intelligence briefing on Microsoft&#8217;s investment in G42 before the deal could progress to its second phase, which would involve transferring export-restricted semiconductor chips from Nvidia and sophisticated AI model weights.</p>



<p>The Biden administration has taken a positive view of the G42-Microsoft deal, stating that G42&#8217;s severance from China&#8217;s Huawei has been a major positive factor for the deal. However, last year, the administration also imposed sweeping curbs on AI chip exports, requiring licenses for shipments under a more restrictive policy than the previous Trump administration. Additionally, the policy of restricting exports to China requires licenses for exports to the UAE and some other Middle Eastern countries.</p>



<p>It is noted that a regional visit by a congressional delegation took place, during which they met with Saudi officials who expressed a desire to alleviate US companies&#8217; concerns about the activities of the Chinese government in Saudi Arabia. Their goal was to obtain permission to import advanced American chips.</p>



<p>The level of interaction between US and other countries&#8217; authorities illustrates the link between technological innovation, international political relationships, and national security issues.</p>



<p><strong>See also: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-unveils-new-ai-model-to-rival-big-tech-giants/">UAE unveils new AI model to rival big tech giants</a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/">UAE blocks US congressional meetings with G42 amid AI transfer concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uae-blocks-us-congressional-meetings-g42-ai-transfer-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SenseTime SenseNova 5.5: China&#8217;s first real-time multimodal AI model</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benchmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multimodal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensenova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensetime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SenseTime has unveiled SenseNova 5.5, an enhanced version of its LLM that includes SenseNova 5o—touted as China&#8217;s first real-time multimodal model. SenseNova 5o represents a leap forward in AI interaction, providing capabilities on par with GPT-4o&#8217;s streaming interaction features. This advancement allows users to engage with the model in a manner akin to conversing with<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model/" title="ReadSenseTime SenseNova 5.5: China&#8217;s first real-time multimodal AI model">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model/">SenseTime SenseNova 5.5: China&#8217;s first real-time multimodal AI model</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.sensetime.com/en">SenseTime</a> has unveiled SenseNova 5.5, an enhanced version of its LLM that includes SenseNova 5o—touted as China&#8217;s first real-time multimodal model.</p>



<p>SenseNova 5o represents a leap forward in AI interaction, providing capabilities on par with GPT-4o&#8217;s streaming interaction features. This advancement allows users to engage with the model in a manner akin to conversing with a real person, making it particularly suitable for real-time conversation and speech recognition applications.</p>



<p>According to SenseTime, its latest model outperforms rivals across several benchmarks:</p>



<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">At the World Artificial Intelligence Conference (WAIC) in Shanghai this weekend, SenseTime unveiled SenseNova 5.5.<br><br>The company claims the model outperforms GPT-4o in 5 out of 8 key metrics.<br><br>While I&#39;d take it with a grain of salt, China&#39;s AI startups are showing major progress <a href="https://t.co/1ZFbojHs3v">pic.twitter.com/1ZFbojHs3v</a></p>&mdash; Rowan Cheung (@rowancheung) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowancheung/status/1810183314466037966?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>



<p>Dr. Xu Li, Chairman of the Board and CEO of SenseTime, commented: &#8220;This is a critical year for large models as they evolve from unimodal to multimodal. In line with users&#8217; needs, SenseTime is also focused on boosting interactivity.</p>



<p>“With applications driving the development of models and their capabilities, coupled with technological advancements in multimodal streaming interactions, we will witness unprecedented transformations in human-AI interactions.&#8221;</p>



<p>The upgraded SenseNova 5.5 boasts a 30% improvement in overall performance compared to its predecessor, SenseNova 5.0, which was released just two months earlier. Notable enhancements include improved mathematical reasoning, English proficiency, and command-following abilities.</p>



<p>In a move to democratise access to advanced AI capabilities, SenseTime has introduced a cost-effective edge-side large model. This development reduces the cost per device to as low as RMB 9.90 ($1.36) per year, potentially accelerating widespread adoption across various IoT devices.</p>



<p>The company has also launched &#8220;Project $0 Go,&#8221; a free onboarding package for enterprise users migrating from the OpenAI platform. This initiative includes a 50 million tokens package and API migration consulting services, aimed at lowering entry barriers for businesses looking to leverage SenseNova&#8217;s capabilities.</p>



<p>SenseTime&#8217;s commitment to edge-side AI is evident in the release of SenseChat Lite-5.5, which features a 40% reduction in inference time compared to its predecessor, now at just 0.19 seconds. The inference speed has also increased by 15%, reaching 90.2 words per second.</p>



<p>Expanding its suite of AI applications, SenseTime introduced Vimi, a controllable AI avatar video generator. This tool can create short video clips with precise control over facial expressions and upper body movements from a single photo, opening up new possibilities in entertainment and interactive applications.</p>



<p>The company has also upgraded its SenseTime Raccoon Series, a set of AI-native productivity tools. The Code Raccoon now boasts a five-fold improvement in response speed and a 10% increase in coding precision, while the Office Raccoon has expanded to include a consumer-facing webpage and a WeChat mini-app version.</p>



<p>SenseTime&#8217;s large model technology is already making waves across various industries. In the financial sector, it&#8217;s improving efficiency in compliance, marketing, and investment research. In agriculture, it&#8217;s helping to reduce the use of materials by 20% while increasing crop yields by 15%. The cultural tourism industry is seeing significant boosts in travel planning and booking efficiency.</p>



<p>With over 3,000 government and corporate customers already using SenseNova across technology, healthcare, finance, and programming sectors, SenseTime is cementing its position as a key AI player.</p>



<p><em>(Image Credit: <a href="https://www.sensetime.com/en">SenseTime</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/07/09/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/"><strong>AI revolution in US education: How Chinese apps are leading the way</strong></a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model/">SenseTime SenseNova 5.5: China&#8217;s first real-time multimodal AI model</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/sensetime-sensenova-china-real-time-multimodal-ai-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI revolution in US education: How Chinese apps are leading the way</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 13:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Assistants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The success of Chinese AI education applications like Question.AI and Gauth in the US market comes at a time of fierce competition within China, where over 200 large language models—critical for generative AI services like ChatGPT—have been developed. As of March, more than half of these received approval from Chinese authorities for public release. Faced<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/" title="ReadAI revolution in US education: How Chinese apps are leading the way">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/">AI revolution in US education: How Chinese apps are leading the way</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The success of Chinese AI education applications like Question.AI and Gauth in the US market comes at a time of fierce competition within China, where over 200 large language models—critical for generative AI services like ChatGPT—have been developed. As of March, more than half of these received approval from Chinese authorities for public release.</p>



<p>Faced with a <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2021/10/15/globaldata-china-is-ahead-of-global-rivals-for-ai-unicorns/">saturated domestic market</a>, more Chinese app developers are now setting their sights on Western markets, including the US.</p>



<p>The <em><a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3267561/china-developed-ai-apps-gain-foothold-us-helping-kids-do-their-homework" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">South China Morning Post</a></em> reported that Chinese AI apps have swiftly gained traction in the US, particularly in the education sector. Applications like Question.AI, owned by Beijing-based educational technology startup Zuoyebang and ByteDance&#8217;s Gauth, are revolutionising how American students tackle their homework by providing instant solutions and explanations through advanced AI algorithms. </p>



<p>For context, Question.AI and Gauth are popular educational apps that use generative AI to help US students in various subjects. Users can photograph homework problems to receive solutions with step-by-step explanations. Question.AI launched in mid-2023, while Gauth (originally Gauthmath) started in 2020 as a math solver before expanding. Both offer free essential use with paid additional features. As of recent rankings, Gauth is the second most popular educational app globally, with Question.AI at seventh.</p>



<p>This convenience has resonated with students and parents, offering a seamless blend of technology and education that complements the increasingly digital learning environment. Initially designed for China&#8217;s vast and competitive market, these apps began bringing cutting-edge AI capabilities to American classrooms. After all, with its high digital adoption rates and openness to educational innovation, the US market presents a lucrative opportunity for Chinese developers looking to expand their user base beyond domestic borders.</p>



<p>According to mobile app intelligence service AppMagic, Question.AI and Gauth, generative AI-driven homework helpers, were ranked among the top three free educational apps in the US on Apple&#8217;s iOS store and Google Play from February to May.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">AI in education: Domestic pressure driving global expansion&nbsp;</h3>



<p>In China, the development of large language models has been prolific. With over 200 such models created, the competition among AI developers is intense. This high-stakes environment has driven many companies to seek growth opportunities abroad. The approval of these models for public release by Chinese authorities signifies the maturity and readiness of these technologies for broader application, encouraging developers to explore international markets.</p>



<p>This push for global expansion is not just about finding new revenue streams but also about gaining a competitive edge and establishing a global presence. For Chinese AI companies, breaking into Western markets, particularly the US, symbolises commercial success and technological leadership on a global scale.</p>



<p>The adoption of Chinese AI apps <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2019/11/01/abi-research-usa-reclaims-top-china-ai-investments/">in the US</a> education sector also illustrates some strategic advantages these tools possess. The sophisticated AI technology in Question.AI and Gauth delivers individual-learnt experiences. In the US, educators appreciate such granularity as they are committed to personalised instruction for students with various learning styles.</p>



<p>Moreover, the flexibility and accessibility of these AI tools align well with the digital transformation sweeping through American education. Given that the pandemic has expedited online learning, AI-powered educational apps stand to bridge this gap in traditional teaching methodologies by providing timely help and improving their delivery methods.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Navigating challenges: Data privacy and cultural integration</h3>



<p>Even with their technological prowess, Chinese AI apps will be met by data privacy and security concerns when entering US markets. There will be increased oversight on how these apps manage user data, especially in light of the geopolitical tensions between the US and China. Ensuring compliance with stringent US data privacy regulations is crucial for gaining user trust and widespread acceptance.</p>



<p>Additionally, cultural integration poses another hurdle. Chinese educational philosophies often emphasise rote learning and discipline, which may contrast with American education&#8217;s focus on creativity and critical thinking. Successfully blending these approaches to create a holistic learning experience will be essential to the sustained success of these apps in the US.</p>



<p>Ultimately, the success of Chinese AI apps like Question.AI and Gauth in the US clearly demonstrates the advanced technological capabilities that have been developed through intense domestic competition. As these companies continue to navigate the complexities of entering the Western market, their impact on the future of education is expected to expand.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/28/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/"><strong>Tech war escalates: OpenAI shuts door on China</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/">AI revolution in US education: How Chinese apps are leading the way</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-revolution-us-education-how-chinese-apps-leading-the-way/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech war escalates: OpenAI shuts door on China</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china ai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week, OpenAI has decisively blocked access to its site from mainland China and Hong Kong, cutting off developers and companies from some of the most advanced AI technologies available today. OpenAI&#8217;s move is not surprising given the increasing geopolitical tensions and technology rivalry; however, it represents an inflection point in AI that will further<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/" title="ReadTech war escalates: OpenAI shuts door on China">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/">Tech war escalates: OpenAI shuts door on China</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This week, OpenAI has decisively blocked access to <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/12/musk-ends-openai-lawsuit-slamming-apple-chatgpt-plans/">its site</a> from mainland China and Hong Kong, cutting off developers and companies from some of the most advanced AI technologies available today.</p>



<p>OpenAI&#8217;s move is not surprising given the increasing geopolitical tensions and technology rivalry; however, it represents an inflection point in AI that will further turn up the heat on rather icy tech cold war. The result is massive repercussions on the future AI landscape in China and worldwide and will lay much groundwork for fierce competition among AI superpowers in the future.</p>



<p>In the face of increased governmental demands and rivalry for AI dominance, OpenAI&#8217;s choice protects the company&#8217;s intellectual property while navigating geopolitical difficulties. The move underscores the deepening digital divide between China and Western countries, which remains one of the defining elements in this tech war era. However, as OpenAI cuts ties with China, it also marks a bigger tech decoupling trend in which the US and Chinese tech ecosystems are pulling apart further, according to some experts.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Implications for Chinese AI players</strong></h3>



<p>OpenAI&#8217;s blockade presents both challenges and opportunities for Chinese AI companies. On one hand, the absence of OpenAI&#8217;s advanced models, such as GPT-4, from the Chinese market could slow the adoption and integration of cutting-edge AI technologies. This is particularly relevant for startups and smaller companies that lack the resources to develop similar models independently.</p>



<p>&#8220;OpenAI&#8217;s move, which is set to go into effect on July 9, could affect Chinese companies developing their services based on OpenAI&#8217;s large language models (LLMs),&#8221; a&nbsp;<em><a target="_blank" href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3267971/tech-war-openai-further-block-access-mainland-china-hong-kong-based-developers?module=Big%20Tech&amp;pgtype=section" rel="noreferrer noopener">South China Morning Post</a></em>&nbsp;report stated, citing experts. However, it can also act as a spark that propels innovation in China, driving Chinese companies even further towards producing their technologies. It could create a new AI research boom and make the Chinese landscape more energetic and self-sufficient.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the blockade creates a vacuum that domestic giants like Alibaba, Baidu, and Tencent are well-positioned to fill.&nbsp;Those companies have the financial muscle, talent, and infrastructure to accelerate their AI research and development, leading to even more active efforts by these players in AI innovation and building homegrown alternatives for OpenAI.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Besides, the Chinese government has aggressively funded its tech industry with large investments and favorable regulations. In turn, we may see a new rush of AI research that would increase competition between domestic Chinese players and bring China in line with its overseas counterparts.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Global AI dynamics</strong></h3>



<p>The move by OpenAI has ramifications beyond China. The potential of this move to shift global AI dynamics is very real, and it looks increasingly likely that we could see an even more fragmented AI landscape. While the US and China are busy defining their dominance, other countries and regions may align with one side based on access to AI technologies.</p>



<p>This is particularly the case for Southeast Asia and African countries where China has strong economic ties &#8211; they would likely favour more Chinese AI solutions. However,&nbsp;European and North American states could increase their dependence on American-based AI solutions. This split could have profound implications for international consortia, data exchanges and the evolution of worldwide AI norms.</p>



<p>The blockade also raises crucial questions of ethics and security. In this context, OpenAI is exercising digital sovereignty—it controls who can and cannot reap the fruits of its technology. The moves are part of a broader clampdown now taking place at all levels of the AI stack to ensure such technologies are built and deployed in ways that meet decent standards and ethics, including security aspects.</p>



<p>This challenges China in strategically positioning its <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2021/10/15/globaldata-china-is-ahead-of-global-rivals-for-ai-unicorns/">burgeoning AI sector</a> so that other nations do not see it as threatening.&nbsp;Yet, as the AI race heats up, we need to&nbsp;put ethics inevitably&nbsp;and international collaboration as top priorities&nbsp;and for&nbsp;some that see China as an essential market, those companies will have to find a way to work around the complicated geopolitical hurdles.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Apple, for instance, is reportedly seeking local partners to provide services that comply with Beijing&#8217;s stringent AI regulations, including the standards set by the China Electronic Standardisation Institute last year. After all, the future of AI hinges not only on technological advancements but also on the geopolitical strategies and policies that govern its development and deployment.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>(Photo: <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-close-up-of-a-computer-screen-with-a-message-on-it-UF3vfhV04SA">Jonathan Kemper</a>)</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/06/13/apple-reportedly-getting-free-chatgpt-access/"><strong>Apple is reportedly getting free ChatGPT access</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/">Tech war escalates: OpenAI shuts door on China</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-war-escalates-openai-shuts-door-on-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US clamps down on China-bound investments</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dashveenjit Kaur]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 16:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quantum Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=15129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a move that has further strained the already tense US-China relations, the Biden administration has advanced plans to restrict American investments in key Chinese technology sectors. This decision, announced by the US Treasury Department, has sparked a swift and sharp rebuke from Beijing, highlighting the deepening rift between the world&#8217;s two largest economies. The<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments/" title="ReadUS clamps down on China-bound investments">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments/">US clamps down on China-bound investments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a move that has further strained the already tense US-China relations, the Biden administration has advanced plans to restrict American investments in key Chinese technology sectors. This decision, announced by the US Treasury Department, has sparked a swift and sharp rebuke from Beijing, highlighting the deepening rift between the world&#8217;s two largest economies.</p>



<p>The proposed rules, focusing on curbing investments in <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2020/06/19/baidu-ai-alliance-us-china-relations-deteriorate/">AI</a>, quantum computing, and semiconductors, represent the latest salvo in what many observers call a &#8220;tech cold war.&#8221; These restrictions aim to prevent China from <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2019/01/31/un-china-us-leading-ai-race/">gaining ground in technologies</a> critical to national security, particularly those with potential military applications.</p>



<p>China&#8217;s Ministry of Commerce responded with &#8220;severe concern and resolute opposition,&#8221; accusing the US of politicizing and weaponizing trade and commerce issues. The ministry&#8217;s statement urges the US to &#8220;respect the rules of a market economy and the principle of fair competition,&#8221; calling for cancelling the proposed rules and improving economic relations.</p>



<p>The Chinese government&#8217;s strong reaction underscores the significance of these restrictions. Beijing views them as an attempt to hinder China&#8217;s technological progress and economic development, a claim it has frequently levelled against Washington in recent years. The ministry went further, asserting that the US move would &#8220;pressure the normal development of China&#8217;s industry&#8221; and disrupt the &#8220;security and stability&#8221; of global supply chains.</p>



<p>This latest development is part of a broader pattern of increasing technological rivalry between the US and China. The trade dispute began in 2018 under the Trump administration and&nbsp;has already&nbsp;resulted in substantial tariffs on both sides. Additionally, the US has taken steps to restrict the activities of numerous Chinese tech firms within its borders and has encouraged global enterprises to limit their business in China.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>US draws new battle lines in tech race with China</strong></h3>



<p>As <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-21/us-moves-closer-to-restricting-outbound-investment-in-china-for-chips-ai-tech?srnd=technology-vp&amp;sref=QqWIvTvt"><em>Bloomberg</em></a> puts it, the recently released <a href="https://sanctionsnews.bakermckenzie.com/us-treasury-department-issues-proposed-rules-restricting-us-outbound-investment-in-advanced-technologies-involving-china/#:~:text=EO%2014105%20and%20the%20related,%2C%20and%20cyber%2Denabled%20capabilities.">Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</a> (NPRM) is&nbsp;essentially&nbsp;one of several bureaucratic steps set in motion by an executive order issued last&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2023/08/09/executive-order-on-addressing-united-states-investments-in-certain-national-security-technologies-and-products-in-countries-of-concern/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">August</a>.&nbsp;The proposed US rules are comprehensive in scope, covering&nbsp;various types of investments, including equity acquisitions, certain debt financing, joint ventures, and even some limited partner investments in non-US pooled investment funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, the proposal includes exemptions, such as investments in publicly traded companies and full ownership buyouts, possibly to balance national security concerns with maintaining some level of economic engagement. The focus on AI in these restrictions is particularly noteworthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The US administration has expressed concerns about China developing AI applications for weapons targeting and mass surveillance, highlighting the dual-use nature of this technology and the ethical considerations surrounding its development. This emphasis on AI reflects its growing importance in future technological and economic competitiveness.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The price of this tech tug-of-war</strong></h3>



<p>The potential impact of these rules extends far beyond the immediate US-China relationship. They could lead to a further decoupling of the US and Chinese tech ecosystems, potentially accelerating China&#8217;s efforts to achieve technological self-sufficiency. Moreover, these restrictions could have ripple effects on international collaborations in scientific research and technological development, potentially slowing progress across the board.</p>



<p>From a geopolitical perspective, this move will likely further complicate US-China relations, which are&nbsp;already strained by trade disputes and human rights concerns. It may also prompt other countries to reassess their policies regarding tech investments and knowledge sharing with China.</p>



<p>The challenge for the Biden administration will be to effectively protect US national security interests without stifling innovation or causing undue economic harm. China&#8217;s assertion of its right to take countermeasures adds another layer of uncertainty to an already complex situation. How Beijing responds could have significant implications for global trade and technology development.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@alecimages?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Chenyu Guan</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2022/09/01/us-introduces-new-ai-chip-export-restrictions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>US introduces new AI chip export restrictions</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments/">US clamps down on China-bound investments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/us-clamps-down-china-bound-investments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft: China plans to disrupt elections with AI-generated disinformation</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 10:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepfakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[democracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=14650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Beijing is expected to ramp up sophisticated AI-generated disinformation campaigns to influence several high-profile elections in 2024, according to Microsoft&#8217;s threat intelligence team. Microsoft warned that state-backed Chinese cyber groups – with assistance from North Korean actors – &#8220;are likely to target&#8221; the presidential and legislative elections in countries such as the US, South Korea,<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation/" title="ReadMicrosoft: China plans to disrupt elections with AI-generated disinformation">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation/">Microsoft: China plans to disrupt elections with AI-generated disinformation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Beijing is expected to ramp up sophisticated AI-generated disinformation campaigns to influence several high-profile elections in 2024, according to Microsoft&#8217;s threat intelligence team.</p>



<p>Microsoft <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2024/04/04/china-ai-influence-elections-mtac-cybersecurity/">warned</a> that state-backed Chinese cyber groups – with assistance from North Korean actors – &#8220;are likely to target&#8221; the presidential and legislative elections in countries such as the US, South Korea, and India this year. Their primary tactic is projected to be the creation and dissemination on social media of AI-generated content skewed to &#8220;benefit their positions&#8221; in these races.</p>



<p>&#8220;While the impact of such content in swaying audiences remains low, China&#8217;s increasing experimentation in augmenting memes, videos, and audio will continue – and may prove effective down the line,&#8221; Microsoft cautioned in the report released Friday.</p>



<p>The company cited China&#8217;s recent &#8220;dry run&#8221; utilising AI-synthesised disinformation during Taiwan&#8217;s January presidential election as a harbinger of this emerging threat. Microsoft assessed that a pro-Beijing group known as Storm 1376 or Spamouflage Dragon made the first documented attempt by a state actor to influence a foreign vote using AI-manufactured content.</p>



<p>Tactics deployed by the Chinese-backed operatives included posting fake audio clips likely &#8220;generated by AI&#8221; that depicted a former presidential candidate endorsing a rival, as well as AI-generated memes leveling unfounded corruption allegations against the ultimately victorious pro-sovereignty candidate William Lai. The group also created AI-rendered &#8220;news anchors&#8221; to broadcast disinformation about Lai&#8217;s personal life.</p>



<p>&#8220;As populations in India, South Korea, and the United States head to the polls, we are likely to see Chinese cyber and influence actors, and to some extent North Korean cyber actors, work toward targeting these elections,&#8221; the Microsoft report stated.</p>



<p>The company added that Chinese groups are already attempting to map divisive issues and voting blocs in the US through orchestrated social media campaigns, potentially &#8220;to gather intelligence and precision on key voting demographics ahead of the US Presidential election.&#8221;</p>



<p>While flagging the risk, Microsoft acknowledged that AI-enabled disinformation has so far achieved limited success in shaping public opinion globally. But it warned that Beijing&#8217;s growing investment and increasing sophistication with the technology poses an escalating threat to the integrity of democratic elections worldwide.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@element5digital?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Element5 Digital</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/04/03/how-to-safeguard-your-business-ai-generated-deepfakes/"><strong>How to safeguard your business from AI-generated deepfakes</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation/">Microsoft: China plans to disrupt elections with AI-generated disinformation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/microsoft-china-plans-disrupt-elections-ai-generated-disinformation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google engineer stole AI tech for Chinese firms</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 17:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellectual property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linwei ding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=14500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A former Google engineer has been charged with stealing trade secrets related to the company&#8217;s AI technology and secretly working with two Chinese firms. Linwei Ding, a 38-year-old Chinese national, was arrested on Wednesday in Newark, California, and faces four counts of federal trade secret theft, each punishable by up to 10 years in prison.<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms/" title="ReadGoogle engineer stole AI tech for Chinese firms">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms/">Google engineer stole AI tech for Chinese firms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A former Google engineer has been charged with stealing trade secrets related to the company&#8217;s AI technology and secretly working with two Chinese firms.</p>



<p>Linwei Ding, a 38-year-old Chinese national, was arrested on Wednesday in Newark, California, and faces four counts of federal trade secret theft, each punishable by up to 10 years in prison.</p>



<p>The indictment alleges that Ding, who was hired by Google in 2019 to develop software for the company&#8217;s supercomputing data centres, began transferring sensitive trade secrets and confidential information to his personal Google Cloud account in 2021.</p>



<p>&#8220;Ding continued periodic uploads until May 2, 2023, by which time Ding allegedly uploaded more than 500 unique files containing confidential information,&#8221; said the US Department of Justice in a statement.</p>



<p>Prosecutors claim that after stealing the trade secrets, Ding was offered a chief technology officer position at a startup AI company in China and participated in investor meetings for that firm. Additionally, Ding is alleged to have founded and served as CEO of a China-based startup focused on training AI models using supercomputing chips.</p>



<p>&#8220;Today&#8217;s charges are the latest illustration of the lengths affiliates of companies based in the People&#8217;s Republic of China are willing to go to steal American innovation,&#8221; said FBI Director Christopher Wray.</p>



<p>&#8220;The theft of innovative technology and trade secrets from American companies can cost jobs and have devastating economic and national security consequences.&#8221;</p>



<p>If convicted on all counts, Ding faces a maximum penalty of 40 years in prison and a fine of up to $1 million.</p>



<p>The case underscores the ongoing tensions between the US and China over intellectual property theft and the race to dominate emerging technologies like AI.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@towfiqu999999?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Towfiqu Barbhuiya</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-in-black-long-sleeve-shirt-using-macbook-pro-em5w9_xj3uU?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/2024/03/06/openai-musk-wanted-merge-tesla-or-take-full-control/"><strong>OpenAI: Musk wanted us to merge with Tesla or take ‘full control’</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/upcoming-events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms/">Google engineer stole AI tech for Chinese firms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-engineer-stole-ai-tech-for-chinese-firms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
