<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ryan Daws, Author at AI News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/author/ryan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/author/ryan/</link>
	<description>Artificial Intelligence News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/ai-icon-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ryan Daws, Author at AI News</title>
	<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/author/ryan/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 16:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Governments are scrambling to establish regulations to govern AI, citing numerous concerns over data privacy, bias, safety, and more. AI News caught up with Nerijus Šveistys, Senior Legal Counsel at Oxylabs, to understand the state of play when it comes to AI regulation and its potential implications for industries, businesses, and innovation. “The boom of<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/" title="ReadAI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/">AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Governments are scrambling to establish regulations to govern AI, citing numerous concerns over data privacy, bias, safety, and more.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="800" height="800" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-16743" style="width:174px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs.jpeg 800w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-768x768.jpeg 768w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-125x125.jpeg 125w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-200x200.jpeg 200w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-285x285.jpeg 285w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-250x250.jpeg 250w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-100x100.jpeg 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-60x60.jpeg 60w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-400x400.jpeg 400w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Nerijus-Sveistys-oxylabs-600x600.jpeg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></figure></div>


<p>AI News caught up with Nerijus Šveistys, Senior Legal Counsel at <a href="https://oxylabs.io/">Oxylabs</a>, to understand the state of play when it comes to AI regulation and its potential implications for industries, businesses, and innovation.</p>



<p>“The boom of the last few years appears to have sparked a push to establish regulatory frameworks for AI governance,” explains Šveistys.</p>



<p>“This is a natural development, as the rise of AI seems to pose issues in data privacy and protection, bias and discrimination, safety, intellectual property, and other legal areas, as well as ethics that need to be addressed.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Regions diverge in regulatory strategy</h3>



<p>The European Union’s <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/eu-ai-act-early-prep-could-give-businesses-competitive-edge/">AI Act</a> has, unsurprisingly, positioned the region with a strict, centralised approach. The regulation, which came into force this year, is set to be fully effective by 2026.</p>



<p>Šveistys pointed out that the EU has acted relatively swiftly compared to other jurisdictions: “The main difference we can see is the comparative quickness with which the EU has released a uniform regulation to govern the use of all types of AI.”</p>



<p>Meanwhile, other regions have opted for more piecemeal approaches. China, for instance, has been implementing regulations specific to certain AI technologies in a phased-out manner. According to Šveistys, China began regulating AI models as early as 2021.</p>



<p>“In 2021, they introduced regulation on recommendation algorithms, which [had] increased their capabilities in digital advertising. It was followed by regulations <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/chinas-deepfake-laws-come-into-effect-today/">on deep synthesis models</a> or, in common terms, deepfakes and content generation in 2022,” he said.</p>



<p>“Then, in 2023, regulation on generative AI models was introduced as these models were making a splash in commercial usage.”</p>



<p>The US, in contrast, remains relatively uncoordinated in its approach. Federal-level regulations are yet to be enacted, with efforts mostly emerging at the state level.</p>



<p>“There are proposed regulations at the state level, such as the so-called California AI Act, but even if they come into power, it may still take some time before they do,” Šveistys noted.</p>



<p>This delay in implementing unified AI regulations in the US has raised questions about the extent to which business pushback may be contributing to the slow rollout. Šveistys said that while lobbyist pressure is a known factor, it’s not the only potential reason.</p>



<p>“There was <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/tech-industry-giants-urge-eu-streamline-ai-regulations/">pushback to the EU AI Act</a>, too, which was nevertheless introduced. Thus, it is not clear whether the delay in the US is only due to lobbyism or other obstacles in the legislation enactment process,” explains Šveistys.</p>



<p>“It might also be because some still see AI as a futuristic concern, not fully appreciating the extent to which it is already a legal issue of today.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Balancing innovation and safety</h3>



<p>Differentiated regulatory approaches could affect the pace of innovation and business competitiveness across regions.</p>



<p>Europe’s regulatory framework, though more stringent, aims to ensure consumer protection and ethical adherence—something that less-regulated environments may lack.</p>



<p>“More rigid regulatory frameworks may impose compliance costs for businesses in the AI field and stifle competitiveness and innovation. On the other hand, they bring the benefits of protecting consumers and adhering to certain ethical norms,” comments Šveistys.</p>



<p>This trade-off is especially pronounced in AI-related sectors such as targeted advertising, where algorithmic bias is increasingly scrutinised.</p>



<p>AI governance often extends beyond laws that specifically target AI, incorporating related legal areas like those governing data collection and privacy. For example, the EU AI Act also regulates the use of AI in physical devices, such as elevators.</p>



<p>&#8220;Additionally, all businesses that collect data for advertisement are potentially affected as AI regulation can also cover algorithmic bias in targeted advertising,&#8221; emphasises Šveistys.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Impact on related industries</h3>



<p>One industry that is deeply intertwined with AI developments is web scraping. Typically used for collecting publicly available data, web scraping is undergoing an AI-driven evolution.</p>



<p>&#8220;From data collection, validation, analysis, or overcoming anti-scraping measures, there is a lot of potential for AI to massively improve the efficiency, accuracy, and adaptability of web scraping operations,&#8221; said Šveistys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, as AI regulation and related laws tighten, web scraping companies will face greater scrutiny.</p>



<p>“AI regulations may also bring the spotlight on certain areas of law that were always very relevant to the web scraping industry, such as privacy or copyright laws,” Šveistys added.</p>



<p>“At the end of the day, scraping content protected by such laws without proper authorisation could always lead to legal issues, and now so can using AI this way.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Copyright battles and legal precedents</h3>



<p>The implications of AI regulation are also playing out on a broader legal stage, particularly in cases involving generative AI tools.</p>



<p>High-profile <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-and-microsoft-lawsuit-github-copilot/">lawsuits</a> have been launched against AI giants like OpenAI and its primary backer, Microsoft, by authors, artists, and musicians who claim their copyrighted materials were used to train AI systems without proper permission.</p>



<p>“These cases are pivotal in determining the legal boundaries of using copyrighted material for AI development and establishing legal precedents for protecting intellectual property in the digital age,” said Šveistys.</p>



<p>While these lawsuits could take years to resolve, their outcomes may fundamentally shape the future of AI development. So, what can businesses do now as the regulatory and legal landscape continues to evolve?</p>



<p>“Speaking about the specific cases of using copyrighted material for AI training, businesses should approach this the same way as any web-scraping activity – that is, evaluate the specific data they wish to collect with the help of a legal expert in the field,” recommends Šveistys.</p>



<p>“It is important to recognise that the AI legal landscape is very new and rapidly evolving, with not many precedents in place to refer to as of yet. Hence, continuous monitoring and adaptation of your AI usage are crucial.”</p>



<p>Just this week, the UK Government made headlines with its announcement of a consultation on the use of copyrighted material for training AI models. Under the proposals, tech firms could be permitted to use copyrighted material unless owners have specifically opted out.</p>



<p>Despite the diversity of approaches globally, the AI regulatory push marks a significant moment for technological governance. Whether through the EU’s comprehensive model, China’s step-by-step strategy, or narrower, state-level initiatives like in the US, businesses worldwide must navigate a complex, evolving framework.</p>



<p>The challenge ahead will be striking the right balance between fostering innovation and mitigating risks, ensuring that AI remains a force for good while avoiding potential harms.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nathangbingle?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nathan Bingle</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/anthropic-urges-ai-regulation-avoid-catastrophes/"><strong>Anthropic urges AI regulation to avoid catastrophes</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:844px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/">AI governance: Analysing emerging global regulations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ai-governance-analysing-emerging-global-regulations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK wants to prove AI can modernise public services responsibly</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 15:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public sector]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The UK Government wants to prove that AI is being deployed responsibly within public services to speed up decision-making, reduce backlogs, and enhance support for citizens. New records, part of the Algorithmic Transparency Recording Standard (ATRS), were published this week to shed light on the AI tools being used and set a benchmark for transparency<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly/" title="ReadUK wants to prove AI can modernise public services responsibly">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly/">UK wants to prove AI can modernise public services responsibly</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UK Government wants to prove that AI is being deployed responsibly within public services to speed up decision-making, reduce backlogs, and enhance support for citizens.</p>



<p>New records, part of the Algorithmic Transparency Recording Standard (ATRS), were <a href="https://www.gov.uk/algorithmic-transparency-records">published</a> this week to shed light on the AI tools being used and set a benchmark for transparency and accountability in the integration of technology in public service delivery.</p>



<p>The initiative is part of the government’s broader strategy to embrace technology to improve outcomes, echoing commitments outlined in the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/missions">&#8220;Plan for Change&#8221;</a> to modernise public services and drive economic growth through innovative solutions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The power of AI for modernisation</h3>



<p>Among the published records, the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office is leveraging AI to provide faster responses to Britons seeking assistance overseas. Similarly, the Ministry of Justice is utilising algorithms to help researchers gain a deeper understanding of how individuals interact with the justice system, while other departments are deploying AI to enhance job advertisements.</p>



<p>The ATRS aims to document how such algorithmic tools are utilised and ensure their responsible application. By doing so, the government hopes to strengthen public trust in these innovations while encouraging their continued adoption across sectors.</p>



<p>Speaking on the government’s approach, Science Secretary Peter Kyle remarked:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Technology has huge potential to transform public services for the better; we will put it to use to cut backlogs, save money, and improve outcomes for citizens across the country.</em></p>



<p><em>Transparency in how and why the public sector is using algorithmic tools is crucial to ensure that they are trusted and effective. That is why we will continue to take bold steps like releasing these records to make sure everyone is clear on how we are applying and trialling technology as we use it to bring public services back from the brink.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Specifically, the Department for Business and Trade has highlighted its algorithmic tool designed to predict which companies are likely to export goods internationally.</p>



<p>The AI-driven approach allows officials to target support towards high-growth potential businesses, enabling them to reach global markets faster. Previously reliant on time-consuming manual methods to analyse the more than five million companies registered on Companies House, this advancement ensures better allocation of resources and expedited assistance.</p>



<p>Business Secretary Jonathan Reynolds said:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;Our Plan for Change will deliver economic growth, and for that to succeed, we need to support companies across the UK to realise their full potential when it comes to exporting around the globe.</em></p>



<p><em>Our use of AI plays a vital and growing role in that mission, allowing high-growth businesses to maximise the export opportunities available to them, while ensuring that we are using taxpayers’ money responsibly and efficiently in delivering economic stability.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Establishing clear guidelines for AI in public services</h3>



<p>To bolster public trust, new guidelines have been announced to clarify the scope of algorithmic transparency records.</p>



<p>Central government organisations will need to publish a record for any algorithmic tool that interacts directly with citizens or plays a significant role in decision-making about individuals. Limited exceptions, such as those concerning national security, apply.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>These records will be published once tools are piloted publicly or have become operational. They will detail the data used to train AI models, the underlying technologies, and the measures implemented to mitigate risks.</p>



<p>Importantly, the records also seek to confirm that – while AI tools are used to accelerate decision-making processes – human oversight remains integral, with trained staff responsible for final decisions.</p>



<p>Dr Antonio Espingardeiro, a member of <a href="https://www.ieee.org/">IEEE</a> and an expert in software and robotics, commented:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;AI has the potential to radically transform the public sector. In recent years, we have seen AI become a credible part of everyday public services. As it becomes more sophisticated, AI can conduct data-heavy tasks traditionally undertaken by humans. It can analyse vast quantities of information and, when coupled with machine learning, search through records and infer patterns or anomalies in data that would otherwise take decades for humans to analyse.</em></p>



<p><em>With this announcement, the UK government has acknowledged AI’s potential and proven that technology investment is essential to improving outcomes and the delivery of vital services. Over time, machine learning and generative AI (GenAI) could bring substantial value to the public system. With increased adoption, we will soon be able to deliver the scalability that the public sector needs and relieve the pressures and workloads placed on staff.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Eleanor Watson, also a member of IEEE and an AI ethics engineer affiliated with <a href="https://www.su.org/">Singularity University</a>, added:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><em>&#8220;With AI growing more rapidly than ever before, and already being tested and employed in education, healthcare, transportation, finance, data security, and more, the government, tech leaders, and academia should work together to establish standards and regulations for safe and responsible development of AI-based systems. This way, AI can be used to its full potential as indicated with this latest announcement.</em></p>



<p><em>Data privacy is probably the most critical ethical consideration, requiring informed consent, data anonymisation, strict access controls, secure storage, and compliance. New techniques such as homomorphic encryption, zero-knowledge proofs, federated learning, and part-trained models can help models to make use of our personal data in an encrypted form.&#8221;</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Transparency remains a key tenet of the UK Government’s AI strategy. This announcement follows a recent statement by Pat McFadden, Chancellor of the Duchy of Lancaster, who affirmed that the benefits of technology – particularly AI – must span both public and private sectors and be used to modernise government.</p>



<p>As the Science Secretary’s department solidifies government efforts to create a &#8220;digital centre,&#8221; it marks a major step forward in boosting the responsible and effective use of AI across the UK’s public sector.</p>



<p>The ATRS records offer a valuable template for how governments worldwide can deploy AI systems to maximise efficiency, grow transparency, and balance the need for innovation with ethical considerations.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@shreyasdbz?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Shreyas Sane</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/"><strong>MHRA pilots ‘AI Airlock’ to accelerate healthcare adoption</strong></a></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:1082px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly/">UK wants to prove AI can modernise public services responsibly</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/uk-wants-prove-ai-can-modernise-public-services-responsibly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CrowdStrike: Cybersecurity pros want safer, specialist GenAI tools</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infosec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>CrowdStrike commissioned a survey of 1,022 cybersecurity professionals worldwide to assess their views on generative AI (GenAI) adoption and its implications. The findings reveal enthusiasm for GenAI’s potential to bolster defences against increasingly sophisticated threats, but also trepidation over risks such as data exposure and attacks on GenAI systems. While much has been speculated about<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools/" title="ReadCrowdStrike: Cybersecurity pros want safer, specialist GenAI tools">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools/">CrowdStrike: Cybersecurity pros want safer, specialist GenAI tools</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/en-gb/">CrowdStrike</a> commissioned a survey of 1,022 cybersecurity professionals worldwide to assess their views on generative AI (GenAI) adoption and its implications.</p>



<p>The findings reveal enthusiasm for GenAI’s potential to bolster defences against increasingly sophisticated threats, but also trepidation over risks such as data exposure and attacks on GenAI systems.</p>



<p>While much has been speculated about the transformative impact of GenAI, the survey’s results paint a clearer picture of how practitioners are thinking about its role in cybersecurity.</p>



<p>According to the report, “We’re entering the era of GenAI in cybersecurity.” However, as organisations adopt this promising technology, their success will hinge on ensuring the safe, responsible, and industry-specific deployment of GenAI tools.</p>



<p>CrowdStrike’s research reveals five pivotal findings that shape the current state of GenAI in cybersecurity:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Platform-based GenAI is favoured </strong></li>
</ol>



<p>80% of respondents indicated a preference for GenAI delivered through integrated cybersecurity platforms rather than standalone tools. Seamless integration is cited as a crucial factor, with many preferring tools that work cohesively with existing systems. “GenAI’s value is linked to how well it works within the broader technology ecosystem,” the report states.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, almost two-thirds (63%) of those surveyed expressed willingness to switch security vendors to access GenAI capabilities from competitors. The survey underscores the industry’s readiness for unified platforms that streamline operations and reduce the complexity of adopting new point solutions.</p>



<ol start="2" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>GenAI built by cybersecurity experts is a must</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Security teams believe GenAI tools should be specifically designed for cybersecurity, not general-purpose systems. 83% of respondents reported they would not trust tools that provide “unsuitable or ill-advised security guidance.”</p>



<p>Breach prevention remains a key motivator, with 74% stating they had faced breaches within the past 18 months or were concerned about vulnerabilities. Respondents prioritised tools from vendors with proven expertise in cybersecurity, incident response, and threat intelligence over suppliers with broad AI leadership alone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As CrowdStrike summarised, “The emphasis on breach prevention and vendor expertise suggests security teams would avoid domain-agnostic GenAI tools.”</p>



<ol start="3" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Augmentation, not replacement </strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Despite growing fears of automation replacing jobs in many industries, the survey’s findings indicate minimal concerns about job displacement in cybersecurity. Instead, respondents expect GenAI to empower security analysts by automating repetitive tasks, reducing burnout, onboarding new personnel faster, and accelerating decision-making.</p>



<p>GenAI’s potential for augmenting analysts’ workflows was underscored by its most requested applications: threat intelligence analysis, assistance with investigations, and automated response mechanisms. As noted in the report, “Respondents overwhelmingly believe GenAI will ultimately optimise the analyst experience, not replace human labour.”</p>



<ol start="4" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>ROI outweighs cost concerns  </strong></li>
</ol>



<p>For organisations evaluating GenAI investments, measurable return on investment (ROI) is the paramount concern, ahead of licensing costs or pricing model confusion. Respondents expect platform-led GenAI deployments to deliver faster results, thanks to cost savings from reduced tool management burdens, streamlined training, and fewer security incidents.</p>



<p>According to the survey data, the expected ROI breakdown includes 31% from cost optimisation and more efficient tools, 30% from fewer incidents, and 26% from reduced management time. Security leaders are clearly focused on ensuring the financial justification for GenAI investments.</p>



<ol start="5" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Guardrails and safety are crucial </strong></li>
</ol>



<p>GenAI adoption is tempered by concerns around safety and privacy, with 87% of organisations either implementing or planning new security policies to oversee GenAI use. Key risks include exposing sensitive data to large language models (LLMs) and adversarial attacks on GenAI tools. Respondents rank safety and privacy controls among their most desired GenAI features, highlighting the need for responsible implementation.</p>



<p>Reflecting the cautious optimism of practitioners, only 39% of respondents firmly believed that the rewards of GenAI outweigh its risks. Meanwhile, 40% considered the risks and rewards “comparable.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Current state of GenAI adoption in cybersecurity</h3>



<p>GenAI adoption remains in its early stages, but interest is growing. 64% of respondents are actively researching or have already invested in GenAI tools, and 69% of those currently evaluating their options plan to make a purchase within the year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Security teams are primarily driven by three concerns: improving attack detection and response, enhancing operational efficiency, and mitigating the impact of staff shortages. Among economic considerations, the top priority is ROI – a sign that security leaders are keen to demonstrate tangible benefits to justify their spending.</p>



<p>CrowdStrike emphasises the importance of a platform-based approach, where GenAI is integrated into a unified system. Such platforms enable seamless adoption, measurable benefits, and safety guardrails for responsible usage. According to the report, “The future of GenAI in cybersecurity will be defined by tools that not only advance security but also uphold the highest standards of safety and privacy.”</p>



<p>The CrowdStrike survey concludes by affirming that “GenAI is not a silver bullet” but has tremendous potential to improve cybersecurity outcomes. As organisations evaluate its adoption, they will prioritise tools that integrate seamlessly with existing platforms, deliver faster response times, and ensure safety and privacy compliance.</p>



<p>With threats becoming more sophisticated, the role of GenAI in enabling security teams to work faster and smarter could prove indispensable. While still in its infancy, GenAI in cybersecurity is poised to shift from early adoption to mainstream deployment, provided organisations and vendors address its risks responsibly.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/"><strong>Keys to AI success: Security, sustainability, and overcoming silos</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:1203px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools/">CrowdStrike: Cybersecurity pros want safer, specialist GenAI tools</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/crowdstrike-cybersecurity-pros-safer-specialist-genai-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gemini 2.0: Google ushers in the agentic AI era </title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Assistants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agentic ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini 2.0m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[models]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google CEO Sundar Pichai has announced the launch of Gemini 2.0, a model that represents the next step in Google’s ambition to revolutionise AI. A year after introducing the Gemini 1.0 model, this major upgrade incorporates enhanced multimodal capabilities, agentic functionality, and innovative user tools designed to push boundaries in AI-driven technology. Leap towards transformational<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era/" title="ReadGemini 2.0: Google ushers in the agentic AI era ">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era/">Gemini 2.0: Google ushers in the agentic AI era </a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Google CEO Sundar Pichai has announced the launch of Gemini 2.0, a model that represents the next step in Google’s ambition to revolutionise AI.</p>



<p>A year after introducing the Gemini 1.0 model, this major upgrade incorporates enhanced multimodal capabilities, agentic functionality, and innovative user tools designed to push boundaries in AI-driven technology.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Leap towards transformational AI&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Reflecting on Google’s 26-year mission to organise and make the world’s information accessible, Pichai remarked, “If Gemini 1.0 was about organising and understanding information, Gemini 2.0 is about making it much more useful.”</p>



<p>Gemini 1.0, released in December 2022, was notable for being Google’s first natively multimodal AI model. The first iteration excelled at understanding and processing text, video, images, audio, and code. Its enhanced 1.5 version became widely embraced by developers for its long-context understanding, enabling applications such as the productivity-focused NotebookLM.</p>



<p>Now, with Gemini 2.0, Google aims to accelerate the role of AI as a universal assistant capable of native image and audio generation, better reasoning and planning, and real-world decision-making capabilities. In Pichai&#8217;s words, the development represents the dawn of an “agentic era.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Introducing Gemini 2.0 | Our most capable AI model yet" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fs0t6SdODd8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>“We have been investing in developing more agentic models, meaning they can understand more about the world around you, think multiple steps ahead, and take action on your behalf, with your supervision,” Pichai explained.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Gemini 2.0: Core features and availability</h3>



<p>At the heart of today&#8217;s announcement is the experimental release of Gemini 2.0 Flash, the flagship model of Gemini’s second generation. It builds upon the foundations laid by its predecessors while delivering faster response times and advanced performance.</p>



<p>Gemini 2.0 Flash supports multimodal inputs and outputs, including the ability to generate native images in conjunction with text and produce steerable text-to-speech multilingual audio. Additionally, users can benefit from native tool integration such as Google Search and even third-party user-defined functions.</p>



<p>Developers and businesses will gain access to Gemini 2.0 Flash via the Gemini API in <a href="https://aistudio.google.com/">Google AI Studio</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai">Vertex AI</a>, while larger model sizes are scheduled for broader release in January 2024.</p>



<p>For global accessibility, the Gemini app now features a chat-optimised version of the 2.0 Flash experimental model. Early adopters can experience this updated assistant on desktop and mobile, with a mobile app rollout imminent.</p>



<p>Products such as Google Search are also being enhanced with Gemini 2.0, unlocking the ability to handle complex queries like advanced math problems, coding enquiries, and multimodal questions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Comprehensive suite of AI innovations&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The launch of Gemini 2.0 comes with compelling new tools that showcase its capabilities.</p>



<p>One such feature, Deep Research, functions as an AI research assistant, simplifying the process of investigating complex topics by compiling information into comprehensive reports. Another upgrade enhances Search with Gemini-enabled AI Overviews that tackle intricate, multi-step user queries.</p>



<p>The model was trained using Google’s sixth-generation Tensor Processing Units (TPUs), known as Trillium, which Pichai notes “powered 100% of Gemini 2.0 training and inference.”</p>



<p>Trillium is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/trillium-tpu-is-ga">available</a> for external developers, allowing them to benefit from the same infrastructure that supports Google’s own advancements.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Pioneering agentic experiences&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Accompanying Gemini 2.0 are experimental “agentic” prototypes built to explore the future of human-AI collaboration, including:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Project Astra: A universal AI assistant</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>First introduced at I/O earlier this year, Project Astra taps into Gemini 2.0’s multimodal understanding to improve real-world AI interactions. Trusted testers have trialled the assistant on Android, offering feedback that has helped refine its multilingual dialogue, memory retention, and integration with Google tools like Search, Lens, and Maps. Astra has also demonstrated near-human conversational latency, with further research underway for its application in wearable technology, such as prototype AI glasses.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Project Mariner: Redefining web automation </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Project Mariner is an experimental web-browsing assistant that uses Gemini 2.0’s ability to reason across text, images, and interactive elements like forms within a browser. In initial tests, it achieved an 83.5% success rate on the WebVoyager benchmark for completing end-to-end web tasks. Early testers using a Chrome extension are helping to refine Mariner’s capabilities while Google evaluates safety measures that ensure the technology remains user-friendly and secure.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Jules: A coding agent for developers  </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Jules, an AI-powered assistant built for developers, integrates directly into GitHub workflows to address coding challenges. It can autonomously propose solutions, generate plans, and execute code-based tasks—all under human supervision. This experimental endeavour is part of Google’s long-term goal to create versatile AI agents across various domains.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Gaming applications and beyond  </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Extending Gemini 2.0’s reach into virtual environments, Google DeepMind is working with gaming partners like Supercell on intelligent game agents. These experimental AI companions can interpret game actions in real-time, suggest strategies, and even access broader knowledge via Search. Research is also being conducted into how Gemini 2.0’s spatial reasoning could support robotics, opening doors for physical-world applications in the future.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Project Astra | Exploring the future capabilities of a universal AI assistant" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hIIlJt8JERI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Addressing responsibility in AI development</h3>



<p>As AI capabilities expand, Google emphasises the importance of prioritising safety and ethical considerations.</p>



<p>Google claims Gemini 2.0 underwent extensive risk assessments, bolstered by the Responsibility and Safety Committee’s oversight to mitigate potential risks. Additionally, its embedded reasoning abilities allow for <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/openai-enhances-ai-safety-new-red-teaming-methods/">advanced “red-teaming,”</a> enabling developers to evaluate security scenarios and optimise safety measures at scale.</p>



<p>Google is also exploring safeguards to address user privacy, prevent misuse, and ensure AI agents remain reliable. For instance, Project Mariner is designed to prioritise user instructions while resisting malicious prompt injections, preventing threats like phishing or fraudulent transactions. Meanwhile, privacy controls in Project Astra make it easy for users to manage session data and deletion preferences.</p>



<p>Pichai reaffirmed the company’s commitment to responsible development, stating, “We firmly believe that the only way to build AI is to be responsible from the start.”</p>



<p>With the Gemini 2.0 Flash release, Google is edging closer to its vision of building a universal assistant capable of transforming interactions across domains.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/"><strong>Machine unlearning: Researchers make AI models ‘forget’ data</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:1139px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era/">Gemini 2.0: Google ushers in the agentic AI era </a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/gemini-2-0-google-ushers-in-agentic-ai-era/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keys to AI success: Security, sustainability, and overcoming silos</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 12:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netapp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scaling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NetApp has shed light on the pressing issues faced by organisations globally as they strive to optimise their strategies for AI success. “2025 is shaping up to be a defining year for AI, as organisations transition from experimentation to scaling their AI capabilities,” said Gabie Boko, NetApp’s Chief Marketing Officer. “Businesses are making significant investments<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/" title="ReadKeys to AI success: Security, sustainability, and overcoming silos">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/">Keys to AI success: Security, sustainability, and overcoming silos</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.netapp.com/">NetApp</a> has shed light on the pressing issues faced by organisations globally as they strive to optimise their strategies for AI success.</p>



<p>“2025 is shaping up to be a defining year for AI, as organisations transition from experimentation to scaling their AI capabilities,” said Gabie Boko, NetApp’s Chief Marketing Officer.</p>



<p>“Businesses are making significant investments to drive innovation and efficiency, but these efforts will succeed only if global tech executives can address the mounting challenges of data complexity, security, and sustainability.”</p>



<p>The findings of NetApp’s latest <em>Data Complexity Report</em> paints a detailed picture of where businesses currently stand on their AI journeys and the key trends that will shape the technology’s future.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cost of transformation</h3>



<p>Two-thirds of businesses worldwide claim their data is &#8220;fully or mostly optimised&#8221; for AI purposes, highlighting vast improvements in making data accessible, accurate, and well-documented. Yet, the study reveals that the journey towards AI maturity requires further significant investment.</p>



<p>A striking 40% of global technology executives anticipate “unprecedented investment” will be necessary in 2025 just to enhance AI and data management capabilities.</p>



<p>While considerable progress has been made, achieving impactful breakthroughs demands an even greater commitment in financial and infrastructural resources. Catching up with AI&#8217;s potential might not come cheap, but leaders prepared to invest could reap significant rewards in innovation and efficiency.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Data silos impede AI success</h3>



<p>One of the principal barriers identified in the report is the fragmentation of data. An overwhelming 79% of global tech executives state that unifying their data, reducing silos and ensuring smooth interconnectedness, is key to unlocking AI’s full potential.</p>



<p>Companies that have embraced unified data storage are better placed to overcome this hurdle. By connecting data regardless of its type or location (across hybrid multi-cloud environments,) they ensure constant accessibility and minimise fragmentation.</p>



<p>The report indicates that organisations prioritising data unification are significantly more likely to meet their AI goals in 2025. Nearly one-third (30%) of businesses failing to prioritise unification foresee missing their targets, compared to just 23% for those placing this at the heart of their strategy.</p>



<p>Executives have doubled down on data management and infrastructure as top priorities, increasingly recognising that optimising their capacity to gather, store, and process information is essential for AI maturity. Companies refusing to tackle these data challenges risk falling behind in an intensely competitive global market.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Scaling risks of AI</h3>



<p>As businesses accelerate their AI adoption, the associated risks – particularly around <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/ai-security/">security</a> – are becoming more acute. More than two-fifths (41%) of global tech executives predict a stark rise in security threats by 2025 as AI becomes integral to more facets of their operations.</p>



<p>AI’s rapid rise has expanded attack surfaces, exposing data sets to new vulnerabilities and creating unique challenges such as protecting sensitive AI models. Countries leading the AI race, including India, the US, and Japan, are nearly twice as likely to encounter escalating security concerns compared to less AI-advanced nations like Germany, France, and Spain.</p>



<p>Increased awareness of AI-driven security challenges is reflected in business priorities. Over half (59%) of global executives name cybersecurity as one of the top stressors confronting organisations today.</p>



<p>However, progress is being made. Despite elevated concerns, the report suggests that effective security measures are yielding results. Since 2023, the number of executives ranking cybersecurity and ransomware protection as their top priority has fallen by 17%, signalling optimism in combating these risks effectively.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Limiting AI’s environmental costs</h3>



<p>Beyond security risks, AI’s growth is raising urgent questions of sustainability. Over one-third of global technology executives (34%) predict that AI advancements will drive significant changes to corporate sustainability practices. Meanwhile, 33% foresee new government policies and investments targeting energy usage.</p>



<p>The infrastructure powering AI and transforming raw data into business value demands significant energy, counteracting organisational sustainability targets. AI-heavy nations often feel the environmental impact more acutely than their less AI-focused counterparts.</p>



<p>While 72% of businesses still prioritise carbon footprint reduction, the report notes a decline from 84% in 2023, pointing to increasing tension between sustainability commitments and the relentless march of innovation. For organisations to scale AI without causing irreparable damage to the planet, maintaining environmental responsibility alongside technological growth will be paramount in coming years.</p>



<p>Krish Vitaldevara, SVP and GM at NetApp, commented: “The organisations leading in advanced analytics and AI are those that have unified and well-cataloged data, robust security and compliance for sensitive information, and a clear understanding of how data evolves.</p>



<p>“By tackling these challenges, they can drive innovation while ensuring resilience, responsibility, and timely insights in the new AI era.”</p>



<p><em>You can find a full copy of NetApp’s report </em><a href="https://www.netapp.com/pdf.html?item=/media/120560-2024-data-complexity-survey-report.pdf"><em>here</em></a><em> (PDF)</em></p>



<p>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@chunlea?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Chunli Ju</a>)</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/o1-model-llm-ai-openai-training-research-next-generation/"><strong>New AI training techniques aim to overcome current challenges</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:961px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/">Keys to AI success: Security, sustainability, and overcoming silos</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/keys-ai-success-security-sustainability-overcoming-silos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Machine unlearning: Researchers make AI models ‘forget’ data</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Researchers from the Tokyo University of Science (TUS) have developed a method to enable large-scale AI models to selectively &#8220;forget&#8221; specific classes of data. Progress in AI has provided tools capable of revolutionising various domains, from healthcare to autonomous driving. However, as technology advances, so do its complexities and ethical considerations.&#160; The paradigm of large-scale<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/" title="ReadMachine unlearning: Researchers make AI models ‘forget’ data">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/">Machine unlearning: Researchers make AI models ‘forget’ data</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Researchers from the <a href="https://www.tus.ac.jp/en/">Tokyo University of Science</a> (TUS) have developed a method to enable large-scale AI models to selectively &#8220;forget&#8221; specific classes of data.</p>



<p>Progress in AI has provided tools capable of revolutionising various domains, from healthcare to autonomous driving. However, as technology advances, so do its complexities and ethical considerations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The paradigm of large-scale pre-trained AI systems, such as OpenAI’s ChatGPT and <a href="https://openai.com/index/clip/">CLIP</a> (Contrastive Language–Image Pre-training), has reshaped expectations for machines. These highly generalist models, capable of handling a vast array of tasks with consistent precision, have seen widespread adoption for both professional and personal use.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, such versatility comes at a hefty price. Training and running these models demands prodigious amounts of energy and time, raising sustainability concerns, as well as requiring cutting-edge hardware significantly more expensive than standard computers. Compounding these issues is that generalist tendencies may hinder the efficiency of AI models when applied to specific tasks.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>For instance, “in practical applications, the classification of all kinds of object classes is rarely required,” explains Associate Professor Go Irie, who led the research. “For example, in an autonomous driving system, it would be sufficient to recognise limited classes of objects such as cars, pedestrians, and traffic signs.</p>



<p>“We would not need to recognise food, furniture, or animal species. Retaining classes that do not need to be recognised may decrease overall classification accuracy, as well as cause operational disadvantages such as the waste of computational resources and the risk of information leakage.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A potential solution lies in training models to “forget” redundant or unnecessary information—streamlining their processes to focus solely on what is required. While some existing methods already cater to this need, they tend to assume a “white-box” approach where users have access to a model’s internal architecture and parameters. Oftentimes, however, users get no such visibility.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Black-box” AI systems, more common due to commercial and ethical restrictions, conceal their inner mechanisms, rendering traditional forgetting techniques impractical. To address this gap, the research team turned to derivative-free optimisation—an approach that sidesteps reliance on the inaccessible internal workings of a model.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Advancing through forgetting</h3>



<p>The study, set to be presented at the Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) conference in 2024, introduces a methodology dubbed “black-box forgetting.”</p>



<p>The process modifies the input prompts (text instructions fed to models) in iterative rounds to make the AI progressively &#8220;forget&#8221; certain classes. Associate Professor Irie collaborated on the work with co-authors Yusuke Kuwana and Yuta Goto (both from TUS), alongside Dr Takashi Shibata from <a href="https://www.nec.com/">NEC Corporation</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>For their experiments, the researchers targeted CLIP, a vision-language model with image classification abilities. The method they developed is built upon the Covariance Matrix Adaptation Evolution Strategy (CMA-ES), an evolutionary algorithm designed to optimise solutions step-by-step. In this study, CMA-ES was harnessed to evaluate and hone prompts provided to CLIP, ultimately suppressing its ability to classify specific image categories.</p>



<p>As the project progressed, challenges arose. Existing optimisation techniques struggled to scale up for larger volumes of targeted categories, leading the team to devise a novel parametrisation strategy known as &#8220;latent context sharing.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This approach breaks latent context – a representation of information generated by prompts – into smaller, more manageable pieces. By allocating certain elements to a single token (word or character) while reusing others across multiple tokens, they dramatically reduced the problem&#8217;s complexity. Crucially, this made the process computationally tractable even for extensive forgetting applications.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through benchmark tests on multiple image classification datasets, the researchers validated the efficacy of black-box forgetting—achieving the goal of making CLIP &#8220;forget&#8221; approximately 40% of target classes without direct access to the AI model&#8217;s internal architecture.</p>



<p>This research marks the first successful attempt to induce selective forgetting in a black-box vision-language model, demonstrating promising results.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Benefits of helping AI models forget data</h3>



<p>Beyond its technical ingenuity, this innovation holds significant potential for real-world applications where task-specific precision is paramount.</p>



<p>Simplifying models for specialised tasks could make them faster, more resource-efficient, and capable of running on less powerful devices—hastening the adoption of AI in areas previously deemed unfeasible.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Another key use lies in image generation, where forgetting entire categories of visual context could prevent models from inadvertently creating undesirable or harmful content, be it offensive material or misinformation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Perhaps most importantly, this method addresses one of AI’s greatest ethical quandaries: <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/privacy/">privacy</a>.</p>



<p>AI models, particularly large-scale ones, are often trained on massive datasets that may inadvertently contain sensitive or outdated information. Requests to remove such data—especially in light of laws advocating for the “Right to be Forgotten”—pose significant challenges.</p>



<p>Retraining entire models to exclude problematic data is costly and time-intensive, yet the risks of leaving it unaddressed can have far-reaching consequences.</p>



<p>“Retraining a large-scale model consumes enormous amounts of energy,” notes Associate Professor Irie. “‘Selective forgetting,’ or so-called machine unlearning, may provide an efficient solution to this problem.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>These privacy-focused applications are especially relevant in high-stakes industries like <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/ai-industries/healthcare/">healthcare</a> and <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/large-language-models-could-revolutionsise-the-finance-sector-within-two-years/">finance</a>, where sensitive data is central to operations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the global race to advance AI accelerates, the Tokyo University of Science’s black-box forgetting approach charts an important path forward—not only by making the technology more adaptable and efficient but also by adding significant safeguards for users.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>While the potential for misuse remains, methods like selective forgetting demonstrate that researchers are proactively addressing both ethical and practical challenges.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/why-qwq-32b-preview-is-the-reasoning-ai-to-watch/"><strong>Why QwQ-32B-Preview is the reasoning AI to watch</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:769px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/">Machine unlearning: Researchers make AI models ‘forget’ data</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/machine-unlearning-researchers-ai-models-forget-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon Bedrock gains new AI models, tools, and features</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon web services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aws]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bedrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[models]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon Web Services (AWS) has announced improvements to bolster Bedrock, its fully managed generative AI service. The updates include new foundational models from several AI pioneers, enhanced data processing capabilities, and features aimed at improving inference efficiency. Dr Swami Sivasubramanian, VP of AI and Data at AWS, said: “Amazon Bedrock continues to see rapid growth<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features/" title="ReadAmazon Bedrock gains new AI models, tools, and features">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features/">Amazon Bedrock gains new AI models, tools, and features</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/">Amazon Web Services</a> (AWS) has announced improvements to bolster Bedrock, its fully managed generative AI service.</p>



<p>The updates include new foundational models from several AI pioneers, enhanced data processing capabilities, and features aimed at improving inference efficiency.</p>



<p>Dr Swami Sivasubramanian, VP of AI and Data at AWS, said: “Amazon Bedrock continues to see rapid growth as customers flock to the service for its broad selection of leading models, tools to easily customise with their data, built-in responsible AI features, and capabilities for developing sophisticated agents.</p>



<p>“With this new set of capabilities, we are empowering customers to develop more intelligent AI applications that will deliver greater value to their end-users.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Amazon Bedrock expands its model diversity</h3>



<p>AWS is set to become the first cloud provider to feature models from AI developers Luma AI and poolside, while also incorporating Stability AI’s latest release.</p>



<p>Through its new <em>Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</em>, customers will have access to over 100 emerging and specialised models from across industries, ensuring they can select the most appropriate tools for their unique needs.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Luma AI’s Ray 2</strong> </li>
</ul>



<p>Luma AI, known for advancing generative AI in video content creation, brings its next-generation Ray 2 model to Amazon Bedrock. This model generates high-quality, lifelike video outputs from text or image inputs and allows organisations to create detailed outputs in fields such as fashion, architecture, and graphic design. AWS’s presence as the first provider for this model ensures businesses can experiment with new camera angles, cinematographic styles, and consistent characters with a frictionless workflow.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>poolside’s </strong><strong><em>malibu</em></strong><strong> and </strong><strong><em>point</em></strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Designed to address challenges in modern software engineering, poolside’s models – <em>malibu</em> and <em>point</em> – specialise in code generation, testing, documentation, and real-time code completion. Importantly, developers can securely fine-tune these models using their private datasets. Accompanied by Assistant – an integration for development environments – poolside’s tools allow engineering teams to accelerate productivity, ship projects faster, and increase accuracy.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Stability AI’s Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large  </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Amazon Bedrock customers will soon gain access to Stability AI’s text-to-image model <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/stability-ai-releases-most-powerful-image-generation-models-date/">Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large</a>. This addition supports businesses in creating high-quality visual media for use cases in areas like gaming, advertising, and retail.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through the Bedrock Marketplace, AWS also enables access to over 100 specialised models. These include solutions tailored to fields such as biology (EvolutionaryScale’s ESM3 generative model), financial data (Writer’s Palmyra-Fin), and media (Camb.ai’s text-to-audio MARS6).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="692" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-1024x692.jpg" alt="Image showing the expanded AI model catalog in the Amazon Bedrock Marketplace." class="wp-image-16656" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-1024x692.jpg 1024w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-300x203.jpg 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-768x519.jpg 768w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-296x200.jpg 296w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-380x257.jpg 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-350x237.jpg 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-100x68.jpg 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence-60x41.jpg 60w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/amazon-bedrock-model-marketplace-catalog-ai-artificial-intelligence.jpg 1294w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Zendesk, a global customer service software firm, leverages Bedrock’s marketplace to personalise support across email and social channels using AI-driven localisation and sentiment analysis tools. For example, they use models like Widn.AI to tailor responses based on real-time sentiment in customers’ native languages.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Scaling inference with new Amazon Bedrock features</h3>



<p>Large-scale generative AI applications require balancing the cost, latency, and accuracy of inference processes. AWS is addressing this challenge with two new Amazon Bedrock features:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Prompt Caching</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>The new caching capability reduces redundant processing of prompts by securely storing frequently used queries, saving on both time and costs. This feature can lead to up to a 90% reduction in costs and an 85% decrease in latency. For example, Adobe incorporated Prompt Caching into its Acrobat AI Assistant to summarise documents and answer questions, achieving a 72% reduction in response times during initial testing.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Intelligent Prompt Routing</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>This feature dynamically directs prompts to the most suitable foundation model within a family, optimising results for both cost and quality. Customers such as Argo Labs, which builds conversational voice AI solutions for restaurants, have already benefited. While simpler queries (like booking tables) are handled by smaller models, more nuanced requests (e.g., dietary-specific menu questions) are intelligently routed to larger models. Argo Labs’ usage of intelligent Prompt Routing has not only improved response quality but also reduced costs by up to 30%.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Data utilisation: Knowledge bases and automation</h3>



<p>A key attraction of generative AI lies in its ability to extract value from data. AWS is enhancing its Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases to ensure organisations can deploy their unique datasets for richer AI-powered user experiences.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Using structured data </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>AWS has introduced capabilities for structured data retrieval within Knowledge Bases. This enhancement allows customers to query data stored across Amazon services like SageMaker Lakehouse and Redshift through natural-language prompts, with results translated back into SQL queries. Octus, a credit intelligence firm, plans to use this capability to provide clients with dynamic, natural-language reports on its structured financial data.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>GraphRAG integration </strong></li>
</ul>



<p>By incorporating automated graph modelling (powered by Amazon Neptune), customers can now generate and connect relational data for stronger AI applications. BMW Group, for instance, will use GraphRAG to augment its virtual assistant MAIA. This assistant taps into BMW’s wealth of internal data to deliver comprehensive responses and premium user experiences.</p>



<p>Separately, AWS has unveiled Amazon Bedrock Data Automation, a tool that transforms unstructured content (e.g., documents, video, and audio) into structured formats for analytics or retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). Companies like Symbeo (automated claims processing) and Tenovos (digital asset management) are already piloting the tool to improve operational efficiency and data reuse.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Amazon Bedrock Data Automation Overview | Amazon Web Services" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/s54hx76QD5k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>The expansion of Amazon Bedrock’s ecosystem reflects its growing popularity, with the service recording a 4.7x increase in its customer base over the last year. Industry leaders like Adobe, BMW, Zendesk, and Tenovos have all embraced AWS’s latest innovations to improve their generative AI capabilities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most of the newly announced tools – such as inference management, Knowledge Bases with structured data retrieval, and GraphRAG – are currently in preview, while notable model releases from Luma AI, poolside, and Stability AI are expected soon.</p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/"><strong>Alibaba Cloud overhauls AI partner initiative</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:1009px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features/">Amazon Bedrock gains new AI models, tools, and features</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/amazon-bedrock-gains-new-ai-models-tools-and-features/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MHRA pilots ‘AI Airlock’ to accelerate healthcare adoption</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics & Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legislation & Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mhra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nhs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has announced the selection of five healthcare technologies for its ‘AI Airlock’ scheme. AI Airlock aims to refine the process of regulating AI-driven medical devices and help fast-track their safe introduction to the UK’s National Health Service (NHS) and patients in need. The technologies chosen for this<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/" title="ReadMHRA pilots ‘AI Airlock’ to accelerate healthcare adoption">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/">MHRA pilots ‘AI Airlock’ to accelerate healthcare adoption</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/medicines-and-healthcare-products-regulatory-agency">MHRA</a>) has announced the selection of five healthcare technologies for its ‘AI Airlock’ scheme.</p>



<p>AI Airlock aims to refine the process of regulating AI-driven medical devices and help fast-track their safe introduction to the UK’s National Health Service (NHS) and patients in need.</p>



<p>The technologies chosen for this scheme include solutions targeting cancer and chronic respiratory diseases, as well as advancements in radiology diagnostics. These AI systems promise to revolutionise the accuracy and efficiency of healthcare, potentially driving better diagnostic tools and patient care.</p>



<p>The AI Airlock, as described by the MHRA, is a “sandbox” environment—an experimental framework designed to help manufacturers determine how best to collect real-world evidence to support the regulatory approval of their devices.</p>



<p>Unlike traditional medical devices, AI models continue to evolve through learning, making the establishment of safety and efficacy evidence more complex. The Airlock enables this exploration within a monitored virtual setting, giving developers insight into the practical challenges of regulation while supporting the NHS’s broader adoption of transformative AI technologies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Safely enabling AI healthcare innovation&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Laura Squire, the lead figure in MedTech regulatory reform and Chief Officer at the MHRA, said: “New AI medical devices have the potential to increase the accuracy of healthcare decisions, save time, and improve efficiency—leading to better outcomes for the NHS and patients across all healthcare settings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“But we need to be confident that AI-powered medical devices introduced into the NHS are safe, stay safe, and perform as intended through their lifetime of use.”</p>



<p>Squire emphasised that the AI Airlock pilot allows collaboration “in partnership with technology specialists, developers and the NHS,” facilitating the exploration of best practices and accelerating safe patient access to innovative solutions.</p>



<p>Government representatives have praised the initiative for its forward-thinking framework.</p>



<p>Karin Smyth, Minister of State for Health, commented: “As part of our 10-Year Health Plan, we’re shifting NHS care from analogue to digital, and this project will help bring the most promising technology to patients.</p>



<p>“AI has the power to revolutionise care by supporting doctors to diagnose diseases, automating time-consuming admin tasks, and reducing hospital admissions by predicting future ill health.”</p>



<p>Science Minister Lord Vallance lauded the AI Airlock pilot as “a great example of government working with businesses to enable them to turn ideas into products that improve lives.” He added, “This shows how good regulation can facilitate emerging technologies for the benefit of the UK and our economy.”</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Selected technologies&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The deployment of AI-powered medical devices requires meeting stringent criteria to ensure innovation, patient benefits, and regulatory challenge readiness. The five technologies selected for this inaugural pilot offer vital insights into healthcare’s future:&nbsp;</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Lenus Stratify</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Patients with Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) are among those who stand to benefit significantly from AI innovation. Lenus Stratify, developed by Lenus Health, analyses patient data to predict severe lung disease outcomes, reducing unscheduled hospital admissions. The system empowers care providers to adopt earlier interventions, affording patients an improved quality of life while alleviating NHS resource strain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="2" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Philips Radiology Reporting Enhancer</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Philips has integrated AI into existing radiology workflows to enhance the efficiency and accuracy of critical radiology reports. This system uses AI to prepare the “Impression” section of reports, summarising essential diagnostic information for healthcare providers. By automating this process, Philips aims to minimise workload struggles, human errors, and miscommunication, creating a more seamless diagnostic experience.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="3" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Federated AI Monitoring Service (FAMOS)</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>One recurring AI challenge is the concept of “drift,” when changing real-world conditions impair system performance over time. Newton’s Tree has developed FAMOS to monitor AI models in real time, flagging degradation and enabling rapid corrections. Hospitals, regulators, and software developers can use this tool to ensure algorithms remain high-performing, adapting to evolving circumstances while prioritising patient safety.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="4" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>OncoFlow Personalised Cancer Management</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Targeting the pressing healthcare challenge of reducing waiting times for cancer treatment, OncoFlow speeds up clinical workflows through its intelligent care pathway platform. Initially applied to breast cancer protocols, the system later aims to expand across other oncology domains. With quicker access to tailored therapies, patients gain increased survival rates amidst mounting NHS pressures.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="5" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>SmartGuideline</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>Developed to simplify complex clinical decision-making processes, SmartGuideline uses large-language AI trained on official NICE medical guidelines. This technology allows clinicians to ask routine questions and receive verified, precise answers, eliminating the ambiguity associated with current AI language models. By integrating this tool, patients benefit from more accurate treatments grounded in up-to-date medical knowledge.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Broader implications&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The influence of the AI Airlock extends beyond its current applications. The MHRA expects pilot findings, due in 2025, to inform future medical device regulations and create a clearer path for manufacturers developing AI-enabled technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The evidence derived will contribute to shaping post-Brexit UKCA marking processes, helping manufacturers achieve compliance with higher levels of transparency. By improving regulatory frameworks, the UK could position itself as a global hub for med-tech innovation while ensuring faster access to life-saving tools.</p>



<p>The urgency of these developments was underscored earlier this year in Lord Darzi’s <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/independent-investigation-of-the-nhs-in-england">review</a> of health and care. The report outlined the “critical state” of the NHS, offering AI interventions as a promising pathway to sustainability. The work on AI Airlock by the MHRA addresses one of the report’s major recommendations for enabling regulatory solutions and “unlocking the AI revolution” for healthcare advancements.</p>



<p>While being selected into the AI Airlock pilot does not indicate regulatory approval, the technologies chosen represent a potential leap forward in applying AI to some of healthcare’s most pressing challenges. The coming years will test the potential of these solutions under regulatory scrutiny.</p>



<p>If successful, the initiative from the MHRA could redefine how pioneering technologies like AI are adopted in <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/ai-industries/healthcare/">healthcare</a>, balancing the need for speed, safety, and efficiency. With the NHS under immense pressure from growing demand, AI’s ability to augment clinicians, predict illnesses, and streamline workflows may well be the game-changer the system urgently needs.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nci?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">National Cancer Institute</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ais-role-in-helping-to-prevent-skin-cancer-through-behaviour-change/"><strong>AI’s role in helping to prevent skin cancer through behaviour change</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:969px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/">MHRA pilots ‘AI Airlock’ to accelerate healthcare adoption</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/mhra-pilots-ai-airlock-accelerate-healthcare-adoption/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google launches Veo and Imagen 3 generative AI models</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 14:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertex ai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud has launched two generative AI models on its Vertex AI platform, Veo and Imagen 3, amid reports of surging revenue growth among enterprises leveraging the technology. According to Google Cloud&#8217;s data, 86% of enterprise companies currently using generative AI in production environments have witnessed increased revenue, with an estimated average growth of 6%.&#160;<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models/" title="ReadGoogle launches Veo and Imagen 3 generative AI models">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models/">Google launches Veo and Imagen 3 generative AI models</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Google Cloud has launched two generative AI models on its <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai">Vertex AI</a> platform, Veo and Imagen 3, amid reports of surging revenue growth among enterprises leveraging the technology.</p>



<p>According to Google Cloud&#8217;s data, 86% of enterprise companies currently using generative AI in production environments have witnessed increased revenue, with an estimated average growth of 6%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This metric has driven the tech giant&#8217;s latest innovation push, resulting in the introduction of Veo – its most sophisticated video generation model to date – and Imagen 3, an advanced text-to-image generation system.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Breaking ground</h3>



<p><a href="https://deepmind.google/technologies/veo/">Veo</a>, now available in private preview on Vertex AI, represents a milestone as Google becomes the first hyperscaler to offer an image-to-video model. The technology enables businesses to generate high-quality videos from simple text or image prompts, potentially revolutionising video production workflows across industries.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Filmmaking with Donald Glover and his creative studio, Gilga | Veo" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dKAVFLB75xs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p><a href="https://deepmind.google/technologies/imagen-3/">Imagen 3</a> – scheduled for release to all Vertex AI customers next week – promises unprecedented realism in generated images, with marked improvements in detail, lighting, and artifact reduction. The model includes new features for enterprise customers on an allowlist, including advanced editing capabilities and brand customisation options.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="614" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-1024x614.jpg" alt="Example images generated by the Imagen 3 generative AI (GenAI) model by Google, available on its Vertex AI platform." class="wp-image-16627" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-1024x614.jpg 1024w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-300x180.jpg 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-768x461.jpg 768w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-333x200.jpg 333w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-380x228.jpg 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-350x210.jpg 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-100x60.jpg 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex-60x36.jpg 60w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/google-imagen-2-generative-ai-model-image-artificial-intelligence-vertex.jpg 1400w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Transforming operations</h3>



<p>Several major firms have begun implementing these technologies into their operations.</p>



<p>Mondelez International, the company behind brands such as Oreo, Cadbury, and Chips Ahoy!, is using the technology to accelerate campaign content creation across its global portfolio of brands.</p>



<p>Jon Halvorson, SVP of Consumer Experience &amp; Digital Commerce at Mondelez International, explained: &#8220;Our collaboration with Google Cloud has been instrumental in harnessing the power of generative AI, notably through Imagen 3, to revolutionise content production.</p>



<p>“This technology has enabled us to produce hundreds of thousands of customised assets, enhancing creative quality while significantly reducing both time to market and costs.&#8221;</p>



<p>Knowledge sharing platform Quora has developed <a href="https://poe.com/">Poe</a>, a platform that enables users to interact with generative AI models. Veo and Imagen are now integrated with Poe.</p>



<p>Spencer Chan, Product Lead for Poe at Quora, commented: “We created Poe to democratise access to the world&#8217;s best gen AI models. With Veo, we&#8217;re now enabling millions of users to bring their ideas to life through stunning, high-quality generative video.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Safety and security</h3>



<p>In response to growing concerns about AI-generated content, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/categories/ai-companies/google/">Google</a> has implemented robust safety features in both models. These include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Digital watermarking</strong> through Google DeepMind&#8217;s SynthID.</li>



<li><strong>Built-in safety filters</strong> to prevent harmful content creation.</li>



<li><strong>Strict data governance policies</strong> ensure customer data protection.</li>



<li><strong>Industry-first copyright indemnity</strong> for generative AI services.</li>
</ul>



<p>The launch of these new models signals Google&#8217;s growing influence in the enterprise AI space and suggests a shift toward more sophisticated, integrated AI solutions for business applications.</p>



<p><em>(Imagery Credit: <a href="https://cloud.google.com/">Google Cloud</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-marco-o1-advancing-llm-reasoning-capabilities/"><strong>Alibaba Marco-o1: Advancing LLM reasoning capabilities</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:969px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out <a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/">AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models/">Google launches Veo and Imagen 3 generative AI models</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/google-launches-veo-and-imagen-3-generative-ai-models/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alibaba Cloud overhauls AI partner initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative</link>
					<comments>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Daws]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 10:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/?p=16610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Alibaba Cloud is overhauling its AI partner ecosystem, unveiling the &#8220;Partner Rainforest Plan&#8221; during its annual Partner Summit 2024. The Chinese tech giant&#8217;s cloud division has outlined several new initiatives, including an AI partner accelerator programme, enhanced incentives, and a refreshed global strategy for service partners, as it seeks to strengthen its position in the<a class="excerpt-read-more" href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/" title="ReadAlibaba Cloud overhauls AI partner initiative">... Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/">Alibaba Cloud overhauls AI partner initiative</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.alibabacloud.com/">Alibaba Cloud</a> is overhauling its AI partner ecosystem, unveiling the &#8220;Partner Rainforest Plan&#8221; during its annual Partner Summit 2024.</p>



<p>The Chinese tech giant&#8217;s cloud division has outlined several new initiatives, including an AI partner accelerator programme, enhanced incentives, and a refreshed global strategy for service partners, as it seeks to strengthen its position in the market.</p>



<p>Selina Yuan, President of International Business at Alibaba Cloud Intelligence, said: &#8220;At Alibaba Cloud, we believe that collaboration is the key to unlocking innovation and driving growth. Our global partners are not just participants, they are the architects of a new digital landscape in the AI era.</p>



<p>The company&#8217;s new AI Alliance Accelerator Programme aims to establish partnerships with 50 AI technology providers and 50 channel partners by 2025. Selected technology partners will receive enhanced technical support, expanded distribution channels, and dedicated AI consulting services, while channel partners will benefit from increased financial incentives for AI-related initiatives.</p>



<p>Alibaba Cloud has also introduced its Revitalised Service Partner Programme, designed to upskill existing partners and cultivate new ones through AI training and empowerment. The programme includes the joint development of Managed Large Language Model Services with service partners, leveraging the company&#8217;s generative AI capabilities.</p>



<p>The cloud provider has also committed to extending strategic partnerships with 18 service partners – including prominent names such as Deloitte, Accenture, and Cognizant Worldwide – from its existing pool of 50 global standard service partners.</p>



<p>In various regional developments, Alibaba Cloud has established strategic partnerships across Asia:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Indonesia:</strong> The company has partnered with <a href="https://www.telkom.co.id/">Telkom Indonesia</a> to deliver AI-supported cloud solutions and develop digital talent.</li>



<li><strong>Japan:</strong> Information security firm <a href="https://www.securai.net/">Securai</a> will localise Alibaba Cloud&#8217;s Zstack service for the Japanese market.</li>



<li><strong>Thailand:</strong> A memorandum of understanding with <a href="https://www.yellinter.com/">Yell Group</a> aims to address growing demand for generative AI in the creative media industry.</li>
</ul>



<p>The company, which currently maintains partnerships with approximately 12,000 organisations worldwide – including industry leaders such as <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/salesforce-uk-set-lead-agentic-ai-revolution/">Salesforce</a>, Fortinet, <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/ibm-granite-3-ai-models-open-source-commitment/">IBM</a>, and Neo4j – has introduced a Synergistic Incentive Programme to foster collaboration between its global technology and channel partners.</p>



<p>&#8220;Today, with our revamped global partner ecosystem, we are committed to supporting our global partners to jointly reap the benefits of the AI era and meet the diverse business demands of global customers,&#8221; Yuan concludes.</p>



<p><em>(Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@hannahbusing?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Hannah Busing</a>)</em></p>



<p><strong>See also: </strong><a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-marco-o1-advancing-llm-reasoning-capabilities/"><strong>Alibaba Marco-o1: Advancing LLM reasoning capabilities</strong></a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="90" src="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11874" style="width:969px;height:auto" srcset="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01.png 728w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-300x37.png 300w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-380x47.png 380w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-350x43.png 350w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-100x12.png 100w, https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/ai-expo-world-728x-90-01-60x7.png 60w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a></figure>



<p><strong>Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?</strong> Check out<a href="https://www.ai-expo.net/"> AI &amp; Big Data Expo</a> taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including <a href="https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/">Intelligent Automation Conference</a>, <a href="https://www.blockchain-expo.com/">BlockX</a>,<a href="https://digitaltransformation-week.com/"> Digital Transformation Week</a>, and <a href="https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/">Cyber Security &amp; Cloud Expo</a>.</p>



<p>Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge <a href="https://techforge.pub/events/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/">Alibaba Cloud overhauls AI partner initiative</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com">AI News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/alibaba-cloud-overhauls-ai-partner-initiative/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
